<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL05831mf</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm <num>5831 mf</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>April 21, 2014</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall Tower Road</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 607-255-3183</addressline><addressline>kheelref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-12-17 23:59:20 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50049279" role="creator" source="lcnaf">Lewis, John L. (John Llewellyn), 1880-1969</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80081625" role="creator" source="lcnaf">Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>5831 mf</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.22 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1922/1962" type="inclusive">1922-1962</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_6d38db6e0a9cafbae5600da569921d42" label="Quantity:">20 microfilm reels</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_8ab572cf5004b971f7b814b58a243a42" label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reports, pamphlets, correspondence, manuscripts, microfilm.</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_483abf43ef6e628e19fc450dbfeba762">This collection documents the origins and early history of the CIO as well as the dynamics of working-class militancy in the era of the Great Depression. The collection also provides a substantial amount of information concerning workers and trade unionism before the creation of the CIO and also after the UMWA's separation from the CIO in 1942.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a4ea4279e78d7cd8ce097850e5bcb6ed">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">3337595</unitid>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_61e649215a286722494485c94793b2a8">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>From its founding in 1935 until 1942, the history of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) was inseparable from that of John L. Lewis and the United Mine Workers of America (UMWA). Lewis created the CIO as an organization, and he used the manpower and treasury of the UMWA to keep the CIO alive. The early history of the CIO was also greatly influenced by the relationship between Lewis and Franklin D. Roosevelt. In 1935, the CIO devoted the bulk of its assets and energies to Roosevelt's re-election campaign. Roosevelt's victory in 1936 set the stage for the CIO's triumph over General Motors and United States Steel in early 1937. As the Lewis-Roosevelt relationship began to cool in 1937, the CIO lost ground to the AFL, Lewis resigned as president of the CIO in 1940, and the UMWA left the CIO two years after that.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f83f8865a75422ab2e620dc6b86631f4">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The CIO general files (1935-1955) include correspondence, CIO personnel files, committee files, financial records, and convention files. Subjects covered include organizing drives in rubber, auto, steel, electronics, timbering and shipbuilding industries; the rift between the AFL and CIO; the development of the CIO national staff; national politics; communism in the CIO; competition between the CIO and the UMWA in organizing industrial unions; impact of Taft-Hartley Act; and AFL-CIO merger negotiations. </p><p> The United Mine Workers of America files regarding loans and financial aid to CIO unions and industrial unions (1922-1955) document a number of loans made by the UMWA to industrial unions and to the CIO itself. Of special interest are the files on the CIO and the Teamsters loans. </p><p> The CIO Field Office files (1937-1942) contain records both from the CIO field offices and from Industrial Union Councils. These files document the CIO's jurisdictional and factional disputes, political activities and organizing drives. </p><p> The AFL general files (1929-1955) comprise John L. Lewis's correspondence both with and about AFL officials. The material documents the rise of industrial unionism in the 1930s and the formation of the CIO, and it provides information on the UMWA's reaffiliation and second disaffiliation from the AFL in 1946 and 1947, respectively. Files for later years provide valuable material on the AFL-CIO merger in 1955. </p><p> United Steelworkers of America (1949-1962) is a continuation of the Steelworkers files in part I. For the most part the series is a newsclipping file; however, there are records detailing the UMWA strike fund assistance to the steelworkers, and there is some material relative to the proposed federation of the UMWA, the steelworkers union, and the Teamsters in the 1950s.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e458173d5649ec0251184cc3b3b93cd1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_6f44cf643def23c6d6413e5a34e274cf">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f99c6d5dd814cc3210244bb5f10706cb">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm, #5831 mf. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_4f4c166c065028c4f05a851adf5ac074">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related Collections:  5830 mf: The CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. I: Correspondence with CIO Unions.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <odd id="aspace_110d3e0a55903fc564be51a60491ef5e">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheelref@cornell.edu">kheelref@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel">https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Randall Miles, April 21, 2014</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- United States -- Officials and employees</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- United States -- Political activity</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions and communism -- United States</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh89005480" source="lcsh">Labor leaders</subject>
    <subject source="ingest">Labor unions -- United States -- Consolidation</subject>
    <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50049279" source="lcnaf">Lewis, John L. (John Llewellyn), 1880-1969</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Boehm, Randolph,</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79091711" source="lcnaf">American Federation of Labor</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80081625" source="lcnaf">Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50062445" source="lcnaf">United Mine Workers of America</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80049653" source="lcnaf">United Steelworkers of America</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">3337595</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_3e935a0b4ccfd11016a76378ebf69878" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1935-1937</unittitle><container id="aspace_2a261ce86024d4c363a643bda46ebfad" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_bae930923971e5ee27f9000914e0a536" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO-Meetings</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b8cae7d73e3e51a52ffcd523f2fbe91" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e5bee9332d69e2fcc11a26287fb48e2c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>34 pp.: Minutes of meetings; reports of director; response to AFL allegations regarding formation of CIO; organization of steelworkers, radio workers, and auto workers; Charles P. Howard; John Brophy; William Green.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_28bc32e44e1b6f6e783231f874a07bcf" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO-AFL Controversy-Releases and Correspondence</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_79f49fd4e12ce280f02b350a35de6d0b" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f61d5a890881e9db3e75c01d780e954d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>69 pp.: Industrial unionism; 1935 AFL convention; publications; William Green; John Brophy; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; Charles P. Howard; Harvey C. Fremming; Thomas F. McMahon; Max Zaritsky.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6e97f1b755ababbeff5a5c1f85720201" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO-John Brophy, Director</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b800f2846b49e180fc4ce310ba8020f" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a3a219ffa309c84cffa7d0fd9bf3e66"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>50 pp.: UMWA support for CIO; organization plans; Brotherhood of Utility Employees of America conflict with IBEW; IUMMSW and UMWA unity negotiations; minutes of meetings of UAW Conference of FLUs; UAW wage scales; John Brophy; Joseph Mayo; Nicholas Fontecchio; Ellis Searles; A.D. Lewis; John Soltis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e620eef3799202f76b0e2af674730e36" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO-AFL Controversy--Releases and Correspondence</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa9a8ed85ff29c566dd068cd3c737d21" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f683767195b09c54dd9bda44275ff686"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>155 pp.: 1936 AFL convention; AFL reorganization and executive council dominance of crafts unions; UMWA trial of AFL president William Green@CIO organization of steelworkers and radio workers; jurisdictional disputes of CIO affiliates with AFL crafts unions; growth in membership of CIO; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL suspension of CIO affiliates; Alabama State Federation of Labor support for CIO; Wisconsin State Federation of Labor proposal for labor unity; AFL Metal Trades Department charges against CIO; John Brophy; William Green; Charles P. Howard; Van A. Bittner; Vincent Sweeney; Max Zaritsky; David Dubinsky; Sidney Hillman; George M. Harrison; William Mitch; Henry Ohl; John P. Frey; G.M. Bugniazel; Joseph N. Weber; Frank Morrison.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3e614f7bb0a38b8748e0672b00e788d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_edb2ac291c14a346581613fa4d1f18c4" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2a71c4ca50baee3bc86e6066b790b80b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>158 pp.: Growth in membership of CIO@CIO organization of auto workers, rubber workers, steelworkers, electrical and radio workers, shipbuilding workers, shoe workers, and woodworkers; publications; conflict with AFL@CIO and SWOC financial matters; social security and legislative programs; Senator Robert M. La Follette committee identification security and legislative programs; Senator Robert M. La Follette committee identification of spies employed by the National Corporation Service; statements of church groups supporting union organization@CIO organization in the Pacific Northwest; UMWA organizers; AFL Metal Trades Department charges against CIO; UMWA support for SWOC; Amalgamated Association of Iron, Steel, and Tin Workers agreement with CIO; reports of the director; John Brophy; William Green; John O'Leary; John Zimmerman; William Dalrymple; Abe Vales; John P. Frey; Glen W. McCabe.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc4b2b9363a5e397b815372262ce9673" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Meetings</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1c934d1b2efda06b210037fcee7448a" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_22a607cc61604cbe33e5d3da4c690d04"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>45 pp.: AFL-CIO controversy; SWOC; unity negotiations; reports of the director; minutes of meetings. Charles P. Howard; Sidney Hillman; David Dubinsky; Thomas F. McMahon; Harvey C. Fremming; Max Zaritsky; William Green; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_611b19f2501b3b570dcddbe2cd16456f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, Powers Hapgood, International Representative</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1936" type="inclusive">1935-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_ebdcf592d869f95b70e5d13c62303c94" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_82d0076c0c7fae98f1c06a7c800f49e2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>17 pp.: UMWA organizers; allegations of Socialist influence; Powers Hapgood; James Nelson.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_354b13c12631c6240ce1b0d8298f9d23" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Office Personnel, Hazelle M. Camp</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_0336a27adfbc814f2577538177b0ce8b" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c012147595416c5dbe550ea334c2c473"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Kathryn Lewis; Hazelle M. Camp.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_faffb69e480867166a976f12d124ec3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Action of UMWA Executive Council on Case of William Green</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_3057efc19dcc7026d25b3f087a9e418d" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ccb74744c0fa46ee8e21a436d11ed400"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>33 pp; UMWA trial of AFL president William Green; AFL- CIO controversy; William Green; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; Walter Smethurst; John Ghizzoni; John O'Leary; Ora E. Gasaway; John J. Mates; Henry Allai.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_caa525391df9c7d32f8707c1675c7a68" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_5213b4654b95131fba0772798510061f" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_81e255798d9330c92824fe46e483671a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>294 pp.: Oil Workers International Union contract negotiations; local industrial union charters and growth in CIO membership; NLRB decisions; UMWA organizers@United Lumber Workers contract negotiations; US Department of Justice prosecution of SWOC members and S.S. Algic crewmen; 1937 CIO conference; plans for CIO convention@United Retail Employees of America request for loan and organizers; UMWA District 50 organizers@CIO financial matters@United Textile Workers of America; statistics by state and union on growth in local industrial unions; Speakers Bureau activities; UCAPAWA locals by state and occupation; jurisdictional disputes@CIO organization plans regarding chartering of unions and jurisdiction by occupation; E.C. Conarty; Mary Evelyn Bendelari; Kathryn Lewis; John Ghizzoni; Lee Pressman; J. Raymond Bell; Philip Murray; Walter Smethurst; James Starr; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_48d20e3b1f04b90e059bc161ff8e5741" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Office General</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_7eb90013631a86fb26cbd5c3684047d3" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a79cecf9ba574976f535f92277edb9df"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>239 pp.: Founding of United Furniture Workers of America; number of field representatives allotted to national and international unions; NLRB policy regarding industrial unionism; weekly analyses of U.S. economic conditions by industry; lists of CIO regional directors and field representatives by state; lists of presidents and secretaries of CIO national and international unions; negotiations with UOPWA CIO office unit; publications; draft constitution and rules for local industrial unions; loans to United Retail Employees of America and Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; lists of local industrial unions@CIO rental of office space@CIO organizational structure and officers; Illinois state unemployment compensation legislation; UMWA and CIO cooperation; Labor's Non-Partisan League; proposal of US Constitution amendment to reform the judiciary; John Brophy; Lee Pressman; Ralph Hetzel; John Bell; Len De Caux; Walter Smethurst; Ora E. Gasaway; Kathryn Lewis; Mary Evelyn Bendelari; David J. McDonald; A.D. Lewis; Maurice Sugar; Eli L. Oliver.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_d53c3079cbbf72da8815a6dd4b934b3e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1937-1938</unittitle><container id="aspace_66e0bd607a01d30ad168f58b40f46981" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><c02 id="aspace_e2805fe1fad8c5e368540325c51889cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO-AFL Controversy--Releases and Correspondence</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d38246a4c21b829110dbd71904e0a57" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ded24dd1d4fd7ea1a6f0c99fd3f119f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>73 pp.: Founding of United Furniture Workers of America; results of AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL jurisdictional disputes with CIO affiliates; AFL executive council internal politics; UMWA support for UAW contract negotiations with General Motors Corporation; 1937 CIO conference; legislative programs; NLRB decisions; Philip Murray; Frank Morrison; Harvey C. Fremming; Charles P. Howard; Sidney Hillman; David Dubinsky; Homer Martin; James B. Carey; Richard Frankensteen; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Donald Henderson; Van A. Bittner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_308e4dd2c9df670fb0775b1c9b9cc9c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Miscellaneous Releases.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_da7ea8b784ad5a8d000efe8b4a6ff4aa" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bca5d79ac68a9793293bf996ccfa7610"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>109 pp; WPA workers and CIO unemployment programs; legislative programs; Social Security Act provisions; union organization; founding of United Furniture Workers of America@CIO regional directors; NLRB elections; American Radio Telegraphists contract negotiations; founding of TWOC; anti-union violence against UAW officers in Anderson, IN; publications; John Brophy; Walter Smethurst; Richard Francis; Lee Pressman; George L. Berry; Francis Gorman; Frances Perkins; Edward Hall.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_577fe16ffc8f274069c42c8e066fc009" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Meeting.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_90d908407005cb8c2970177b0b8194f0" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6acac3549fddf57cdc8aad4d10fc0b44"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>March 9, 1937. 12 pp; Report of director; national and international union requests for CIO affiliation; regional and state organization; financial matters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cc4beabfe5ce9e0ffec864fa1317dc51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Agreement between CIO and United Textile Workers of America.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_09e8636af4f5ae2ea4b5d50bf750fb65" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77b54bfb172ac06ae3846197dffd7c77"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>March 1937. 3 pp.: Founding of TWOC; Francis Gorman; Charles P. Howard; Sidney Hillman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_143804cc905eb2e630ce054fcf6db492" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO Convention--Atlantic City, NJ (Part 1).</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e055251497aced2d0f36eeaa2b92591" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ab0f95dc08b9b271b4827cadb4ca6cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>October 1937. 316 pp.: Informal minutes of CIO conference, October 11-15, 1937; SWOC report; report of director; NMU report; American Newspaper Guild report; special Southern report@United Packing House Workers Council report; TWOC report; IWA report@CIO Maritime Committee report; UERMWA report; Transport Workers Union of America report; ACA report; Shoe Workers Organizing Committee report; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA District 50 report; safety and health; National Leather Workers Association report; ILWU report; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America report; legislative programs; NLRB decisions@United Retail Employees of America report; Pacific Northwest jurisdictional disputes with AFL; political activities; Toy and Novelty Workers Organizing Committee report; Aluminum Workers of America report; UCAPAWA report@United Federal Workers of America report; IUMMSW report; State, County, and Municipal Workers of America report; UAW report; UOPWA report; URW report; Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists, and Technicians report; Philip Murray; John Brophy; Joseph Curran; Heywood Broun; Jonathan Eddy; Victor Pasche; Walter Smethurst; Sidney Hillman; Harold Pritchett; Mervyn Rathborne; James B. Carey; Michael Quill; Powers Hapgood; Lee Pressman; David Dubinsky; Homer Martin; James Nelson; Abram Flaxer; Daniel Boyle; Harry Bridges; John Green; C.W. Deal; Louis Leonard; Alexander Ravitch; Paul W. Fuller; N.A. Zonarich; Donald Henderson; Reid Robinson; Lewis Merrill; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Lewis Alan Berne; Samuel Wolchok.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_53b5bbb666e69e2b68fac3b3ecb5b522" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO Convention--Atlantic City, NJ (Part 2).</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c7c9a23733e62cd468b0db1e5fc0711" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_993b4e79f28618d30e0745f3e4fbbc26"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>October 1937. 161 pp.: Committee reports to CIO conference; Special Committee on Finance report; report of director; growth in membership of CIO; NLRB election statistics; resolutions of CIO conference; speeches to CIO conference; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; South Chicago Memorial Day massacre; Walter Smethurst; John Brophy; Philip Murray; Van A. Bittner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2de75f21898f9e0905ade14d5b90a623" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Auxiliary Organization, Edwardsville, IL.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8f0a066bad38cfa3fdeec4d75a86ae2" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_82e054550431d5eabbfd86087e872967"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Local CIO support group.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_520c66ed577ffc67faa24da17d323e44" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Speakers Bureau</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_47db4b6c16fe28138dcf287d827a154d" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c53639cc60cfc999d70313485a53b3ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>23 pp.: UOPWA CIO office unit protest against work of Mary Evelyn Bendelari in Charter department; Speakers Bureau Labor Day activities; publicity; Kathryn Lewis; Mary Evelyn Bendelari; Len De Caux.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ed2ac606370343d10bb808955347640a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Office Personnel, Bell, J. Raymond.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_95823713a41b31822f3a1471693af3c4" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_764a438b6f6079fc772767671e4faef8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: Appointment as CIO comptroller; appointment of Richard Francis to SWOC payroll; John Brophy; J. Raymond Bell; David J. McDonald; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a48c718d615a604e1a0c7b96eaa6e358" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, Bendelari, Mary Evelyn.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_96840152aaa5e16fc29bae08bc7b7ddf" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5a03b29c9f9a59d921f74229e0dc55a9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: Appointment as chief of the Division of Chartered Organizations and Speakers Bureau; Walter Smethurst; Kathryn Lewis; Mary Evelyn Bendelari.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6f45ef926c0572ac578e6d9ddd863e79" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, Dernoncourt, Joseph.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_5388432ec0ed569be92e9fde4b313423" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aad118693fd87c928266aaa5bf2deed4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: Criticism of CIO and UMWA organizer Dernoncourt; boycott of General Motors Corporation products during UAW strike.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_787cab2ab217941ef97c93a6b103183f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, DuBois, Marian (later Mrs. Ralph Hetzel).</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa417fb4a6b346f2529c22ee336fec9f" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a1b5522807a94ece715f0b5d2f62598a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: Letter of recommendation; Edwin S. Smith.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9377f6d4aaa68313f39e2394dfdc1cff" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, Haywood, Allan S.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_05550d8c0d4a5811dfe1a51d7d74b282" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_95d62724c421bf90bddcc955a38ffe87"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Congratulations on General Motors Corporation contract negotiations; Allan S. Haywood.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_de83115ddd257071578d8758b9f45228" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Office Personnel, Hetzel, Ralph.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_37209161461ee73d3bcb39028de138d4" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_720556d0005be73101c5d1fb6d0229ad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: Appointment as secretary to CIO chairman; Walter Smethurst.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4c769408e0e4eaedf4add40538396393" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, Kovner, Joseph (Legal Dept.).</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6fa40d0269fdd4b14262b30dd7194e1" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3b374207c9edbaf94927a9285ae0649"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>6 pp.: Appointment as assistant to Lee Pressman; background and experience; Lee Pressman; John Brophy; Joseph Kovner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_88ce9d0b98586ce5731f607e4a4ea60b" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, Pressman, Lee (Legal Dept).</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_929cf9e6e2f28a972f6b008edbfe3966" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5db54dfd710d67ba02601773356381e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Appointment as CIO Counsel; Philip Murray; David J. McDonald; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b2739df274acca0f78a4467f7612df93" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, Smethurst, Walter.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2ffd951dd2fd7017ec1da1faa3b6e9e" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c7043204311e0b3be645a7335ed49dd8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Plans for birthday celebration.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ba844f1d2828726e3bf9f5bac056fea8" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel, Suttle, John H.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_2aeb404640863a292b53b8089201cf50" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f069ae56e8bc06a413204aeecba24781"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: Appointment as CIO organizers; Virginia E. Jenckes; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_048329ab17658c9d3d9c5bd6729a3c98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Request from Various Groups of Workers for Organization under CIO.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3429f35249f320229fdf6a57a5624f8" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ed2a82092569e8fb8b7582035eba378"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>28 pp.: Proposed organization of domestic and farm workers.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_055c4afc60f53aeea4d905ae9c5b8473" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_542376ec75ea975adbfe0d74d7d0df70" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a55c3a8b1331d1caa4d157fee854c407"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>175 pp.: Office space for Labor's Non-Partisan League; AFL competition with CIO; NLRB elections@CIO organizers; UMWA organizers@CIO regional directors; UMWA executive council matters; organization in New York, Illinois, Utah, Wyoming, Montana, Nebraska, Tennessee, Pennsylvania, North Carolina, Colorado, Kansas, and Michigan; factionalism and internal politics; organization of black workers and Communist activities among Omaha, Nebraska, packing house workers; Communist activities among Duluth, Minnesota, steelworkers; legislative programs; Tennessee Valley Authority electrification competition with coal industry; growth in membership of CIO; Communist activities, factionalism, and internal politics among Detroit, Michigan, auto workers; organization of WPA workers; A.D. Lewis; Walter Smethurst; David W. Davis; James Morgan; Thomas Kennedy; John Brophy; Ben Williams; Harmon R. Ballard; Ora E. Gasaway; Tom Jones; Joseph Angelo; Kathryn Lewis; Philip Murray; Walter N. Polakov; David H. Watkins; Tom White.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_1466ed469faf61eb01686b3ed03c881c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1938</unittitle><container id="aspace_63b1934d0fbba93e37626344b6de3e25" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><c02 id="aspace_ba3413600692e1e21d30d33eea5fd58b" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Office General.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_29ed63ba2d67c7a0209196ed6cd4607a" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6848f814375da4b8dd3e19ce531c1096"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>165 pp.: CIO organizers; personnel matters; lists of CIO personnel and comparison of regional office expenses; Jersey City, NJ, civil rights case; publicity; financial matters of The CIO News; Dies Committee hearings; Labor Day activities; plans for CIO constitutional convention; NLRB decisions; CIO Legal Department bulletins; proposed amendments of Wagner Act; Walter Smethurst; J. Raymond Bell; Kathryn Lewis; Len De Caux; John Brophy; Philip Murray; A.D. Lewis; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cf1d626977b0a23ac97678d80888a319" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General File.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_87c3a07a1c1998a0eb505ccb2a1cf09d" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a385e6d3ff19c19347f9d4fa655294e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>54 pp.: Agreement between CIO and UOPWA CIO office unit; contract negotiations; NLRB decision in the matter of Inland Steel Company and SWOC; growth of The CIO News and proposed mailing to UMWA membership; Joseph Kovner; Hollace Ransdell; Walter Smethurst; J. Raymond Bell; J. Warrne Madden; Edwin S. Smith; Donald Wakefield Smith; Kathryn Lewis; Len De Caux. John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_751ce92ed643a36a0f3384875526961a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Meetings.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_5854e1076cd41b03f95f2dcbb7913c3b" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db844f0053692c9cc682e5993675fc44"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: CIO staff meetings; Labor's Non-Partisan League; legislative programs; Eli L. Oliver.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_26dc2f8577d040e0e0180b2d04cc364e" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO Conference</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c0e697d1de54783bd9f6b78c96cf06b" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6e1f649a52362cf03f8bf49ad85a8168"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Washington, DC. April 12-13, 1938. 121 pp.: Digest of proceedings; report of director; report of comptroller; report on The CIO News and publicity; report of legal department; report on unemployment activities; Workers Alliance of America; reports of affiliated organizations; legislative programs; growth in membership of CIO; John Brophy; J. Raymond Bell; Len De Caux; Lee Pressman; Ralph Hetzel; Richard Frankensteen; Joseph Curran; Charles P. Howard; Sidney Hillman; Homer Martin; Julius Hochman; Samuel J. Hogan; Jacob F. Potofsky; James Nelson; Morris Muster; Allan S. Haywood; Mervyn Rathborne; Lewis Alan Berne; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Samuel Wolchok; Lewis Merrill; Emil Rieve; Philip Murray; Abram Flaxer; Albert Stonkus; James B. Carey; David Lasser; Samuel Levin; Donald Henderson; Harvey C. Fremming; James Lawson; Paul W. Fuller; Reid Robinson; Jacob Baker; Michael Quill; Powers Hapgood; Eli L. Oliver; John Green; N.A. Zonarich; E.C. Conarty; Harold Pritchett.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a400710059e221547bc391256ce8b997" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO First Constitutional Convention</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_ccefc9c3b39abaaf0489567aba7bab1d" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9f1b3af9722180d64a641f303d267bf2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Pittsburgh, PA. November 14-18, 1938 [October 28-November 19, 1938]. 183 pp.: Greetings to convention; constitution; report of chairman; UMWA report; lists of delegates and committee memberships; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; convention resolutions; plans for convention; Franklin D. Roosevelt; John Brophy; John Owens; Frank Miley; Lee Pressman; David J. McDonald.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_971c5082926b0a99001b183ac5f387d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Audits and Accounting.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_eead4f497a5abf76f008c14fe25bd4ea" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b582e48e18315d97973435877a5f494"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>70 pp.: Financial matters; per capita payment by affiliates; CIO payroll expenses; Leo F. Tearney; Len De Caux; Kathryn Lewis; J. Raymond Bell; Walter Smethurst; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1dc3bc7b6ea48a9f0f5d22c3451ef659" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Committee on Education.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_2dec711bf609cdf3b3909726756e68ca" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_198af3690c753c546e5937547b649c0a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>14 pp.: Proposed CIO adult education program; Ralph Hetzel; Ralph E. Turner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f4535eb70f684731c3a52745d06537ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Housing Committee.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f7e2795c44c97f92640364206f1c71d" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d06984c223b9e71589463b7e8f64aa28"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10 pp.: Cooperation with US Housing Authority; low-rent housing projects; Anthony Wayne Smith; Michael Quill; Bertram M. Gross; Ellis Searles; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9910f63d4fecc98536851a85ea8ba38a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Legislative Committee.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_db41313821c96d8f932b2597d2f1c772" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_94d765c6c7a3f8928c0d4d5b0357a3da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 pp.: Legislative programs; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Sidney Hillman; Eli L. Oliver.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_60d47cc42e146d8b4e7606345d6d5b5d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Personnel--Office.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_23b34afa44e6a78d519eaec3abdd4726" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b5d007ffa29a4680721eefd48eb8cea0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>13 pp.: CIO relations with UOPWA CIO office unit; appointment of Hildegarde Gray; Walter Smethurst; Ralph Hetzel; A.D. Lewis; J. Roymond Bell; Frank Sobers.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_697acbe855e84247f3e83e153d956d0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Research Department.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd2a5ed3daf35de42d8104c67869833c" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9456ddbc2394c8934b4d23afdbe46869"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>138 pp.: Domestic and world economic conditions; labor, economic conditions, and political relations in Maryland, Pennsylvania, West Virginia, Ohio, Indiana, Illinois, Wisconsin, Minnesota, North Dakota, South Dakota, and Montana; U.S. urban economic conditions; industrial survey of Florida, South Carolina, North Carolina, Alabama, Tennessee, Georgia, Mississippi, and Louisiana; survey of distilled liquors industry; copper industry; average hourly earnings for major industries; memorandum on the movie industry; sugar productions; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; innovative wage and hour policy and labor-management relations of the Hormel Packing Company; CIO public relations; legislative programs; James Gillan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3421a0d65aa324258e26a557c82a80f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Social Security Committee.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d2e1b27bdf30050f4b99923cb086f7a" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_100bc5e3850aed1b191864096063bd24"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8 pp.: Reports of Social Security Committee; Charles P. Howard; Joseph Kovner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dabaf60a7eb3b8b483dd27f7f522e958" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Unemployment Committee.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_28436fc825c775e8a0d48c38e24dc367" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60a7916d48062c0365a1ee3f37d80103"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>91 pp.: WPA; legislative programs; wage and hour legislation; Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938; organizations of unemployed and WPA workers; federal relief programs; joint meeting with regional directors; Workers Alliance of America. Ralph Hetzel; Anthony Wayne Smith; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_65ef8d0ef6c8661c1d17618ce5fe5209" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Story of the CIO.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_f51564c1868aaa4723df3f694a6c24f5" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4bef505002db62d3f4663d41200555f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>28 pp.: AFL-CIO unity negotiations; founding of CIO; analysis of affiliates; James Gillan.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a5f83f8f51d8266c4bc9003e98f255eb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1939-1941</unittitle><container id="aspace_c16dc478dc7779b92034c753fa2c6e96" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><c02 id="aspace_ac99430f7583b532e8bc204bfb5685af" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Office General.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_6003660cd5eeebed7763a3bab2a5d996" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8809a794f9de81a3a840e978e130927"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>149 pp.: U.S. monetary policy; Temporary National Economic Committee hearings on technology changes and employment; transfer of John Brophy and Walter Smethurst from UMWA to CIO payrolls; Consumers Power Corporation strikes in Michigan; CIO organizers; WPA projects in Montana; Southern Coal Operators Association; Interstate Commerce Commission; crafts unionism; AFL competition with CIO; plans for 1939 CIO convention; Harry Bridges Defense Committee; reactions of US congressmen to attack of John L. Lewis on US vice president John Nance Garner; PWOC; CIO relations with UOPWA CIO office unit; resignation of Harvey C. Fremming as Social Security committee chairman; WPA and federal relief programs in connection with UMWA work stoppage in West Virginia, Kentucky, and Alabama; support for UMWA contract negotiations; CIO unemployment program; CIO office space lease arrangements; issuance of new CIO charters following reorganization; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; suspension of CIO affiliates from the Trades and Labor Congress of Canada; proposed amendment of Wagner Act; lists of CIO regional and subregional directors, officers of national and international affiliates, and executive board members; Ralph Hetzel; Lee Pressman; Walter Smethurst; Rinaldo Cappellini; James Gillan; J. Raymond Bell; Kathryn Lewis; John Brophy; Len De Caux; Ramsey Wilson; Ora E. Gasaway; A.D. Lewis; Joseph Kovner; Anthony Wayne Smith; Frank Hefferly; D.W. Morrison; R.J. Tallon; Walter N. Polakov; Philip Murray.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_02afd0e69381191c55bd653cfb544e7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d8f10bff348de99edcbc409a72d8a66" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ece95a4a4970a4c0b902ac143c24ff94"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>21 pp.: AFL-CIO unity negotiations; founding of United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; UMWA cooperation; proposed mine foremen and assistants union; proposed replacement of The CIO News; A.D. Lewis; John Owens; James Mark; Van A. Bittner; Ellis Searles; Frank Miley.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2ac70d51856b1b06f05d7c89a09d361b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Los Angeles Industrial Union Council--Harry Bridges, president (CIO financial assistance for West Coast organizing drive).</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0d5d9d8205c48c04bddaff33899cbde" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c30e846cdc2cc740af3fa3d003a75a3e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 pp.: CIO financial assistance for West Coast organizing drive@United Studio Technicians Guild; Harry Bridges; J. Raymond Bell; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c8e9ed954857725481ef44d3a51cef79" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Executive Board Meeting.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a1dd8fb1a645d4044e73f2dcd571809" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c66def0a1da8dc9cfd8497e1ca913930"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>June 1939. 4 pp.: News release.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_02ca918656e6ea1a38a707a76a0d222e" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Executive Board Meeting.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_606a4c1af9176c99ab1a1b10860b45b9" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_118f08ac4ced17cec9f9a381508aa0a2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>October 5, 1939. 14 pp.: List of motions passed at meeting; minutes of meeting; J. Raymond Bell; Kathryn Lewis; Mervyn Rathborne; Allan S. Haywood; John L. Coulter; James B. Carey; Lee Pressman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e565e6137166eb94d33104e82b8ee9fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO Convention.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_2dce41b7e3613ef5f38f97440f549033" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8622e8522edf42968ed28377cf0a400b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>70 pp.: Constitution; UMWA report; UMWA delegates; credentials; resolutions on the war in Europe; committee memberships; report of committee on legislation; report of the president; greetings to convention; Martin Wagner; John O'Leary; John Brophy; Robert F. Wagner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aacd20a91b4f701fd75f2d8d10dabc13" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Releases. 1939 (part 1).</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_df409ff9c4775589fcac556999645f48" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8c35ecbd5d73413e3bfbdecce865a3fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>221 pp.: AFL proposal for amendment of the Wagner Act; wage and hour legislation; Fair Labor Standards Act; legislative programs; Social Security committee; national health bill; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; violations of free speech and rights of labor by strikebreaking services; Homer Martin UAW controversy; Labor's Non-Partisan League; federal relief spending cuts; John Brophy; Lee Pressman; Walter Smethurst; Harvey C. Fremming; Joseph Kovner; Robert M. La Follette; Sidney Hillman; Philip Murray; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Ralph Hetzel; Anthony Wayne Smith.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_32f4c5c81db7ae3e8ba026994271414f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Releases. 1939 (Part 2).</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_9530e24443eaf48480bfeae01e2d3f01" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_53c06f6f21724d23f4699fdac6946a81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>205 pp.: Founding of United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; legislative programs; local industrial union organization; AFL-CIO competition; press allegations of Communist influence in CIO; health and welfare programs; Labor Day speeches; AFL factionalism and internal politics; proposed amendment of Wagner Act; WPA legislation; Lee Pressman; John Brophy; Joseph Kovner; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e168c67ae684a7cffe0864f2f106b22d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Audits and Accounting.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3953e9eb56148d7c209fd1c6905721f" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b379ef060b47dae88092734eb045117"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>38 pp.: Financial matters; UMWA loans to CIO; J. Raymond Bell.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5b354e816bf98991f13154f1ee832383" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Housing Committee.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_22bc6f4e74d257c44f8866ce15adecfc" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_571826ca82089d734704b4de2fb6533c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>21 pp.: US Housing Authority low-rent housing programs; Havana Labor Congress; report on the International Congress for Housing and Town Planning; plans for 1939 CIO convention; Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists, and Technicians; Anthony Wayne Smith; John Anderson; John Brophy; Michael Quill; John M. Ross.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1793480d94d13f3120147ce2ecc469a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Legislative Committee and Legal Department.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1941" type="inclusive">1939-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_c35c780d7d9a94b529f52ce7d2e9699d" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ac25efd6800e29038b59a7ad9686025f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1939 [and 1941]. 67 pp.: Legislative programs; industrial mobilization plans of the AFL and the National Association of Manufacturers; CIO negotiations with UOPWA CIO office unit; US Supreme Court decision regarding Jersey City, NJ, civil rights case; NLRB decision; AFL proposed amendment of the Wagner Act@United Kingdom financial matters (1941); Lee Pressman; Anthony Wayne Smith; Joseph Kovner; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ddb2c9746817e7a6b49629b7d72d14e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Organization Director.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c742aafbc7c7ccd7b767bd871d5442b" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_242399346cb9d9f3c8e369fcf82fe393"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10 pp.: 1939 CIO convention; call for a southern conference on organization; CIO organizers; Aluminum Workers of America; CIO regional directors; Allan S. Haywood; August Scholle; Michael J. Kosik; Walter Harris.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2da81ca215ae1b6144ef5a5f02e0dbe" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Social Security Committee.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7d69b1d99dc05c1504a84456fec5d40" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab6b583ad45bfec223aa04c8716879f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>25 pp.: Social Security legislation; Joseph Kovner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2b5a5d305d8b297372ae88004f53d550" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Unemployment Committee.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8ecfa242ba07d0922087abad09c595e" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b978c7fd3d2236a62bb4ecef527312c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>20 pp.: WPA legislation; relief programs in Kentucky, Alabama, and West Virginia in connection with UMWA contract negotiations; Ralph Hetzel; James E. Murray; A.D. Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0f5f6978a1b52a7b26b80e5021445161" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Committee on Latin American Affairs.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1941" type="inclusive">1939-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f083d21d19c36eee9252d893587ba13" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6bdf6ca0c43db9022ad4b9f8c7f81374"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>178 pp. [continued on Reel 5]: Appeal from Dominican Republic labor leaders; Mexico City meetings of the Confederation of Latin American Workers (CTAL); report of the Pan-American Maritime Council; ILO; Philip Murray; Nelson A. Rockefeller; Kathryn Lewis; J. Raymond Bell; Edward Gordon; Ad Staal; Joseph Curran; Thomas Kennedy; Reid Robinson; Ralph Hetzel; Harold Ruttenberg; Anthony Wayne Smith; Ernest Galarza; James B. Carey; Jacob Baker; James Robinson.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_3a464cf0a1dafc74371b6dc53fd58034" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1939-1941</unittitle><container id="aspace_1c80d0d74ea40017454c82d4da416ade" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><c02 id="aspace_7c05bbc30f5c552c83e55b10d828ba9d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Committee on Latin American Affairs.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1941" type="inclusive">1939-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb152f2aa7bce79c0e81bb65fd25caf8" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1da1814a44ad7d81ba7343f3a25d4d2a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>246 pp. [continued from Reel 4]: Pan-American Union; entertainment of Latin American visitors; Cuban Labor Congress; Havana Conference of the ILO; US legislation for international cooperation; minutes of meetings; Mexico City meeting of the Latin American Congress of Trade Unions; fascism; Kathryn Lewis; Anthony Wayne Smith; Reid Robinson; Joseph Kovner; John Brophy; Ray Torr; James B. Carey; Isador Lubin; David Fowler; Ernest Galarza; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Lee Pressman; Michael Quill; Joseph Curran; Mervyn Rathborne.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1b8f59b9dcff5fcb4faef1c17666dc60" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e3ee9660c185a0928242241b088b98d" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1ad12389ea8cdf2c88c311bd95baa05d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>191 pp.: Support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; legislative programs; 1940 US presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; economic impact of national defense mobilization; union shop; SWOC; Consumers Power Corporation; protests against federal budget cuts; economic analysis of industrial trends; payment on United Packinghouse Workers of America loan from CIO; CIO personnel matters; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA organizers; leave of absence granted to John Brophy; lists of officers of national and international affiliates and CIO regional and subregional directors; J. Raymond Bell; Thomas Kennedy; Kathryn Lewis; Walter Smethurst; Allan S. Haywood; Lee Pressman; Rinaldo Cappellini; Ralph Hetzel; Len De Caux; Ora E. Gasaway; Henry Allai; Charles Funcannon; James Robb; John Brophy; Van A. Bittner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_eb51d22ea055b00ec11de50d0a2b9fec" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Executive Board Meetings. February-November</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_fca58724156763f17321c0390881e364" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b9b26ed2f36825256e0db86c888db34"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>47 pp.: Legislative programs; union organization; housing committee report; Social Security committee report; unemployment division report; national defense mobilization; WPA; Michael Quill; Anthony Wayne Smith; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Emil Rieve; Ralph Hetzel; Franklin D. Roosevelt.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ef350ae9a4647574d3571b1ede31362f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Convention.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_2518d4f0b085d5d05a77446a21e4b7d9" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d219a474a43f7b37df0110d06a2de4d8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>73 pp.: UMWA delegation; committee memberships; speeches; national defense mobilization; constitution; Ralph Hetzel; Kathryn Lewis; Philip Murray; Sidney Hillman; James B. Carey.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_d73c0f8acca57eed95b2215855d6f3ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1940-1941</unittitle><container id="aspace_c01e4e727e56afec6618f9c4f5027eea" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><c02 id="aspace_f2ee3a6f9d5ab57db1e45d58bd344203" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Publicity and Pamphlets.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_55bbb6569023b13a2091f5d6a5a4bde6" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_593c8a419764eb4bbf094949da86bd18"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>102 pp.: Proposed amendment of Wagner Act; union organization; youth employment; national defense mobilization; growth in CIO membership; American Youth Congress; social security programs; organization of black workers; National Negro Congress; legislative programs; anti-war activities; Len De Caux; Joseph H. Padway; Gilbert Montague; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Joseph Kovner; Van A Bittner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9660ecc14a504eb6749392d50072feb8" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Audits and Accounting.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_34fa68d0fd3eeae9b0b93300c73c83ba" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6cd0298f68388c47ee0b48bc66802f5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>72 pp.: Financial matters; national and international union payments of per capita and assignments of CIO organizers; Leo F. T. Tearney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1621802f0cd9257d948d2ad3c56331e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Housing Committee.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_805f320951964cc313d9cf7bcadfa5b7" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_265db16b4ed1425437e53e7bc70662af"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: U.S. Housing Authority appropriations; legislative programs; Michael Quill; Anthony Wayne Smith.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1ad660dacc5ade914ed3a401afbb80bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Legislative Committee and Legal Department.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_d04adc8af9b1d0530855762d0d9cd433" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66f06ebc7655d0e35b2126434175df12"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>76 pp.: Legislative programs; proposed amendments to CIO constitution; national defense contracting policies; legislative committee report to executive board; foreign exchange assets and needs of countries fighting against Germany; Lee Pressman; Anthony Wayne Smith; Joseph Kovner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_241ca595aaace05ef6721a0de1e8a583" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Marine Maritime Committee.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_ddec7b75edec3a9035f136698c4ab23f" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f61c05c2d3c6fe746319f126a3123d50"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>42 pp.: Earl King, Ernest G. Ramsey, and Frank J. Connor murder case in California; political activities; opposition to nominations of John J. Dempsey and Joseph K. Carson to US Maritime Commission; anti-union policies of US Maritime Commission; Pan-American Maritime Federation; Harry Bridges deportation case; Bjorne Halling; Joseph Curran; James B. Carey.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ff6ee2f2aab792e3ff989fa8e1eba42a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Organization Director.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_518d9f90e1906788c37328917e564224" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ff63213ceb2d9905b67ee099330495a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>38 pp.: Support for 1940 US presidential campaign of Wendell Willkie; Utility Workers Organizing Committee; Consumers Power Corporation NLRB elections; UAW; CIO organization plans; CIO organizers and regional directors; financial difficulties with UOPWA and CIO loans; AFL organization of industrial insurance agents; UERMWA contract negotiations; 1940 UMWA convention; AFL-CIO competition; Allan S. Haywood; Kathryn Lewis; William Collins; James B. Carey.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ad81490f27118e1142d30db2d8f98756" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Replies to Release regarding National Labor Relations Act and Government Contracts.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_87e66b47a74441825d03e65ceed3b88a" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3312afe489e06bfc9f3a2b50a404e4ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>194 pp.: Proposed guarantees of collective bargaining in government contracts that would debar firms violating NLRA from receiving such contracts; local and national union support for proposals; Advisory Commission to the Council of National Defense; proposed executive order; proposed amendments to Walsh-Healey Act; Van A. Bittner; Sidney Hillman; Samuel J. Hogan; Frank Hefferly; Morris Muster; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Harold J. Pritchett; Edward T. Cheyfitz; Michael J. Quill; Lewis Merrill; Sam Nicholls; Richard Francis; Marcel Scherer; John Green; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; O.F. Nigro; James B. Carey; Julius Emspak; Frank McCarty; Ralph Hetzel; Abram Flaxer; Jacob Baker; Reid Robinson; Morris Watson; N.A. Zonarich; Donald Henderson; Joseph Curran; John Brophy; Lee Pressman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_92749289dd4dccf7c5c4c0236a764d00" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Unemployment Committee.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_38303721a90ff04e91d12437f07c84b9" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_06118991c4a17035cb269ba2abddb0f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>60 pp.: US government unemployment statistics; US Civil Service employment opportunities; WPA budget appropriations; legislative programs; economic analysis of industrial production; unemployment committee report; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_938ea9f165646ac646bd232d53ac4cb3" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Women's Auxiliary.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c82ccd56bfbd05ca6a1a54e531940ff" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_160d2b04b3638639f010f0a45b99adc3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>24 pp.: National Coordinating Committee for Women's Auxiliaries; anti-war policies; educational programs; WPA programs. Julia Katz; Kathryn Lewis; Mary Santo.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5b4983d41a50cf0e6a0067fe49357eed" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8a528260349487c97b2a773af8cd02e" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d608765aea65178447c72d4267a8da34"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>240 pp.: Requests for union organization of office, domestic, and restaurant workers; requests for miscellaneous information; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; NLRB elections; labor problems in national defense contracts; IWA factionalism and internal politics; Robert F. Wagner; John T. Jones; Philip Murray; Kathryn Lewis; Harry Bridges.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_525b47844637a9d54af85496912ce37c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Office General.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_5bc9706657c839a3aee097a398cb9641" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b7b2c85c0b015bba6dd0065e796a536"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>100 pp.: Support for UMWA contract negotiations in the captive mines dispute; National Defense Mediation Board; Office of Production Management; wartime mobilization plans; expansion of UMWA District 50; CIO factionalism and internal politics; legislative programs; national defense mobilization; lists of CIO regional and sub-regional directors, officers of national and international affiliates, and district, county, and city industrial union councils; Allan S. Haywood; Walter Smethurst; James B. Carey; Sidney Hillman; Philip Murray; Michael F. Widman; Lee Pressman; Ralph Hetzel; John Brophy; Earl E. Houck; K.C. Adams; Ora E. Gasaway; Percy Tetlow; Thomas Kennedy; Franklin D. Roosevelt; J. Raymond Bell.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d9d34071b0e72452f21ab5a0e8f21765" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Executive Board Meetings.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6cfeb9a324f59b90a471bd80568b961" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_766113c67fdd0be301feb419082ba790"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: Resolution in support of United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; plans for meeting; James B. Carey.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c6a1ff53957b1f0da3f286ac9d97b898" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1941-1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_7707469b68955dcc131f096e44fc1856" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><c02 id="aspace_9541beea9a1dc7f91325a1f27ff26d89" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Convention. 1941. 22pp.: Resolutions adopted by the convention in support of UMWA in captive mines dispute@ UMWA delegation to convention@ plans for convention in support of the Townsend plan@ call for the convention; James B. Carey@ Percy Tetlow@ P</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><container id="aspace_01016dd4558af891ab3d209d3ed08664" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e62e062e55e9fa14944e514f3ddc69ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Audits. 1941. 18pp.: Financial matters@ CIO support of affiliates@ UMWA loans to CIO@ payment of per capita@ The CIO News@ CIO committee on Latin American affairs. John O'Leary@ John Ghizzoni@ David J. McDonald@ Kathryn Lewis.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><container id="aspace_b3fb285ba2683120b95a5a6238a66146" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8481ea2a2dd3ec55df69d233c37290a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Economic Division.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2508a57ff1cebb2b2c261a096bbf105" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e7d6ace375f850a0acc3c56dd99ea0c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>49 pp.: Use of cost of living and wage indexes in wage agreements; change in name of unemployment division to economic division; economic analysis of industrial statistics; economic effects of national defense mobilization; James B. Carey; Ralph Hetzel; Philip Murray.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bdc9490f3da982c1eb9d67a37ad7b3c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Housing Committee.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_7194c8a40f9ab18a58660d60978f413f" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc7bdfd9da28eff211cf4960f0015662"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: Legislative programs; Federal Works Agency; Thomas Kennedy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e538ece8ebb82f05f84d237cfb108f19" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Legislative Committee and Legal Department.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_3243c0891d1ca4481f7bc785763b1c9b" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c51a9427450cadf676571ce3d0023ad6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>84 pp.: Difficulties with Colorado coal production; legislative programs; national defense property requisition authorization; anti-labor legislation; pardon efforts in California King-Ramsey-Connor case; NLRB elections; petition for writ of certiorari before the US Supreme Court on southern poll tax case; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; Labor's Non-Partisan League; FBI budget appropriations; use of injunctions and picketing in labor disputes; Lee Pressman; Thomas Kennedy; Josephine Roche; Philip Murray.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c24fda9ae5e3610e5e6a4f19a73dda81" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Maritime Committee.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_94ca6cbc3a32300c0e719d2b3510bd3f" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_73f59df2d9a9f1cbe76ea2949bc7e3f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Bjorne Halling.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ac8f1f2f6079f0a71d3875ec459b9324" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Social Security Committee.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e508eb4ccec2a10323b2027b0c55d9a" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a87c746feeb1137d6739aff28be5eefb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>126 pp.: Proposed amendments to state unemployment compensation laws; Federal Security Agency Social Security Board; Interstate Conference on Employment Security Agencies; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_596e57045d3e0f552175ee49c2cc30ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Women's Auxiliary.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfaa15e198d5c42336017414a6720a93" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d6416c42e4c5bad025ecf945051e21ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>39 pp.: National Coordinating Committee for Women's Auxiliaries; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; plans for conference; Oil Workers International Union ladies auxiliary; 1941 CIO convention resolutions regarding women's auxiliaries and youth; National Defense Council; public relations efforts of the meat packing industry; Julia Katz; Kathryn Lewis; John Owens.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_22d3069f42aadc053c3084ff34642ed1" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Office General.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_90471fc407654e4726f3ec9846a2d206" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f725860ccec362da9323b6cccc6aee53"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>47 pp.: Call 1942 CIO convention; digest of 1942 CIO convention proceedings; war mobilization; War Production Board; National War Labor Board; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA relations with CIO; 1942 UMWA convention; legislative program;s CIO regional directors and organizers; Philip Murray; James B. Carey; John O'Leary; Thomas Kennedy; Richard Francis; William Dalrymple; W.A. "Tony" Boyle; Frank Hefferly; Henry Allai; David Fowler.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5c5b3fb379dd93f1b6fa2ddfc8e925db" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Releases.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_348f614b89acf6ec0b0aebb24e785021" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_df73de8ae4116203398cb3816f0bd3c1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>429 pp.: National War Labor Board regional directors and advisory boards; war mobilization efforts; political activities; government-labor cooperation; Office of Civilian Defense; legislative programs; CIO-UMWA relations; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; CIO housing committee; Office of Price Administration; UMWA loans to CIO; Congress of Women's Auxiliaries of the CIO; public relations efforts and radio programs; legal memorandum prepared for the State, County, and Municipal Workers of America in support of the power of municipalities to enter into collective agreements; no-strike pledge; economic analysis of industrial production; anti-poll tax legislation and civil rights programs; AFL-CIO cooperation; Dies Committee; support for Farm Security Administration; unemployment programs; beating of CIO organizer in Port Arthur, Texas; Philip Murray; Len De Caux; Lee Pressman; Nathan E. Cowan; James B. Carey; John Brophy; R.J. Thomas; Reid Robinson; Joseph Curran; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Emil Rieve; Thomas Kennedy; Faye Stephenson; Abram Flaxer; August Scholle; Ralph Hetzel; Allan S. Haywood; Franklin D. Roosevelt.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c492d132fd4c3beb976cfce6405bff4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Publicity Pamphlet.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_dae3e3e13549bccc38d4a039e3a2a02d" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_005d41b308324c326f578dddc187b8f7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>114 pp.: Federal tax legislation; war mobilization; CIO-UMWA relations; jurisdictional disputes involving UMWA District 50; criticism of UMWA president John L. Lewis; women's auxiliaries; union organization; organization of black workers; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; government-labor cooperation; Len De Caux; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; James B. Carey.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dfb47b4d6184cbe9c78f6b042b47a1df" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Economic Division.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_c83baae6a7684a95a1c7bd05cea6b986" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_83be4d947f5bd9d3a08a75449d5312b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: Economic analysis of industrial production; War Production Board; rationing programs; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ec3159808c1ce4f9e7e355e94b73ae96" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Housing Committee.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef21d3e02902e357ad8f0df239352c62" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aa070d1a435667e0b00c8f3240ea5add"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8 pp.: Legislative programs; Labor's Non-Partisan League; US Housing Authority appropriations; R.J. Thomas.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a06a9bf0bc9d35f4a75d2af75305209c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Social Security Committee.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_f371ab7f9ea27f223ea13499adcfbd00" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_455e742259a6bca1ef1035d20e285635"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>13 pp.: Social Security committee report; Federal Security Administration Social Security Board; federal tax proposals; Van A. Bittner.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4035103ea57e88eefa859a6d8331d5d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Women's Auxiliary.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_e278d20b96b53db5a169779faac47087" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a846a99698ce338d8c51c6540f430c29"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>37 pp.: Founding of CIO women's auxiliary committee; proceedings of 1941 conference of the Congress of Women's Auxiliaries of the CIO; national defense mobilization; Philip Murray; Faye Stephenson; Julia Katz; R.J. Thomas</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_bb13c6c44fae596c7a72ed259625a542" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1943-1953</unittitle><container id="aspace_daac157df994fafc781f458f9259a4cc" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><c02 id="aspace_58647eff326dbee45616e92ab538d609" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_cebdc7cedd7ae1cd6bc7e7d8db82444d" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_71e10f56dee1f6ee1247dce2106d04e9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>89 pp.: Support for UMWA wage negotiations; CIO Committee on Political Action; digest of 1943 CIO convention; public relations efforts; CIO-UMWA relations; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; War Production Board; National War Labor Board; support and criticism of UMWA strike; J. Raymond Walsh; Philip Murray; Ray Torr.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ec5f6dcc63e9cd461450d4daf56f4238" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_69c3147eb8e04bfac95be68ecdc09eab" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b3a86bb8c431d3bfcbcf8ba89678d262"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 pp.: Report on Communist activities at 1944 CIO convention; CIO factionalism and internal politics.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_80cf6f32e069b1ac3ee44d3ae6af9956" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_178b378375528f7e4ab9252ba9d6dc68" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ce4af4bf2a8c40474b181ba07580f8ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>30 pp.: Newsclippings; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Communist influence in CIO; 1947 CIO convention; Marshall Plan; Taft-Hartley Act.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3cc172f8fa735ee9bd93afc74f04ff67" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_310c829f037f6fb958e727ed6d99a4ec" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f3d062ba921cd890d3aa73c1ec48ca35"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>145 pp.: Legislative conference proposal; 1948 CIO convention report by the president; digest of proceedings; factionalism and internal politics; anti-Communist activities; Marshall Plan; Taft-Hartley Act; civil rights programs; resolutions; political activities; 1948 US presidential campaigns; CIO negotiations with UOPWA CIO office unit regarding pension plans; Cecil Owen; Philip Murray; William O. Douglas; Walter White; Harry S Truman; Herbert Hoover; James B. Carey.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_769439db5e899e93bd9ad902f308fd5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ece3f39064e6c66c0f6247fc123e393" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5628f9e2c11cc730a8238d533a723dc7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>63 pp.: Local support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis and coal and steel strikes; 1949 CIO convention; anti-Communist activities in CIO; report by the president to the 1949 CIO convention; Taft-Hartley Act; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; political activities; Philip Murray; John T. Jones.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a4db88348f4b8add8e0b3f92c1b02e15" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_54d79603681670a3b772b343670b404f" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a4ba88c5f2523cc23d76eedf241ccfc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>29 pp.: Economic demands of the IUE in response to the offer of the General Electric Company; economic analysis of General Electric Company; UMWA cooperation with American Newspaper Guild; labor unity proposals@United Steelworkers of America support for UMWA strike; UMWA offer of loan to UAW; local union support for UMWA strike; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; Walter P. Reuther.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_73ae784ed36f38e7cec6566da1586fdb" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Convention.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5c61238e637c0db7d75b6c435830bf8" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_470c170bcd942a2b90f70f6a05a41b9e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>92 pp.: Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); 1950 CIO convention; labor unity proposals; call for convention; report by the president to the convention; resolutions committee report; Justin McCarthy; Thomas Kennedy; John T. Jones; John Owens; A.D. Lewis; Philip Murray.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f84fa42ddaa862139c08d5ca31065625" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--President Murray's Call for Joint United Labor Committee.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_4202d146a2076375264f0d986bcea9ec" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fb3b9deee2b07ad653dcbe4d223a944b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>123 pp.: Labor unity proposals; newsclippings; press releases; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); local union and public support for labor unity; Philip Murray; Justin McCarthy; A.J. Hayes; John J. Mates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_389c1e57e5fad85963b54867b7766940" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_a46c445911d348a2add4ba69b37e3bde" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_254547ccf0eb5228f5e65949a07812a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: CIO contribution to UMWA disaster relief funds; UMWA support for United Steelworkers of America contract negotiations; American Newspaper Guild cooperation with UMWA; Thomas Kennedy; Sam B. Eubanks.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9a4e6568f9cd1f6b747b472b38272f3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_1551e60cd618ccbc93210d36b78a06be" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c4abffa9956e98b87c06d5719628f50b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>100 pp.: Report by the president to the 1951 CIO convention; union organization; legislative programs; NLRB and court decisions; political activities; maritime committee; housing committee; Social Security committee; Philip Murray.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4a8dacb4b35f063020f1768ab37fed08" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_5788285bc393cee9678e24d199cb3b27" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_71e3defd32b58153f4b0e931a4474924"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>133 pp.: ACWA cooperation with UMWA; IWA@United Steelworkers of America dissatisfaction with CIO policies; death of Philip Murray; report scheduled to be delivered by the president to the 1952 CIO convention; union organization; legislative programs; NLRB and court decisions; political activities; committee to abolish discrimination; Social Security committee; maritime committee; housing committee; Wage Stabilization Board appointments; Taft-Hartley Act; southern organizing campaign; use of injunctions in labor disputes; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm)@United Steelworkers of America contract negotiations; HUAC; testimony of John Brophy regarding allegations of his cooperation with Communists; Jacob F. Potofsky; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; Harry S Truman; Cecil Owen; Justin McCarthy; John Brophy</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c776eaba8d2a56ccbb63ead98bca6fa6" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6f7cb716d0e0c4d86c4788a00999222" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b17df6096b200fdb299eafeec89994d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>95 pp.: United Steelworkers of America relations with CIO; UMWA contribution to the American Newspaper Guild; Moral Rearmament Movement (MRA); Crusade for Freedom Conference; labor unity negotiations; Textile Union Workers of America competition with United Textile Workers-AFL; Communications Workers of America constitution; Taft-Hartley Act; the Sidney Hillman Foundation; death of Allan S. Haywood; National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools; John Owens; Thomas Kennedy; Joseph F. Collis; Walter P. Reuther; Emil Rieve; Mrs. Allan S. Haywood.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e89be5d921dbc841157dc59c93c8b6e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Convention and General.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c3f5a5adbd3564d3eafebcc0953435d" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f7c7ed81739210433b107b75abdcb748"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>258 pp.: Resolutions committee report; report by the president; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; union organization; southern organizing campaign; legislative programs; Taft-Hartley Act; NLRB and court decisions; international labor relations; political activities; civil rights activities; Social Security committee; maritime committee; housing committee; Crusade for Freedom Conference; reorganization of CIO; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); Walter P. Reuther; Cecil Owen; Justin McCarthy.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_0b144d09b24a98d43c6da0e5f188921f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1922-1942; Alabama through Arkansas, 1937-1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_ca101404fbebd5e00b580957d0e68b24" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><c02 id="aspace_89dade51bdbc855bbc31f374ed6905d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Convention and General.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4692f750a05575c7f480fc099e1376c" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af0a61fccdef9cf370a50d059b30caf0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>109 pp.: Digest of 1954 CIO convention proceedings; report by the president; union organization; resolutions of the convention; legislative programs; call to the convention; US Department of Labor; right-to-work legislation proposals; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; ICFTU; Taft-Hartley Act amendments@United Steelworkers of America relations with CIO; US foreign policy; Jewish-American labor representatives and US relations with Arab states; Walter P. Reuther; Dwight D. Eisenhower; James P. Mitchell; J.H. Oldenbroek; Arthur J. Goldberg; Robert Oliver; John Foster Dulles; Matthew Woll.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_17a4e84d7d92408c5bc1bdd4d62b4d97" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_41be7e4ded7d653d637d57f77bba930a" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af80e562c108edffa4dbfd79b17bff16"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: UMWA request for repayment of loans to CIO; National Union of Mineworkers; ICFTU; international labor relations; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; jurisdictional dispute between United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers and IBT; James B. Carey; John Owens; John Brophy; Thomas Kennedy; Victor G. Reuther; Karl F. Feller; Walter P. Reuther.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3502d5300e7e3df01882a0d7977b41f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--General.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><container id="aspace_630e0851c5aaea4df1ec6cbe50a021b2" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_64a5be478a800906199d4c149a75a780"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>21pp: CIO convention to ratify AFL-CIO merger; unemployment insurance plans; UAW contract negotiations with Ford Motor Company; Americans for Democratic Action convention; international labor relations; Arthur J. Goldberg; Victor G. Reuther; Justin McCarthy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3633fb001dca94569ba44eb0038e6a7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>UMWA Loans and Contributions to CIO and Miscellaneous.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1955" type="inclusive">1935-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_bdedd5844b025ba46fbe496c2eab2ac5" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f71a0f8a011f7f22caa6396ba8cdc9c1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>180 pp.: Requests for repayment of loans from UMA; AFL-CIO merger; UMWA public relations efforts; lists of monies advanced to CIO and CIO affiliates; CIO financial statements; 1942 UMWA convention; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; UMWA payment of per capita to CIO; UMWA District 50 jurisdictional disputes with CIO affiliates@United Packinghouse Workers of America repayment of loan from CIO; CIO partial repayment of loans from UMWA; UMWA loans to CIO; CIO requests for money to meet current operating expenses; SWOC financial matters; UAW financial matters; UMWA contributions to CIO; formation of CIO; UMWA executive council; John Owens; James B. Carey; Kathryn Lewis; John T. Jones; John O'Leary; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; J. Raymond Bell; James Mark; Ray Edmundson; Leo S. Tearney; Van A. Bittner; John Brophy; John Ghizzoni; James R. McCormick; John J. Mates; Tom White; Henry Allai; O.F. Nigro.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_869f627849de6b3ea731620fbabeb0ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>UMWA Per Capita Tax to CIO; UMWA Payments for The CIO News and Miscellaneous Reimbursements by CIO to UMWA.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1942" type="inclusive">1937- 1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_383909fd32ca2a63ca9ef54f85a8b119" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ba0ad65cf059af57fe0ab116a672ecb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>154 pp.: UMWA payment of per capita to Canadian Congress of Labor; UMWA payment of per capita to CIO; UMWA loans to CIO; criticism of UMWA president John L. Lewis; UMWA payments for distribution of The CIO News to its members; UMWA membership statistics; ACWA arrears on per capita prior to CIO convention; 1937 CIO institution of per capita payments by affiliates; CIO repayment of loans for miscellaneous items; J. Raymond Bell; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; James B. Carey.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f62697aff9762322b389cc94d8dd5822" level="file"><did><unittitle>Loans to UAW by UMWA.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_f33d3fb790e248bba0ca68f6d5e77f27" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c521b308986abb6de207d40aae3942b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>6 pp.: Receipts for loans to UAW by UMWA. George F. Addes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4ac54382f24053d004efc74c28cea97e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial Transactions between UMWA and ILGWU.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1922/1938" type="inclusive">1922-1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_1167f46091df71d72c4a473e5ca433e8" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ebb4800c871fc7e4a4a781a611631195"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1922-1934 [1934-1938] 7 pp.: ILGWU donation to UMWA; UMWA loans to ILGWU; ILGWU repayment of loans by UMWA; Communist activities in ILGU. David Dubinsky; Thomas Kennedy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d9770b7acf7c00cb8f2e664b9c069b7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>UMWA Contribution to Marine Firemen, Oilers, and Watertenders Union of the Atlantic and Pacific.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a1b265acc7fdcef57eb7bc8d9113914" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_777d5c9ae89d7ef9173c8a5eb5cf96c6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Thomas Kennedy; A.D. Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c336528b1470f5054ece190b416b156c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Loans and Contributions Made by UMWA to Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1937" type="inclusive">1935-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e02225968020060ac2d4df928ca5bea" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_426ce017ad14d419adc0d64e4c01daae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10 pp.: Strikes, union organization. UMWA loans and contributions; Philip H. Van Gelder; Roy Williams; John Green; Thomas Kennedy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2f3b19cb6645a7465880d269c6fec478" level="file"><did><unittitle>Loan to IUMMSW.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_9958281ebdefcc0f8deeb21bb56e095f" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6bea22b2e326d293bfe31a126ad8f31"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: UMWA loan; IUMMSW payment of per capita to CIO; UMWA executive board; IUMMSW membership statistics; Kathryn Lewis; John O'Leary.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3ef4ce11492e99a1b56a7030360ad37f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Loan to American Newspaper Guild.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d64c47235dfd3b61b0ef95384086242" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_175aa0eed52654228a506c22df534109"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: UMWA loan; union organization; Thomas Kennedy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bac47c34b8eae95e3059cef546768a98" level="file"><did><unittitle>UMWA-SWOC Financial Matters.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1952" type="inclusive">1936-1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c00ffdb959a2e7e8ea3f4dfb82b7967" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d193f90d15d4678aacd5fa037fca3815"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>44 pp.: Initial contribution by UMWA to SWOC: UMWA direct loans to SWOC; SWOC salary arrangements; National Surety Corporation surety bond extended by UMWA to SWOC; SWOC bail bond needs; UMWA District 19 bail bond needs@United Steelworkers of America offer of gift to UMWA during 1950 UMWA contract negotiations; labor unity proposals; UMWA offer of strike assistance to United Steelworkers of America during 1952 contract negotiations; National Bank of Washington; David J. McDonald; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; Kathryn Lewis; Earl E. Houck; John Owens; Barnum L. Colton.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e4144cb502fd456c8e87379f6e4d5753" level="file"><did><unittitle>Repayment of $10,000 to Teamsters Union Covering Loan from IBT Milk Wagon Drivers Local to Insurgent UMWA District 12 President John W. Walker.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_2796bc81f70840b9ed1f4adb19e2ac0e" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dea8b8f13831fbb65506d0bc57bed98b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>6 pp.: UMWA repayment of IBT local union loan to insurgent UMWA District 12; AFL executive council meeting; Daniel J. Tobin.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ad498819e901c08a56302c1e726b9a74" level="file"><did><unittitle>UMWA Contribution of $5,000 to United Textile Workers of America, AFL.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1934/1934">1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb76ddf363e847e52d4ed3bef6656085" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_15165d1a980fb8c3677daac146e88934"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>September 7, 1934. 4 pp.: Strike relief and UMWA organizer assistance for United Textile Workers of America; William Green; UMWA-CIo and Union Financial Relationship Files--General . Undated. 2 pp.: Partial listing of folders in series.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c37133007762213eb93bca71d027e0ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Loans to Textile Workers Union of America from UMWA and CIO.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1939" type="inclusive">1937-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_84b56f595e0071805157093f57dee1a4" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_17125a7e45d2b8b0754d1395411aea41"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>16 pp.: Southern organizing campaign; per capita and other expenses; CIO loan by TWOC; ACWA per capita payments; UMWA loan to TWOC through CIO for use in organizing campaign; TWOC meetings; strikes; J. Raymond Bell; Emil Rieve; Sidney Hillman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_53f11f3daed7797dd8e2250a3951db4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Alabama.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_3af8c18e6ce9e623c4e2245c16292b60" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1c32cc853a2a6203488ea7dc4b4ee130"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>11 pp.: CIO public relations and radio broadcasts; Speakers Bureau Labor Day arrangements; union organization in the South; Yelverton Cowherd; Kathryn Lewis; Mary Evelyn Bendelari.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aa1e2339871c0fb48b88960ad4a2ed1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Alabama.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3eb234d787c31578e071599e5edd48f" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe33bff02c1107899f473900d75683f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>16 pp.: Organization of black workers; UMWA cooperation; AFL-CIO competition; racial discrimination against black workers; industrial council publications; press relations. John Brophy; Yelverton Cowherd.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b138c49791e8209241011b40d52d7263" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Alabama.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a7e995cd410256f1e187fa9c2e27e1c" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a36f2b51c0a6574d1ad645023593fea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>259 pp.: Publications: CIO songbook; southern organizing campaign; plans for 1939 CIO convention; anti-labor legislation; anti-labor activities of the Alabama Woman's Democratic Club; racial discrimination against black workers; unionization of WPA workers; factionalism and internal politics; Senator Robert M. La Follette congressional committee; SWOC union organization and contract negotiations; Republic Steel Corporation; anti-union activities in Birmingham; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; local union support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; protests against national defense contracts in anti-labor locales; IUMMSW contract negotiations; press relations; 1940 Alabama state CIO convention; Gadsden, AL, Jim-Crow ordinance barring union meetings; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; complaints against IUMMSW organizer, alleging Communist influence and provocation of jurisdictional disputes; 1941 Alabama state CIO convention; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; proceedings of the 1942 Alabama state CIO convention; labor support for war mobilization efforts; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Communist influence in CIO; CIO presidency of Philip Murray; UMWA organization in the South; William Mitch; A.D. Lewis; Lee Pressman; Yelverton Cowherd; Virginia Durr; Allan S. Haywood; Noel R. Beddow; Sidney Hillman; Reid Robinson; Philip Murray; Franklin D. Roosevelt; James B. Carey; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e02945050dd7e69692e08a5886996759" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Alaska.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_23cb8477c902aa8dc16a0069e07526f5" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04154002c945954084a4bcb91aced32d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>64 pp.: No-strike pledge; ILWU contract negotiations; proceedings of 1942 state CIO convention.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_792d7992b4c8b8107bfdc9bcb6840810" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Arizona.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><container id="aspace_714e4ac7a0d25aaffd0ac8bffeef43d7" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e9103add5fd2d71f0cb32fd059bd32cd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Undated. 2 pp.: see CIO--NM, NV, and AZ file folder.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_85168a2e0e0c82d660fcc1bc4df8432e" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Arkansas.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce9dfba779e35b70aedb2008d44438a5" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4dce08636d473c4ef98244ceaa823468"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>30 pp.: ACA contract negotiations; executive officers report to the 1938 Arkansas-Oklahoma CIO convention; CIO regional directors; UMWA district presidents; legislative programs; David Fowler; A.D. Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d683c2316462a6468fa4c9b38250dec1" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Arkansas.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_914de83164bd0c1693918c3f230c8f59" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_125a410601fae6b9746d8df4d4bc6989"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: Plans for 1939 CIO convention; factionalism and internal politics; AFL-CIO competition; UMWA-PMWA competition; WPA; local union support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; CIO policies against racial discrimination; Ora E. Gasaway; Joe Ozanic; A.E. Sowards; James Kindrick.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_6ce284404eb505107f31cacf60e9be26" level="file"><did><unittitle>California through Iowa, with Nebraska, 1936-1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_bef3b15f763f3de818d85e22f8c6e962" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><c02 id="aspace_78f26e7ef45013119312fad4dae75795" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--California.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8b9005e1985ebe4dd765f8fbdf9453b" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b8b0f380a14b50711ba38092a1179fe0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>20 pp.: Educational programs; competition with IBT; AFL-CIO competition; organizing campaign; Kathryn Lewis; Harry Bridges; William Dalrymple.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_224a65f58d101f45068a549c9684c922" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--California.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c61dd186b2f6248939fc9be92ca0656" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e3d333389280b5608d75c1169ef02d0c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>35 pp.: Competition with IBT and talks between Harry Bridges and Daniel J. Tobin; AFL executive council matters; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Communist activities; factionalism and internal politics; Labor's Non-Partisan League; SWOC organization; Harry Bridges; Eli L. Oliver</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b9d9076652feac30f3f4e2b4a8f55302" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--California.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_d651cb4e3b177c30e3108e46cbb66bc5" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2c09c495f2d8c5486b2aa84f0d8b951f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>283 pp.: Organizing campaign; anti-union efforts of employers; ILWU contract negotiations; US Maritime Labor Board; political activities; radio broadcasts; unemployment; strikes; AFL-CIO competition; NLRB elections; union organization of the film industry@United Studio Technicians' Guild; CIO and IWA organization in Washington and Oregon; CIO financial assistance for Los Angeles Industrial Union Council; support for CIO presidencies of John L. Lewis and Philip Murray; support for UMWA contract negotiations; proceedings of 1940 state CIO convention; application of child labor and negotiations; proceedings of 1940 state CIO convention; application of child labor and labor contractor laws to agriculture; report of the California State Department of Industrial Relations; UAW contract negotiations; jurisdictional dispute between ILWU and United Retail and Wholesale Employees of America; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Office of Production Management; SWOC shipyard workers strike; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; support for war mobilization efforts; Philip Murray; Allan S. Haywood; Harry Bridges; Kathryn Lewis; Louis Goldblatt; Mike Quinn; Powers Hapgood; Ralph Hetzel; J. Raymond Bell; John Brophy; Philip M. Connelly; Reid Robinson; R.J. Thomas; L.H. Michener; Wyndham Mortimer; Walter Smethurst; Mervyn Rathborne.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0c1ebc329f5cea064364ac0c5745aa0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Canada.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e05c7740b3f3cd138201922231dd156" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd0391a5c42e6c3e4e2cff84428617c7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: Financial matters; union organization</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3b535701cbd5ff215d61972052defbb6" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Canada.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_29317860bb3c37935defeac5f40aac0a" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d20537930ae7c8c617d876f7348e8821"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>14 pp.: Payment of per capita to Canadian Congress of Labor by CIO affiliates; AFL-CIO competition; Silby Barrett; D.W. Morrison; John Brophy; A.D. Lewis; Walter Smethurst.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5d808d7c309d404273da92eb527628cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Colorado.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e2b022b74b477bd170fd8861ae7e003" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7124b3491c5bf8bca93a4a8edf5ead6b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: CIO organizers; UMWA district presidents; Frank Hfferly.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_500132e5840a2531fa074a7c8e841ec4" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Colorado.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_b309180b46df422a4867258b8254546a" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_698a0213d6e9cba9603afcee65a56b34"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>27 pp.: CIO regional directors; political activities; 1940 US presidential campaign of Franklin D. Roosevelt; 1940 state CIO convention; support for war mobilization efforts; UMWA-CIO relations; Frank Hefferly; Ben Riskin; Reid Robinson; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9dbe2dd458e035532ec4ed7559df9afe" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Connecticut.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6455d79b10991045ab940a2b5cf5e60" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8de429468debfa68dc1d228fcb88aa0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: Local union support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c34c8d09baf57434e26d7fdb79271d81" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Connecticut.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_f69bf89ce327c77529f0fe8d6471712f" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_84c345bd04a94ff20c1b031decd2e0d1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Local union support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6581a5240911e334a3ebca55c2393d24" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Connecticut.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1941" type="inclusive">1940-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_471961c0618bc18f03a22be5884f972b" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67e3291de1d9b9af2df93b271e14d8a9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA contract negotiations; National Defense Mediation Board; criticism of lend-lease bill; Allan S. Haywood; Thomas R. Malloy; Joseph Mayo.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f0aa8fabffe39e731165b5c52e8a1339" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Delaware.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ee32233b6c40ea8f97a7bb1ff8e0d1b" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b62e51422634d198601a3c1f01e60c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: Union organization; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Miles M. Sweeney; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bf7fb71dd417143ae4e0b2362a22202d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Delaware.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a568e1ee30b52db480bed281d9946ac" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9e78d85e916723f05dd7ab7052f7c329"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10 pp.: AFL-CIO competition; Labor's Non-Partisan League; political activities; UMWA-PMWA competition in Pennsylvania; Miles M. Sweeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7652c41b7c77a1638a3ebe405c588521" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Delaware.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1941" type="inclusive">1940-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6070c2356fcf8802bbae6edb6c0b46e" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1700f7502d967ed9ff608b4344f03bba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>48 pp.: Union organization; national defense mobilization efforts; local union support for UMWA contract negotiations in captive mines dispute; radio broadcasts; Don Harris; Fullerton Fulton; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8c45791507c8c207815e39d512447da9" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--District of Columbia.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_1186edd63524288ff720f1d871f4643a" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fb1c9925090c044a691c9a50d7f5b536"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>13 pp.: Invitation to social event; minutes of meetings; political activities; radio broadcasts; WPA projects; Kathryn Lewis; Sidney R. Katz; Allan S. Haywood; Ray Thomason.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9db5ca3af13485cf35a2cdf7f56d31bf" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--District of Columbia.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_c408fb458576dcdb3790d5726c99be5e" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d23e438e7280f526148e1881854d7a72"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>77 pp.: WPA appropriations; political activities; proceedings of 1938 CIO Maryland and District of Columbia convention; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 US presidential campaign of Franklin D. Roosevelt; lists of local unions of CIO affiliates; housing programs; support for UMWA contract negotiations; SWOC organization; UAW organization; support for war mobilization efforts; Sidney R. Katz; Cecil Owen; John T. Jones; Philip Murray; Franklin D. Roosevelt.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb4f0aab23b04edaca325ac36ea8ffa3" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Georgia.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_eac8faec3966a93add0d1635b375049c" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_180645cadba68146b95a9ed6b581fdf3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fb7a7da4aaba97d6a471603eb6e9ed74" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Georgia.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1942" type="inclusive">1940-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_78b688a71c043fef17b430212679adfd" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96d9e4c56ee31fb3c765106806658cea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>56 pp.: 1940 US presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; press relations; support for UMWA contract negotiations; Textile Workers Union of America southern organizing campaign; National Defense Mediation Board@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; labor support for war mobilization efforts; Lucy Randolph Mason; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Robert B. Jarvis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b90d5f4bf5d96781acfa0882705b70a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Illinois.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_be02fd7f5b1337f3a93b74cc8f218c60" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_85735236693bc7499fe6c3667480a08e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>12 pp.: Labor's Non-Partisan League; PMWA appeal for CIO financial assistance; founding of United Furniture Workers of America; John Fitzpatrick; A.D. Lewis; Walter Smethurst; Tom White; Ray Edmundson.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_20e10cadc80fd36d76b34d4c45850eca" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Illinois.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_d45f0b0fbfd5fac3a31a10829515b076" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fc5e84a2c3ace3b3df3333d24f49001e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>14 pp.: AFL-CIO competition; IBT jurisdictional dispute with International Brewery Workers; Frank Rosenblum; Kathryn Lewis; Sidney Hillman; John Brophy; Ray Edmundson.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aed673225c183242d428876a7a9e75a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Illinois.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_081faee8dadcf0f1d342ffe9b674ad6e" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66d14b2e67d88b865b5acd76ee2cc420"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>147 pp.: CIO regional directors; union organization; UMWA-CIO cooperation; Labor's Non-Partisan League; AFL-CIO competition; support for UMWA contract negotiations; constitution of Chicago Industrial Union Council; CIO factionalism and internal politics; PWOC; 1940 US presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; CIO organizers; educational programs; national defense mobilization efforts; strikes; legislative programs; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; support for war mobilization efforts; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; executive board meetings; support for CIO presidency of Philip Murray; Ernest B. Pugh; Walter Smethurst; August Scholle; Thomas Kennedy; John O'Leary; Albert E. Glenn; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Fullerton Fulton; Robert Travis; Philip Murray; Samuel Levin; Walter Frisbie.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fec75663e26177e5f4e54a9c16b8dde5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Indiana.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_60ac58a838665c3de90fd29517924ab0" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_41a653d6848152356b335d311f1b8af2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: Union organization; UMWA-CIO cooperation; Ora E. Gasaway.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_60454096da62fbace1b907536afd3f12" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Indiana.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_1440c5387cf034ba377438f4ad0f4484" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3447aae5042b73a6d0d426dc7bf35fea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>60 pp.: CIO organizers@United Furniture Workers of America; AFL-CIO competition; UMWA-CIO cooperation; SWOC; political activities; Ora E. Gasaway; Kathryn Lewis; Frank Barnhart; Walter Smethurst; James Robb.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3e593df10be57338f83df942a85efc30" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Indiana.</unittitle><unitid>23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_600c106d909ed66cfc154bf35bdda6bc" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f8c77e00303329ad2891d54bbc00582d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>343 pp.: SWOC; union organization; factionalism and internal politics; organizing drive; 1939 state CIO convention; state CIO constitution; CIO organizers and regional directors; UAW; radio broadcasts@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; 1940 state CIO convention; national defense mobilization efforts; Labor's Non-Partisan League; legislative programs; publications; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA contract negotiations in captive mines dispute; 1942 state CIO convention; Ora E. Gasaway; James Robb; Charles Funcannon; Philip Murray; Sidney Hillman; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Eli L. Oliver; Robert F. Wagner; Powers Hapgood; Allan S. Haywood; A.F. Whitney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_08ab84f947d585e63bf2e1a97ef172c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Iowa.</unittitle><unitid>24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_117d28922d6f38366a29f92f067cd044" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4d1f83e7c9df2cdba5a48f62767727b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>13 pp.: CIO and UMWA organizers; CIO regional directors; AFL-CIO competition; Joe Allison; Walter Smethurst; Harmon R. Ballard.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e706f1e51f96c228ab74d0fe5be6dc65" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Iowa.</unittitle><unitid>25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d6e4d74ad4db00710e263976cb4476e" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_87fee0778bfac9f15753a988707598bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>14 pp.: Union organization; CIO-UMWA cooperation; jurisdictional disputes with IBT; 1938 state CIO convention; J. Raymond Bell; Frank Wilson; Kathryn Lewis; Tom White.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a191100a6bc51fd5bc0ef7765a074cc9" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Iowa and Nebraska.</unittitle><unitid>26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_8941ee0a839f34a56d52d48b2b8057d9" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b1c8d37b9b5cb6b6269fcb5aaaed38b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>172 pp.: CIO regional directors; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; legislative programs; CIO-UMWA cooperation; proceedings of the 1940 joint state CIO convention; support and criticism of CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; UCW Organizing Committee; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; proceedings of the 1941 joint state CIO convention; US Dept of Labor Wage and Hour Division; UMWA payment of per capita to joint state CIO; PWOC; Harmon R. Ballard; Frances Perkins; J. Raymond Bell; Ben Henry; Frank Wilson; Michael F. Widman; A.D. Lewis; Ora E. Gasaway; Joseph Dernoncourt; Philip B. Fleming; Powers Hapgood.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_5d305cb69935494beaf61727cdd38d0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kansas through New York, with Arizona, 1937-1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_8482b2f0c79ee9e000367341a780e0a0" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><c02 id="aspace_9434a492699a8063c4e2dc033184e1e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Kansas.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_3afd5a4755ab4cda3530a2c3c3cf8cf0" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fb90fc87f3d25b5fc6733fe5241085c0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0bfa4403ce4585d1960589f4b119964b" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Kansas.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1941" type="inclusive">1940-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc9088d4daf8be88bf8a45c1f90396bb" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_91ae2154c6948a99916d2d4dc279f005"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: 1941 state CIO convention; support for CIO presidencies of John L. Lewis and Philip Murray; Henry Allai; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9a30ea7a6971e31591516e1346594cbb" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Kentucky.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_f460ed12a62ca74434164333afd63fca" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_42d8c852ebb8905cc5088ac59fc04804"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>16 pp.: US Senate Civil Liberties Committee; Citizens National Committee; AFL-CIO competition; CIO regional directors; International Typographers Union; AFL factionalism and internal politics; AFL suspension of CIO affiliates; AFL executive council matters. A.D. Lewis; Peter Campbell.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_32308c8bbfa9b6ae099d58e0064308bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Kentucky.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_bcb9ed4fc89a7a3f1ecdd6c42412e823" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0ffc8faba9924f0ae9f02cd080c24633"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>11 pp.: 1938 state CIO convention; union organization. Peter Campbell; Samuel Caddy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_afe3a46a68f07cf63104f6443bb04823" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Kentucky.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_c406f00cac2715f4d3d6c3690a3e3c28" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d1ec7c35b6ea66ccc171a00ec83a0bdc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>62 pp.: 1939 state CIO convention; CIO-UMWA cooperation; use of National Guard as strikebreakers in Harlan County; union organization of black workers; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; 1940 state CIO convention; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; Labor's Non-Partisan League; 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA contract negotiations; CIO regional directors; factionalism and internal politics; National Maritime Union organizers; war mobilization efforts; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; anti-Communist activities@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; political activities; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; William Turnblazer; Samuel Caddy; A.D. Lewis; Peter Campbell; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Frank Murphy; J. Raymond Bell; David Fowler; Ray Edmundson; Walter Smethurst; John T. Jones; Kathryn Lewis; Ora E. Gasaway.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_74530eecc20da6cf8aec0dd3bf7a7e9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Louisiana.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7418ab520620e7c436f19f0263661c8" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4865a083015cba024ca6c1bf42b8f914"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>11 pp.: Public Works Administration budget matters; strikes; anti-union violence and arrests; police brutality; AFL-CIO competition; ILWU organizers; National Maritime Union; use of injunctions in labor disputes; Lee Pressman; Kathryn Lewis; Felix Siren.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_df96f7c94ac2e920167fc9dd5b018b65" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Louisiana.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5def6d354781bd1a939665e452a770a" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_55108f3200172ddcc93946efb4f93f19"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: CIO regional directors; NLRB elections; AFL-CIO competition; radio broadcasts; F.C. Pieper.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8a055d0359b6e0a20026883be05e3440" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Maryland [and DC].</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_23d6d2f1645f0e99cd9e84e49758b0e7" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_142886684314a8a4b90fb218a2a6d362"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>13 pp.: CIO regional directors; union organization; NLRB elections; strikes; AFL-CIO competition; US Department of Labor; US Employment Service; 1937 joint state CIO convention; Frank J. Bender; A.D. Lewis; Kathryn Lewis; Sidney R. Katz; John T. Jones.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2ba42b50027e47423c3ebe9b9f4a930" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Maryland [and DC].</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ef1d1dbeb0b5ee8f38128f24a9d8af2" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0fdd3bf08c5dec37a5d2c16eceeb7460"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>14 pp.: CIO-UMWA cooperation; WPA budget appropriations; political activities; legislative programs; union organization; NLRB elections; CIO organizers; J. Raymond Bell; Sidney R. Katz; Frank J. Bender; Ben Rilenge.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2d95d9fe18a06fe8b46a82748cd2d798" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Maryland [and DC].</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1942" type="inclusive">1938-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_d7e1cce1bde825cda1fb53c2aca1a8fe" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cce809a13d0e3bfdeff28bf7c00c32c9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>78 pp.: Political activities; UMWA District 50 organization; CIO- UMWA cooperation; proceedings of 1938 joint state CIO convention; 1940 joint state CIO convention; radio broadcasts; support for CIO and UMWA presidencies of John L. Lewis; CIO educational programs; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; CIO regional directors and organizers; NLRB elections; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; legislative programs; Labor's Non-Partisan League; John T. Jones; Ora E. Gasaway; Sidney R. Katz; Kathryn Lewis; Frank J. Bender; Ralph Hetzel; Ben Rilenge.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7ae59228c66f1312b52ea596e9a67614" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Massachusetts.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_1af7a3dfc42fb2c21d38d6a9a9c7ac95" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_faa61df22ac4ed33810e4a4537d8afb5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>19 pp.: 1937 state CIO convention; CIO regional directors; union organization; CIO-UMWA cooperation; Michael F. Widman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_47f9a854d5a7b1595d2158c6459f4be6" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Massachusetts.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a3e9148a72688bb19662afa4b8fe7d0" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1433b95f034c9cb06c9362831732c0c3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[1937-]1938. 11 pp.: 1938 state CIO convention; CIO-UMWA cooperation; Michael F. Widman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6844a51d53f6a73c78e4e788585da28c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Massachusetts.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1941" type="inclusive">1939-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bc99804540f10a0affcdcc4c3213791" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23bac7da3d0cc8c53582c825fa8a9394"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>18 pp.: 1939 state CIO convention; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; anti-war sentiments; CIO organizers and regional directors; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA contract negotiations; Michael F. Widman; Michael Tyson; Robert L. Glenn; Hugh Lyons; Joseph Mayo; Joseph A. Salerno.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e7a4cbaf8ec4b3d3dcbb18de6372d7ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Michigan.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_6bd271c6c2b15406077c5d7e511ef2f2" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_02527f57e3e93cfac2f744456552620e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: CIO regional directors; UAW factionalism and internal politics; 1937 Atlantic City, NJ, CIO conference; Labor's Non-Partisan League; AFL-CIO competition; beating of CIO organizer; UAW contract negotiations with General Motors Corporation; union organization; Communist influence in UAW; Adolph Germer; Walter Smethurst; William S. Knudsen; Homer Martin; George F. Addes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4b11e9528a61b715648b44ec236d0cef" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Michigan.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_a3852ce4c29c4557f8d518ba7c841edb" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f15139856ab78d8b1c06e32bd3e8aa39"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>99 pp.: NLRB elections; CIO regional directors; political activities; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Communist party activities; UAW-CIO friction; AFL-CIO competition; UAW factionalism and internal politics; influence of Jay Lovestone in UAW; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; AFL criticism of NLRB; UAW presidency of Homer Martin; Consumers Power Corporation contract negotiations; strikes; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Utility Workers Organizing Committee; press relations; William Fleming; Adolph Germer; William Green; J. Warren Maden; Walter Smethurst; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_774e316cf3f00453735bf0636891ca14" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Michigan.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce9a0cf8f00e7b279e3e66168ba514bc" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3755a08bb85a4881348790ea854cf6f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>365 pp.: CIO regional directors; anti-Communist activities; Labor's Non- Partisan League; radio broadcasts; UAW factionalism and internal politics; NLRB elections; AFL proposal of amendments to the Wagner Act; press relations; CIO and UAW organizers; 1939 state CIO convention; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; UAW campaign to organize employees at the Ford Motor Company; national defense mobilization efforts; anti-war sentiments; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 state CIO convention; Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists and Technicians; proceedings of the 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; 1941 state CIO constitution; 1942 state CIO convention; war mobilization activities; political activities; August Scholle; Adolph Germer; Allan S. Haywood; Kathryn Lewis; Ray Thomason; Ora E. Gasaway; Tracy M. Doll; George F. Addes; John W. Gibson; Leo Krzycki; R.J. Thomas; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Michael F. Widman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b7db3b8bc46d40134cd0f4336553410e" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Minnesota.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f9a04fa8f9dfada25cc3ea4b4df0c17" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_40c7418e8a2618b32a0b401552c48337"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: 1937 state CIO convention; TWOC organizers; organization of packing house workers; CIO and UMWA organizers; CIO regional directors; Joe Van Norstrand; John Brophy; Frank Rosenblum; Sander Genis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f15cc6f647e2ebed252ecdccfbd0c862" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Minnesota.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_d20beccda0c4595eec8eed6b8548d60d" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf229bd67c54e3ffbb094d2ceb532b51"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>16 pp.: CIO regional directors; AFL-CIO competitions; Farmer-Labor Party; Joe Van Norstrand; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_752011fa60a189da971ea1bc76adc477" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Minnesota.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f8c866904a3bf5f3c66d7fe1182518a" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49a2c875c0559c3aae0fcb2dbee4df05"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>6 pp.: Political activities; US Department of Agriculture; 1940 US presidential campaign of FDR; Joe Van Norstrand; Henry A. Wallace.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dfcd6eea3b372f6d5b7c40bbf2832a34" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Minnesota.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1f77119acf258d8549ca29c48cace1d" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed80e3bb8bf244404ab7ad970ad9dc79"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>28 pp.: Labor's Non-Partisan League; protests against the America First Committee; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; John T. Jones; Leonard Lageman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2a04c72f7722f9792efbff39b7ef5755" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Missouri.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_98638082062edbfa2de2d6ae8d119964" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7a27419a4350589583e754a464ee9793"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>13 pp.: 1942 state CIO convention; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis and UMWA District 50; war mobilization efforts; CIO regional directors; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; David H. Watkins; Harvey C. Fremming.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1389af9fa28017bdc53ee9201d08f316" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Missouri.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ec89496b31a677c12df3816df68c8b9" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_606c7f377b23427f610c3153610a0921"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>12 pp.: CIO regional directors; UMWA-CIO cooperation; contract negotiations with packing houses; Neil Beam; Ora E. Gasaway; Henry Allai.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c7d879ed907f5394bc4956815da4ea33" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Missouri.</unittitle><unitid>23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_2557e9bcf1eb6b3d8d02075d2e63382c" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dce985630211211702dccc195775e434"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8 pp.: Management-labor relations; organization of WPA workers; J. Raymond Bell; John Doherty.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8f544109690b8ecce613f84f7380b53a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Missouri.</unittitle><unitid>24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9f9462ea548323f32c62cfa856281e7" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2baf6feccf697a47ddfb73322a873037"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>30 pp.: CIO, IUMMSW, and UMWA organizers; CIO regional directors; UMWA organization in Harlan County, Kentucky; political activities; support for New Deal budget appropriations; 1939 state CIO convention; J.R. Ferns; John Doherty; Kathryn Lewis; Neil Beam; Arthur Capper; Harry S Truman; John Brophy; W.D. Duncan; Ralph Hetzel; John T. Jones.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9aa38780a2f3f844a1773d1c139410cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Missouri.</unittitle><unitid>25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_8bb765ca05e8f9b008ff4fdbd5b0dc2b" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5aa2be031eea8b07035164ff80f2522b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>66 pp.: CIO organizers; organization of packing house workers; mass meetings; Labor's Non-Partisan League; income tax reform proposals; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; CIO regional directors; J.R. Ferns; Allan S. Haywood; John Doherty; Neil Beam.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c1d073dbc7211fa416a8f4a37fe11bed" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Missouri.</unittitle><unitid>26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_23947a5d68472cd8d2ae0a224170dab3" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b00d84501ad128b34ae0509389408e56"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>17 pp.: CIO regional directors; Oil Workers International Union jurisdictional dispute with UMWA District 50; AFL-CIO competition; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; national defense mobilization efforts; Harvey C. Fremming; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f3c5ae9755bdbe8b2c745a91164eda79" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Montana.</unittitle><unitid>27</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_211dff916c85d60d061b15cb27363462" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5122ae4bbc9a54d6c7d9566c4dffffd8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8 pp.: CIO regional directors; AFL-CIO competition; factionalism and internal politics; political activities; Walter Smethurst; Jerry J. O'Connell.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4aeee7cb760a6fa97e54c0bc58e739ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Montana.</unittitle><unitid>28</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_c499e21316215e4b30f1c95ed69bc490" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8f9d7409f91f502b9442fde35bf7f8ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: CIO regional directors; Joe Hunter.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4e7656fc0374a271200b8d4828f36df9" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Montana.</unittitle><unitid>29</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_065897b1447033c43ddf60f98981db3e" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1e9caa81880ddb50b61d6ff74bcab34d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: 1940 state CIO convention; American Youth Congress; National Negro Congress. Sylvester Graham.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_481a374135cd3bf83d107129fcbf3aae" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Montana.</unittitle><unitid>30</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6e7b8598fb61e3b62104fe534cb390b" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_148ae95e38cddee86eff0e9446757b76"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: Factionalism and internal politics; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; John Dwyer.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb89aa18239c33005f42bffe43fe22ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Nebraska.</unittitle><unitid>31</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_864e46c22e30dbbcf6051706d86335a9" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f3a9838b58be5b17a648eb28ce7fd04d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: Union organization. See also CIO--Iowa and Nebraska file folder.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b09981c0e423256e582925946b19893e" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Nevada.</unittitle><unitid>32</unitid><container id="aspace_b33e5ad86f7b4a1a7e02bc7e8d1a0a7e" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e6b48f31588d4f4c847293ff2b7d3e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Undated. 4 pp.: Anti-union violence and intimidation. See also CIO--New Mexico, Nevada, and Arizona file folder.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_68b0f0122da89f2171b2fc4bd16ea2ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New England Council.</unittitle><unitid>33</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_71206ccd4123ad48e41cd14a41b252ac" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f07d437203d3952193fdd9d71b9237f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>6 pp.: CIO regional directors; ILGWU relations with UERMWA; factionalism and internal politics; organizing drives; Michael F. Widman; Walter Smethurst; Powers Hapgood; Joseph A. Salerno.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_793046be933a34c48ad059d11a14f44a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New Jersey.</unittitle><unitid>34</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d520f5a0d20200a3c97abd707047158" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_980bf838e67c937579fb2610f85a90a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8 pp.: Strikes; social events; legislative programs; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO organizers; Mary Evelyn Bendelari; Kathryn Lewis; Earl E. Houck.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_839eebff845e9a2f098a15b69afc65c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New Jersey.</unittitle><unitid>35</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff9096012ed50c02e286f1d3653a7d93" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc70715a9858a506ed1ce11439ec3177"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: CIO regional directors; proposed pen and pencil workers organizing committee; Walter Smethurst; W.J. Carney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6f7081156b1c45343c943373a43c3b2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New Jersey.</unittitle><unitid>36</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f590782ed1af7b13aa6ab879918f867" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3fc5584621b87ec92f1a41c380da408f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>25 pp.: CIO regional directors; labor management cooperation; CIO retention of outside legal counsel in US Supreme Court case involving Mayor Frank Hague of Jersey City, NJ; ACLU cooperation with CIO; strikes; public relations activities; UMWA District 50; CIO organizers; anti-labor decisions of NLRB; AFL-CIO competition; AFL-CIO cooperation; W.J. Carney; Lee Pressman; John Brophy; Morris Ernst; James Nelson; Leonard H. Goldsmith.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a9c348302f73d2dcc6fc3529cfb939bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New Jersey.</unittitle><unitid>37</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_4db0d79305a75467a720c67862e76c81" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0860858e97db7d598c4fc26937b6f257"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>123 pp.: CIO organizers; factionalism and internal politics; 1940 state CIO convention; criticism and support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; CIO regional directors; AFL-CIO competition; ACWA failure to pay per capita and suspension from state CIO; minutes of state CIO executive council meetings; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Allan S. Haywood; Leonard H. Goldsmith; W.J. Carney; Kathryn Lewis; Carl Holderman; John T. Jones.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_146f6986763b24446d3630dbcfc9f783" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New Jersey.</unittitle><unitid>38</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_125301d10841b03c5a0fcbe55d81da59" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cf370dd83c0166e057caef4b9704cd0a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>20 pp.: 1941 state CIO convention; factionalism and internal politics; Labor's Non-Partisan League; criticism of Labor's Non-Partisan League chairmanship of John L. Lewis; support of UMWA in captive mines dispute; Leonard H. Goldsmith; Irving Abramson.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_05cf6eb0d737fc718c7affe5c2652dc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New Jersey.</unittitle><unitid>39</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c988d6151e0d16dae31a716d79b87a5" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f82033d713d67e22771d482bff6fe53a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: Criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; war mobilization efforts.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c9d890319dbccd867aecabe889bf2b1e" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New Mexico, Nevada and Arizona.</unittitle><unitid>40</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_42551ee1e7ec84e6b501aa862e853405" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25942238173f5b2f3a54444f44be9f07"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: 1937 joint state CIO convention.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5e1ee33586dd9a9d8ad1dfc8974ce013" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New York.</unittitle><unitid>41</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_64caf9dc5a6a0020f4d30d2ac3559289" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_37090f7f0516b177a167d188a492ea98"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: CIO regional directors; union organization; strikes; NLRB elections; labor racketeering; Alabama anti-union violence and intimidation; Allan S. Haywood; Pete Mosele; Sherman H. Dalrymple.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c685d5afd79bed23eec25b856c920b59" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York through Oklahoma, 1938-1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_3985fb104fb4e2d392772b0ab9e6fba6" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><c02 id="aspace_36c528655748e86fa616c71d3aa1bddd" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New York.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_444fa8e4727db3d2a7827cf891fa4978" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_38287e799b41fed2df86aad1481edc28"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>90 pp.: Legislative programs; union organization; contract negotiations; Utility Workers Organizing Committee; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA organizers; reorganization of local industrial unions; Transport Workers Union; AFL-CIO competition; workmen's compensation matters; political activities; Allan S. Haywood; Sidney Hillman; Ora E. Gasaway; A.D. Lewis; Pete Mosele; Ralph Hetzel; Kathryn Lewis; Hugh Thompson; Rinaldo Cappellini; Thomas Kennedy; John Brophy; W.P. Hapgood.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f99367c3adc8afeb176c9ec2b3f2def4" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New York.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_0697fee0256608e0c1af741887f56d05" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_71c81d518802390166bb916b4564c645"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>42 pp.: Legislative programs; press relations; Utility Workers Organizing Committee; AFL-CIO competition; CIO regional directors; NLRB hearings; AFL-CIO competition in Cleveland, Ohio; CIO organizers; support for UMWA contract negotiations; strikes; 1939 state CIO convention; Adolph Germer; Allan S. Haywood; Kathryn Lewis; Ora E. Gasaway; Pete Mosele; John P. Frey; Rinaldo Cappellini; James B. Carey; John Brophy; Fiorello H. La Guardia.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c2ba27224ce94864f364f59ef26365b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New York.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_beb675b07d696523d3891aa439e026d1" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a29a6efbae5f49ddac0785db8dfc602c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>133 pp.: Political activities; factionalism and internal politics; national defense mobilization efforts; legislative programs; disputed 1940 state CIO convention; NLRB decisions of William E. Leiserson favoring crafts unions; AFL-CIO competition; CIO organizers and regional directors; press relations; 1940 US presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; allegations of Communist influence; support for CIO and UMWA presidencies of John L. Lewis; Saul Mills; Kathryn Lewis; Joseph Curran; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Michael Quill; Abram Flaxer; Frederick Myer; John F. Ryan; Arthur Osman; Samuel Wolchok; Allan S. Haywood; Vito Marcantonio; Sidney Hillman; Gustave A. Strebel; Lee Pressman; Hugh Thompson; Adolph Germer; William Green; Ralph Tillotson; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9221b778d73a2f7a56c2758ddbbca76b" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New York.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_f33fe01210db54798a5defaf7f6baf04" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_effe1edd84d20f64524eecb2914a8ac7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>55 pp.: Council meeting minutes; political activities; strikes; union organization; UMWA District 50; jurisdictional disputes involving the United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; AFL-CIO competition; CIO organizers; national defense mobilization efforts; legislative programs; NMU; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Joseph Curran; Saul Mills; A.D. Lewis; James B. Carey; Len De Caux.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_278dae7abf03a0cebf8a654e9ffe694a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--New York.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_53f180a810f4016288a759820c9a14f3" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_357ff9899602eacdb7a25c4ba601e5fd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8 pp.: Legislative programs; war mobilization efforts; contract negotiations; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis, UMWA District 50 organization of Dairy Farmers Union, and UMWA expulsion of Philip Murray; council meeting minutes; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Gustave A. Strebel; Austin Hogan; Saul Mills.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e48331f2b3108e17242099d6ab46c9e0" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--North Carolina.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f8d4ed4f1a30da9b301ef846fc800f6" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3302d03306192ca2a3b65cd7abd3974a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: CIO organization of tobacco workers; AFL-CIO competition; Ralph Hetzel; Kathryn Lewis; E.L. Sandefur.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_22d5a9e5c5c02bb39a76ada7d99e111f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Ohio.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca7562838f04b39684edc855bfa279ee" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8e81b324c02b77b74314436e6e2ffd23"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>53 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; CIO-UMWA cooperation; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; factionalism and internal politics; organization of packing house workers in Iowa; NLRB case involving cooperation by Massillon, Ohio, public officials; mass meetings; Ora E. Gasaway; Thomas Davis; Walter Smethurst; Kathryn Lewis; Lee Hall; Mary Evelyn Bendelari; Don Harris; John Owens; A.D> Lewis; Malcolm Ross; August Scholle; Clinton S. Golden.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_20b2c1451430791a17b26ed05c61f779" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Ohio.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_4277e600a5e0617f551cc7801e3ceb75" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2e0abf49338250b25717ae7fb4f66e9c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>157 pp.: Political activities; Labor's Non-Partisan League; support for New Deal legislative programs; use of National Guard as strikebreakers in Middleton, Ohio; NLRB decisions; AFL-CIO competition; SWOC; CIO organizers and regional directors; legislative programs; support for WPA budget appropriations; proceedings of 1938 state CIO convention; Len De Caux; Ted F. Silvey; John Owens; Martin L. Davey; Philip Murray; B.J. Damich; Van A. Bittner; Lee Hall; A.F. Whitney; Adolph Pacifico; Kathryn Lewis; Adolph Germer; John Brophy; David J. McDonald; Eli L. Oliver; James B. Carey; George F. Addes; Frank Barnhart; Richard Frankensteen; Irwin L. DeShetler.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_64e1c43a6e7601e27e827236b4eed9d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Ohio.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d61799480629479628fd29b7225d194" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9f386099711187003c795ba4c38971f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: Radio programs; CIO organizers and regional directors; CIO-UMWA cooperation; SWOC; press relations; contract negotiations; legislatives programs; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; political activities; Ted F. Silvey; Paul W. Fuller; Ora E. Gasaway; Lee Pressman; A.D. Lewis; John Brophy; Michael Gallagher; John Owens; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_50bfbf953908f76b130b4e00bdbd4580" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Ohio.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_4cd9048410a2f043ae262e88e9c187fe" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a1556137d1f641a825dea70964f5050c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>72 pp.: Legislative programs; political activities; Labor's Non-Partisan League; UMWA district presidents; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA District 50; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; Adolph Pacifico; Ted F. Silvey; Kathryn Lewis; Paul W. Fuller; Ora E. Gasaway; Allan S. Haywood; John Brophy; John T. Jones.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_90dd0db26692197f261f90b8a03848f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Ohio.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_0eaa6b4d98dd24e0a71dc15a5696d12e" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61274234b4082ae427d10c842c052da5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>71 pp.: 1941 state CIO convention; CIO organizers and regional directors; CIO-UMWA cooperation; organizing drives; jurisdictional disputes between Aluminum Workers of America, UAW, and National Association of Die Casting Workers; 1940 constitution of state CIO; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; National Defense Mediation Board; Ted F. Silvey; John Owens; Ora E. Gasaway; Kathryn Lewis; Percy Tetlow; Philip Murray; Edward T. Cheyfitz; N.A. Zonarich; Robert J. Davidson; Franklin D. Roosevelt</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aa2a5a617cee15b9dc3a801d56170b31" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Ohio.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a22a8fea61e47172b8a2ca9cdf2e98a" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_455615b1b851e2681518d0c7a0bcfe7d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: Criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; support for CIO presidency of Philip Murray; UMWA withdrawal from CIO; war mobilization efforts; Ted F. Silvey</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f334d350fe0d8a23fa9a10f9b8655b07" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oklahoma.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_76abd3658e48c896de49440e8854574c" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1bdae1017a181522fd83d96b920521d1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>12 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; factionalism and internal politics; UMWA district presidents; AFL-CIO competition; John Wilkinson; David Fowler.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_af076e3c7c5977943d9d9c14274568f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oklahoma.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a60570251e8f89e1fc2b6d93e59431b" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b3483d7a159e644408aa97b02353ec6c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: CIO regional directors; union organization; AFL-CIO competition; IUMMSW contract negotiations; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA support for CIO; "Arkansas-Oklahoma Industrial Union Council Bulletin"; Labor's Non-Partisan League; financial matters; radio broadcasts; David Fowler; J.D. Kimberling; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c9a007b4c68fe1c3e42d5595769f8458" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oklahoma.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d478b31ea1e8e757203ba721f2fbf7e" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ca8e0652d6e71d233d411b9634b54d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>52 pp.: UMWA support for CIO; financial matters; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO regional directors; UMWA district presidents; proposed amendment of the Wagner Act; Workers Alliance of America; allegation of Communist influence; political activities; proceedings of the 1939 state CIO convention; David Fowler; Ralph Hetzel; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0585e0001a0a3f27d124530adbf436e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oklahoma.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_067e19fb287cae30a8b004660fd0fbb6" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e98013dee84e62aebfb84aa389ea4c48"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10 pp.: CIO regional directors; UMWA district presidents; AFL-CIO competition; proposed organization of train porters; Oil Workers International Union; CIO organizers; factionalism and internal politics; David Fowler; Allan S. Haywood.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_657aaa81b6093f55132f3e9d8980a0d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oklahoma.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_b11a6537d27a0484e234c5bcbab8fc66" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a4d2bf956b958fda729ee06fa7788ea3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: CIO regional directors; UMWA district presidents; UMWA District 50; union organization; contract negotiations; David Fowler.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1cf11eb40deb1e027b799b7f83c3f13f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oklahoma.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5cc66bb99ec413e9f64945043114d3c" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_298160d4ceaa12d7ee040342e78f08fc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_daa7555abecca29786ce2985fdcbb1a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oregon through Pennsylvania, 1937-1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_b62d825c4714e18eae01d9d93f9d519b" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><c02 id="aspace_44c63c586f37c99ac0d46028b89f4044" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oregon.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_678b815f72706f8792949dac0f1c53cc" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_95984c32ca61e0b0057b0b0895fda56b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; AFL-CIO competition; AFL boycott of CIO-produced lumber; Kathryn Lewis; E.B. O'Grady.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_37482629a3886f32e73b7b2f0d2f695c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oregon.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_45ec8476bc6734fd2e5fdf1020347b15" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab4d0ad692431fc88a46b332338a57c8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: Support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; Kathryn Lewis; James Fantz.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1ae9b159ddb95a48465c0ad739e69d05" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oregon.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><container id="aspace_f9af6b1be5d287bd3aa60eda4dbd806b" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3773213d4bac914d192b748d4b328ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Undated. 2 pp.: CIO regional directors; state CIO convention; Richard Francis; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_505d042a3809b7da45ba9f23c8dfdc1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oregon.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef86744d2b178661e3049397cd6119ac" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0f46c1611550640af894d8f935c72c51"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>113 pp.: CIO regional directors; factionalism and internal politics among ladies auxiliaries of the IWA; National Coordinating Committee for Women's Auxiliaries; 1940 CIO convention; CIO factionalism and internal politics; IWA factionalism and internal politics; Inland Boatman's Union; 1940 Washington state CIO convention@United Furniture Workers of America; AFL-CIO competition; NLRB elections; Communist influence and anti- Communist activities in CIO; criticism of ILWU presidency and West Coast CIO directorship of Harry Bridges; radio broadcasts; national defense mobilization efforts; Advisory Commission to the Council of National Defense; jurisdictional disputes between ILWU and Textile Workers Union of America; anti-war sentiments; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; IWA organizing campaigns; IWA organizers; proposed amendments to the Wagner Act; political activities; US Department of Labor; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie@United Federal Workers of America; 1940 state CIO convention; support for UMWA and CIO presidencies of John L. Lewis; William Dalrymple; Kathryn Lewis; Allan S. Haywood; Morris Muster; Adolph Germer; John M. Brost; Sidney Hillman; Lee Pressman; Ralph W. Peoples; Thomas Kennedy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4d2b7e5662259c8e343ada9838eab7be" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oregon.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec9b0d43c9904b21580c6083446dd8c6" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f49094d9dfa08d99223cf856bb9f9ea9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>70 pp.: CIO regional directors; legislative programs; political activities; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Office of Production Management; National Defense Mediation Board; national defense mobilization efforts; anti-labor bias; competition between United Construction Workers Organizing Committee and IBT; CIO organizers; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; union organization in Alabama; anti-strike policies of the Civil Service System; ILWU and CIO factionalism and internal politics; SWOC membership in California; radio broadcasts; UMWA organizers and personnel matters; 1941 state CIO convention; tribute to CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; William Dalrymple; Ralph W. Peoples; Philip Murray; John M. Brost; Franklin D. Roosevelt; A.D. Lewis; Sidney Hillman; John B. Whitson; James B. Carey; Kathryn Lewis; Louis Goldblatt.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a571636dd1342aeeea6edc7c36855c5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Oregon.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb0dadb7176f8fbfb0ba3c6c25500fd5" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2697528a7cd90c619a1b2cb5e491e8cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>40 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; plans for 1942 Washington state CIO convention; radio broadcasts; IWA and Aluminum Workers of America organization matters; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Communist influence in CIO; UMWA district presidents; UMWA District 50 organizers; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; 1942 state CIO convention; William Dalrymple; Allan S. Haywood; William Mitch; Ralph W. Peoples.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6464d6778471be4233ff046a99959160" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia Committee for Industrial Organization.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_17f61b877fd310b7afd50fb62c5e2e2f" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c1096e1951a6d31077f0988232f74b49"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>69 pp.: Factionalism and internal politics; labor racketeering; CIO organizers and regional directors; financial matters; regional coordination between CIO affiliates; SWOC; TWOC; NLRB elections; cooperation between IBT and Bakery Workers International Union; AFL-CIO competition; mass meetings; John Brophy; Joseph D. Cannon; Ralph Tillotson; B.J. Damich; John Edelman; Bernard Levinson; William Leader; A.D. Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fdd057eed47d49fd9908bcb2062a45d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Pennsylvania--Pittsburgh.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_d73bee8ca2b52ff6b824b73f59d9ba8a" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b5eb6c3304a499370c184f1af98fee10"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: Youngstown, Ohio, area strikes; requests for intercession with Home Owners Loan Corporation; Lee Pressman; A.D. Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1ee6e1afebe1dd4f5358e3f58e5f33d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Pennsylvania.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_b7bc152f939832d8d45e21edccf598a0" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c2b6850bbed77a8756bd3524a549ca69"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>117 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; political activities; proceedings of the 1938 state CIO convention; UMWA organizers; NLRB decisions; SWOC; ACWA; TWOC; David J. McDonald; John Edelman; Kathryn Lewis; Ralph Tillotson; John A. Phillips; Thomas Kennedy; A.D. Lewis; James B. Carey; John Brophy; Philip Murray; Leo Krzycki; Michael Quill; Emil Rieve.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e24b94b905d6855ff8b37292f2207e40" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Pennsylvania.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc31ce25ad3de7fcbe051c62b9ffed95" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7a9d2b8ffdd621fc481c0792d60f49b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>120 pp.: Minutes of meetings; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; UMWA-CIO cooperation; union organization; Textile Workers Union of America organizers; AFL-CIO competition; legislative programs; state Workmen's Compensation Act; brief amicus curiae filed by CIO and Textile Workers Union of America in William Leader and American Federation of Full Fashioned Hosiery Workers, Philadelphia, Branch No. 1, Local 706 v. Apex Hosiery Corporation (US Circuit Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit); Sherman Antitrust Act; CIO policy regarding expense accounts for organizers; mass meetings; 1939 state CIO convention; SWOC organizers; support for UMWA in contract negotiations; resolutions regarding 1940 US presidential elections and anti-war sentiments; Allan S. Haywood; Michael J. Kosik; John Kmetz; John Brophy; Walter Smethurst; Garfield Lewis; John A. Phillips; Lee Pressman; Joseph Kovner; Anthony Wayne Smith; Philip Murray; J. Raymond Bell; Joseph D. Cannon; A.D. Lewis; David J. McDonald.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_16bbe60524160dccddf004c81a5f46a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Pennsylvania.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_4547a46816aecf1ccdd46868a510a2cf" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4b0fb6cefd19e157c8c336687c3c965a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>119 pp.: Legislative programs; American Labor Party; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; support and criticism of CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; UMWA local union organization; national defense mobilization and neutrality efforts; UMWA-CIO cooperation@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; plans for John L. Lewis's appearance before the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP); 1940 state CIO convention; Transport Workers Union contract negotiations; political activities; AFL-CIO local cooperation; organizing campaigns; voter registration efforts; Labor's Non-Partisan League; John A. Philips; Anthony J. Federoff; P.T. Fagan; J. Raymond Bell; Kathryn Lewis; Michael J. Kosik; Joseph D. Cannon; Philip Murray; John Brophy; Allan S. Haywood; William Leader; A.D. Lewis; John Kmetz; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_55c7f023f53144ccdb6bc3d44857495c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Pennsylvania.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_9eb400077ee884b6aa25c7a7b358264e" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_688d82a1f8b00a483c5f9ec2b314d60c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>139 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; UMWA factionalism and internal politics; CIO organizers and regional directors; CIO-UMWA cooperation; proposed unionization of mine foremen; unemployment compensation legislation; national defense mobilization and anti-war sentiments; proceedings of the 1941 state CIO convention; legislative programs; UMWA district presidents; John A. Philips; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Arthur H. James; J. Raymond Bell; Ora E. Gasaway; O.F. Nigro; George Craig; Philip Murray; John Kmetz; Leo Krzycki; John Brophy; Allan S. Haywood; David J. McDonald.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b97d4682345d1a1cb7bb5186c13e2936" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Pennsylvania.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_5490cf3124cd025e99c3eded68f7927a" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5c45b8c5a9b2c03456b4817eb4dd3d66"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>108 pp.: CIO factionalism and internal politics; war mobilization efforts; criticism of UMWA expulsion of Philip Murray; violence and intimidation; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; state unemployment compensation legislation; proceedings of the 1942 state CIO convention; legislative programs; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA district presidents; UMWA-CIO relations; John A. Philips; Anthony J. Federoff; Philip Murray; Allan S. Haywood; Van A. Bittner; John Brophy; James B. Carey; David J. McDonald; James Mark; John O'Leary; Jake Yablonsky; John Kmetz.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_efb9d1679f4e512bf624038d1c443732" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rhode Island through West Virginia, 1937-1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_8a93fe7dbe35e10f391e80e2bea99f26" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><c02 id="aspace_f12e51e4e0170c66f176faf3e4311762" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Rhode Island.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_23d3808a51d6c6bfb82f7665acd552b5" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dbeaba2a96f50474e94e11e2b60a2429"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: CIO organizers; Joseph Mayo.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4d78d9a0b9f232ceccf53b5a10673afe" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Rhode Island.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_02f1238a279fbc85e77aef54822e49a6" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4f61472ad2d1654e9904ba9850dc1ace"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10 pp.: CIO organizers; CIO lawsuit against local textile unions' unauthorized use of CIO initials; TWOC; Joseph Mayo; A.D. Lewis; Lee Pressman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3db508f6e2da1cff63c6d8baa705e3e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Rhode Island.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_03bd442918f03d08fae318e78ce1edfa" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb86dfaeb4f1c1c65d796e0ef2bbbc2c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9 pp.: CIO regional directors and organizers; SWOC; TWOC; UMWA District 50; Joseph Mayo; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Anne Marsoli.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a928e6279ec49d7304e10229d4e6d5f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Rhode Island.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb0464a0269a8c45c6b97f76c35fb571" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ac196f120fd69c4c349bb8ec57f7c572"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: CIO regional directors and organizers; 1940 state CIO convention; Joseph Mayo; Ora E. Gasaway; Anne Marsoli.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3b29a5be4246c85cbaec721bcdc9c075" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Rhode Island.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_a44b3bdbea58d432d8c307c13eddd7c9" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ca33581b6d616ba2911cb3686a3b313"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; CIO organizers and regional directors; Joseph Mayo; Anne Marsoli.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_10b11801962158d90f2270c111c1dc47" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--South Dakota.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa76993eb6f8413c247336c431227449" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_435c88892ae7789c9227555f778a14b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: Local union criticism of CIO regional directors; PWOC cooperation with IBT; J. Raymond Bell.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_246c2e670ef70e950ac117c0627e49bb" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Tennessee.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d14446ef8aed787e7f139ec54bad4ab" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e0ab54c06f90ef4e162179fbc582dcc7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: AFL-CIO unity negotiations; press relations; Kathryn Lewis; T.J. Smith.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cb6b6fa9dc889014fa4d45d6538c0a99" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Tennessee.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e7c941fb1b271ab0843c524b0f46eb3" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8cfb5d9101375c3b13f65c0ce7ab2f0e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>6 pp.:Alliance of America; southern regional conference; T.J. Smith; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6ae497d2fae5a98100fa79924c78f8c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Tennessee.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_4459ea16f12c5daf3c402394e6937d1b" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e5528806a0e5c50c2eaf0fa974f4764f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>22 pp.: UMWA district presidents; UMWA-CIO cooperation; political activities; proceedings of the 1940 state CIO convention; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; William Turnblazer; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0dd2cff3b546d35697dca168d7f21a67" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Tennessee.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a7b318b566cf1b5b686a9bb48415044" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_946d3708b159b5865fe768ed5ca2db01"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: Proceedings of the 1941 state CIO convention; support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; UMWA-CIO cooperation; Harry Bridges Defense Committee; national defense mobilization efforts; financial matters; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Henry Pirtle v. H.B. Brown, Christian Kopp, and W.F. Warren (petition for writ of certiorari filed before the US Supreme Court as a challenge to enforcement of southern poll taxes by the Judges of Election for the Fifth Civil District of Grundy County, Tennessee); Paul R. Christopher; Kathryn Lewis; Lee Pressman; Crampton Harris</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_374b17fd21495f6b5ae0586cffcd17e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Texas.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_65fb9192d0eabb8c32866d324490fdad" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_986e22433368e89c6c0fa9584e85e89a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; financial matters; John Brophy; Allan S. Haywood.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1690e6ef5ea19ce752981a6291d1f293" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Texas.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1acbde1d48b42f50f662a357d53ed83" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35d54dd57d1c325ed8f007b434f5cbbf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>14 pp.: 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; 1940 Oil Workers International Union convention; CIO organizers and regional directors; political activities. Maurice J. Dineen; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_92deeb65a994e6aa5c02ab27ee68813f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Utah.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_455c7209aaa54eeccf5ec6b6240c9c34" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aa9c925ac2fead6599b57d7c727f668d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>13 pp.: 1937 state CIO convention; AFL expulsion of CIO affiliates; CIO regional directors; UMWA contract negotiations; union organization in Utah and Wyoming; James Morgan; Ora E. Gasaway; Walter Smethurst.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c7911c3f219aac603f3cf13842fb171f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Utah.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_584061cce86e30d309194d7eef158044" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b49c4d74380352e4bd4da3eff187f75"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>18 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; 1939 Washington state CIO convention; CIO-UMWA cooperation; plans for 1939 CIO convention; union organization in Utah and Wyoming; IUMMSW-AFL cooperation in Colorado, Montana, and Utah; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA organizers and district presidents; James Morgan; A.M. Peterson; Walter Smethurst.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b165977dc6516fd1ef2406ffe92c1579" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Utah.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_52e5eb7fc8fd80176e0d33356b81c9b5" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2fd911e394c4365fc56705d5df095e20"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>23 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; SWOC organization of ethnic workers in Colorado; union organization in Utah and Wyoming; IUMMSW contract negotiations; political activities; UMWA District 50; 1940 state CIO convention; legislative programs; James Morgan; Walter N. Polakov; John T. Jones.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_30eea3a9c5691c93ce7d0a9375afb46d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Utah.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_debfe44b1b64015dec258d8502dfed77" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6574741aaf61f6fcdb9cdd21dfc97176"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>14 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA organizers; union organization in Utah and Wyoming; NLRB elections; CIO-UMWA cooperation; 1941 state CIO convention; SWOC organization of ethnic workers in Colorado; Inland Empire CIO Organizing Committee; James Morgan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_97a864627dcea14898bcf4f3db4140e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_0016caa2583cc3afa38490058dfcabc2" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2685204481a8e090318448171d1b0e59"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>15 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; organization of tobacco workers; contract negotiations; NLRB hearings; Virginia Better Business Bureau's anti-CIO activities; union organization; growth in membership of CIO; Ray Thomason; Ora E. Gasaway; John Suttle; Mont Crum.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7c952ba170294f5e029bdcb76681cdf5" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_e29bd373472776181190b370b1650db4" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5bed393b4ae5cc845a9c9257f7dac31f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Plans for mass meeting in WV.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_99209e4895d7341ddd86d3e2669535f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_a0ddc56505c02ed8cf1b68c2fd13133e" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_315852a7c9f41d6671a74d05e064f1e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>36 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; plans for 1939 CIO convention; organizing campaigns; financial matters; UMWA organizers and district presidents; growth in membership of CIO; UMWA contract negotiations; Ben Williams; Ora E. Gasaway; Ray Thomason; Kathryn Lewis; J. Raymond Bell; Thomas Kennedy; Walter Smethurst; A.D. Lewis; James Mark, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_37161ec7ed51c46dae47d930dade2a8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb652554f5f919a18b443f15ec571ac8" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c9ff13f9387b1d92724df12fa3e5923d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>37 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; Illinois Department of Mines and Minerals; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; southern organizing campaign; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; legislative programs; Geyer anti-poll tax bill; Ben Williams's reminiscences of 1891 Mahaska County, Iowa, UMWA strike; 1940 state CIO convention; Thomas Hunter; Ray Thomason; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Frank P. Graham; Ora E. Gasaway; Ben Williams.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f6e8d7c8ad0ac9ab0983603cb4caa3c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_6024aa1ab55f6dfddd3a843299aa125c" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ea59b0fd310c7aa67441b327ad807c34"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>36 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; National Defense Mediation Board; CIO organizers and regional directors; criticism of UAW in North American Aviation Co. strike in California; national defense mobilization efforts; Federation of Hosiery Workers strike and contract negotiations in Kingsport, TN; 1941 state CIO convention; Ray Thomason; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Ora E. Gasaway; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bdc3e167ad606bc4667947b74b8b9473" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa18ebc5cd998e5cd19786748ef56ea8" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a15f7b1b824327cda719391be885b368"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: Support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1cd02660d3ffd92fd336eee6b862f8ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Washington.</unittitle><unitid>23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_a785fc8876a6202e85bff304fdae4a18" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3d54cda33dec423a67a2f3a12a5fa9e9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>23 pp.: Legislative programs; support for five-day work week; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO organizers and regional directors; Labor's non-partisan league; political activities; SWOC; AFL-CIO competition; American Newspaper Guild strikes; CIO strike relief; financial matters; Richard Francis; Kathryn Lewis; Eli L. Oliver.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4d1cbb24aabfd1358d68c041010af837" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Washington--Seattle Committee for Industrial Organization.</unittitle><unitid>24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_43ee4b1449a903a72792689f24142483" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5bf6a3213934fc3df9ea3828b5ced5d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8 pp.: American Newspaper Guild strikes; CIO strike relief; competition with IBT; anti-CIO policies of city administration; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO regional directors; Richard Francis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_23a6d20f214c9375c93614587fe562d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Washington.</unittitle><unitid>25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ae1fccd4fcdd4a3841450d92c96474d" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_81c07ceb3f8c2b0edeefda470644820c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>42 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; company unions; press relations; 1938 state CIO convention; plans for Labor Day celebrations; UMWA district presidents; IWA; legislative programs; AFL-CIO competition; IBT labor racketeering; violence and intimidation; political activities; CIO-UMWA cooperation; radio broadcasts; Richard Francis; Walter Smethurst; Frank Hefferly; William J. Sneed; Eli L. Oliver.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8a8c791c9b9968ed661d17844088e462" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Washington.</unittitle><unitid>26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_619ebe66367e535b73f7b4bd3483727c" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c10719dc0265189e0857bed2bc178c9a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>35 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; press relations; plans for 1940 UMWA convention; factionalism and internal politics; Communist activities; 1939 state CIO convention; ILWU; IWA; IUMMSW; UMWA district presidents; Speakers Bureau arrangements for Labor Day celebrations; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; A.D. Lewis; Richard Francis; David Fowler; Ora E. Gasaway; John Brophy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_89177e502d892dbe3354f300a96c500c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Washington.</unittitle><unitid>27</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_385433f4620285b4dc9a971e2f059144" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c8d716ae92378af35c288b7ddfe4c98"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>115 pp.: 1940 state CIO convention; minutes of meetings of Seattle Industrial Labor Union Council; UMWA district presidents; CIO organizers and regional directors; Communist activities; legislative programs; Labor's Non-Partisan league; Washington Commonwealth Federation; IWA factionalism and internal politics; 1940 Washington State Democratic Convention; US Department of Labor; 1940 presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; factionalism and internal politics; 1940 UMWA convention; 1940 Oregon state CIO convention; controversy over activities of Adolph Germer; Richard Francis and William Dalrymple; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; Harry Bridges; Richard Francis; Adolph Germer; John T. Jones; Eli L. Oliver; Kathryn Lewis; Allan S. Haywood; Lee Pressman; Len De Caux; A.D. Lewis; Harvey C. Fremming; Gola Whitlow.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e2430afd36dad524547a17f0ba1bda2c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Washington.</unittitle><unitid>28</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_59c85941c2fa7b04cba6ac0acae642a5" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_137ba98dc50200f7a57cd1dd9de7c447"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>84 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; formation of National War Labor Board; Office of Production Management. AFL-CIO competition; national defense mobilization efforts; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Communist activities; 1941 state CIO convention; factionalism and internal politics; IWA factionalism and internal politics; UMWA district presidents; shipbuilding situation in Oregon and Washington; political activities; Richard Francis; A.D. Lewis; Adolph Gremer; Harvey C. Fremming; Allan S. Haywood; Sidney Hillman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4a9b85b3fad61b1182c0a10628f79343" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Washington.</unittitle><unitid>29</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_a9ece61064edf8ceacf9fca5aa2f0ba5" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_27fde023fe49f3d4802e1d185fde2073"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>34 pp.: 1942 state CIO convention; war mobilization efforts; political activities; summary of all state industrial union councils; Philip Murray; John Brophy; Richard Francis; Adolph Germer.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a8252cc98b8ca851f768b8065b8c0c23" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--West Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>30</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_61f0af639883805f8a5f31ba53fbd846" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c4e6491ee10635b6d2dff974d9366bef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA organizers; Adolph Pacifico.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ef1c20420e91dcc670cadc9cc84832e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--West Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>31</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_daef8f50e7ad20514930229645e601c4" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_58dfa0ec5dc9f1feb23f437b50febde5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>77 pp.: Proposed organization of WPA workers; proceedings of the 1938 state CIO convention; AFL-CIO competition; AFL criticism of NLRB; AFL support of PMWA; UMWA district presidents; union organization; Kathryn Lewis; FDR; John B. Easton; William Blizzard; Van A. Bittner; William Green.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1a0758e461c69fcd5f0eda2c89dcce4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--West Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>32</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_07facce159cfe9e385dbc1ef91599b6e" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f75a46fa404af84265c9ca97b61c0270"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>59 pp.: Press relations; 1939 state CIO convention; PWOC; educational programs; Workers Alliance of America; John B. Easton; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Ralph Hetzel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_80392242dca933361b0540c5f8952c12" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--West Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>33</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_09d8e3e8cef3ec0511eae0bb981bbb6c" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_200df3dc2106a325dd719ddb905f5a36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>86 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; organization of WPA workers; national defense mobilization efforts; 1950 state CIO convention; legislative programs; anti-war sentiments; press relations; political activities; educational programs; women's auxiliaries; UMWA union organization; 1940 presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; Joseph Angelo; C.F. Davis; Allan S. Haywood; John B. Easton; Kathryn Lewis; Franklin D. Roosevelt.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_687afa251acdc073226b6980a16e64a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--West Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>34</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_14c2dda6972a604e0914e9fe8e5fe37d" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fc0d8686e8efe25df1370d77236aea49"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>40 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; union organization; UMWA District 50; Labor Day arrangements; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; National Defense Mediation Board; Joseph Angelo; Ora E. Gasaway; John B. Easton; Franklin D. Roosevelt.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a4cff97e51676de671f440ac3bc94743" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--West Virginia.</unittitle><unitid>35</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3e7665dc039851761becd020bd47e3f" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_55a3a9c14449cc52ae4879ab34d49a27"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>31 pp.: UMWA conflict with CIO; UMWA non-payment of per capita to CIO; 1942 state CIO convention; UMWA district presidents; support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; John B. Easton; George J. Titler; Philip Murray.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_d8041ff220b8e88702d5568519538955" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wisconsin through Wyoming, 1936-1942; AFL, 1929-1933</unittitle><container id="aspace_818b9608805f96dd847ca34373664348" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><c02 id="aspace_19bab91e02c0744769cc0d462c983593" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wisconsin Provisional CIO Committee.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac09c7a41689e25367c79b4d77ba1b96" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_954e4794e07eb53d0fec1c4a3b75ad2f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: 1936 state CIO convention; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c22d8c40a3f0f6e210a50b03480b0c3f" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wisconsin Provisional CIO Committee.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_932a0b962154994036fdf9f76db01762" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6214371c383f8d73339545c39978f293"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>20 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; 1938 state CIO convention; factionalism and internal politics; UAW-CIO relations; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL-CIO competition; 1938 Bricklayers, Masons, and Plasterers' International Union of America convention; press relations ; CIO organization of building trades; National Progressive party and Senator Robert M. La Follette; Gunnar Mickelson; Kathryn Lewis; John Brophy; Emil Costello. CIO--Wisconsin.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e8436d0fb9c79d97dfc3ab365c7ec776" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wisconsin.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ce9a1c09a64d2ad9fabe80cd0f6cd6c" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e226b95779ef079284a86401aa893546"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>18 pp.: National defense mobilization efforts; strikes; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 state CIO convention; NLRB; political activities; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Walter J. Burke; Sidney Hillman; Harvy H. Kitzman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c5c76b953eac7c629f4c9a8cf5de5e9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wisconsin.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e90b66aadc6e742e8e5622b72174f78" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_825970805c55306300f65b54239a969c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; 1941 state CIO convention; Walter J. Burke.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_169512d89e60387b09621630cb7ee04e" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wisconsin.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_b71048434afc336b80d90ac73c6ac9b6" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2e7ea2842ebd1a5561ed761a74660ea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: Criticism of UMWA District 50 organization of dairy farmers; war mobilization efforts.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0908d582e366bd87b7dba796acdcbe1e" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wyoming.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_6281e5d69ab9e5bbebaa6c05f17bf712" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6e219d58d7960edb6ea3c465d468e50d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 pp.: See CIO--Utah file folders.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ed50123c87bedc57d7146290190cab4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wyoming.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_efce2e6555825a7860448d34cf19e5c2" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b24b3074f9de378f49585ef4005cdc85"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pp.: Support for AFL-CIO unity proposals of Daniel J. Tobin; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; union organization in Wyoming and Utah; NLRB elections; James Morgan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_eae649c743558d7a22ab9d40ceed8543" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wyoming.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_4979aac784003f54e702acfc88e36377" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_748754d455ef0175366c92233d73b319"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; James Morgan; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1ec2bf327b8c17e4c3a53514f3aadb7d" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wyoming.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8c272c02c0f5cb5e217ba98ce931cd2" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb11221ce07fdeb27cfda4e9876de631"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; union organization in Wyoming and Colorado; Oil Workers International Union; IUMMSW; UMWA organization; finding of dynamite in coal mines; James Morgan</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_30aa94cb2c2dc5bc02ea73c8a132db24" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wyoming.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_9eccea3fb611ecb4777c04ba1b9fb759" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6151ab58a7745d1858b44feaa3a0c210"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 pp.: Local union plans for a celebration.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e8dd4e65ab892cb07b180453e8e7f5fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>CIO--Wyoming.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><container id="aspace_d7655c022b6f50c0d58c501696f272d9" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e2bf27a63f89c7d81992f1046d00a05"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Undated. 2 pp.: Support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c3a9cf46c67f2f56cec93ae70ebe68eb" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1929.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce2b1e8c865416c55f0821215e94e3b6" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bdc530a84fe360ca0b63e4069e3e47ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>97 pp.: AFL volunteer organizers; AFL-UMWA cooperation; UMWA district presidents; UMWA organizers; southern organizing campaign@United Textile Workers; 1929 AFL convention; conference between labor officials and Herbert Hoover regarding US economic conditions and contract negotiations; radio broadcasts; state and local AFL organizations; America' Wage Earners Protective Conference; warning regarding Communist influence int eh international Labor Defense, Workers International Relief, and Conference for Progressive Labor Action; UMWA factionalism and internal politics; Reorganized United Mine Workers of America; William Green; O.F> Nigro; Frank Morrison; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; Matthew Woll.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_51cac42278d180ac3147c88f5e2a0268" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1930.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1930">1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_720e85a106b244555500af6357e2d72c" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b0aa13630917660f95ebea5e4ff5e0ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>189 pp.: AFL volunteer organizers; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL state and local organizations; political activities; UMWA factionalism and internal politics; Reorganized United Mine Workers of America; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; insurgent UMWA District 12; US Senate rejection of appointment of John J. Parker as US Supreme Court nominee; 1930 AFL convention; legislative programs; southern organizing campaign; support for UMWA contract negotiations; UMWA v. Red Jacket Consolidated Coal and Coke Co. (US Circuit Court of Appeals for West Virginia, opinion by Judge John J. Parker); use of injunctions in labor disputes; 1930 UMWA convention; William Green; John H. Walker; Frank Morrison; Matthew Woll; Victor A. Olander; Henry Warrum; Paul J. Smith; Thomas Kennedy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cae288dd7851175b97b01e65a0675beb" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1931.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_67925831b47523edecd79ddfe7ea9bd1" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1bf0c857d6712753926bddf3fb7a64b8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>121 pp.: Legislative programs; unemployment relief efforts; 1931 AFL convention; AFL volunteer organizers; economic analysis of US coal industry; AFL state and local organizations; Communist influence in the National miners' Union; US Department of Commerce; US Senate investigation of unemployment; Reorganized United Mine Workers of America; insurgent UMWA District 12; use of injunctions in labor disputes; AFL executive council matters; Frank Morrison; Edward F. McGrady; William Green; Philip Murray; Matthew Woll; William Collins; Herbert Hoover.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c4da9b7fcf03e1cb277b6fb20a808a80" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1932.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1932/1932">1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3811475007359e5a61bf532ea70ca41" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ed11a9104f377c27b8ade4675b28120"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>224 pp.: 1932 AFL convention; PMWA; AFL state and local organizations; International Brotherhood of Paper Makers; Labor's National Committee for the Modification of the Volstead Act; Hotel and Restaurant Employees' and Beverage Dispensers' International Alliance; radio broadcasts; withdrawal of National Federation of Federal Employees from the AFL; founding of American Federation of Government Employees; insurgent UMWA District 12; use of injunctions in labor disputes; unemployment insurance proposals; legislative programs; AFL executive council matters; 1932 presidential campaign of FDR ; educational programs; Labor Advisory Council of the American Legion National Employment Commission; National Brotherhood of Operative Potters; UMWA history of strikes in Mingo County, WV, and Alabama; UMWA benefit programs; Friends of the Soviet Union; UMWA district presidents; IBEW; Journeymen Barbers' International Union; AFL factionalism and internal politics; UMWA contract negotiations; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; press relations; 1932 UMWA convention; William Green; Philip Murray; P.T. Fagan; Thomas Kennedy; Matthew J. Burns; Matthew Woll; Frank Morrison; Robert B. Hesketh; Paul J. Smith; James M. Duffy; Tom Mooney; O.F. Nigro; John B. Easton; G.M. Bugniazet; J.C. Shanessy; James Morgan; Lee Hall; William Turnblazer; Lee F. Hartman; Louis Adamic.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b62b2e29248fd5a6386369ff37a07744" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1933.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1933/1933">1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_03f6cf0ce90b38ab334388ef98dd59ab" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c978f09a27e99e916ff1e36ab8ab751"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>375 pp.: National Labor Board elections; Regional Labor Board decisions; AFL executive council matters; 1933 AFL convention; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA organizers; company unions; unemployment relief programs ; AFL state and local organizations; NRA code development and implementation; UMWA district presidents; legislative programs; International Hod Carriers' Building and Common Laborers' Union of America jurisdictional dispute with UMWA; Bricklayers, Masons, and Plasterers' International Union of America jurisdictional dispute with UMWA; organizing campaigns; FLU organization; Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers and Station Employees; political activities; Gallup, NM, coal miners' strike; ACLU; Workers Education Bureau of America; ACWA membership statistics; NRA; President's Reemployment Agreement; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; IBEW; Labor's National Committee for Modification of the Volstead Act; press relations; appointment of Frances Perkins as US Secretary of Labor; International Printing Pressmen and Assistants' Union of North America; thirty-hour week legislation; John Fitzpatrick; William Green; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; Matthew Woll; Van A. Bittner; Hugh S. Johnson; Joseph V. Moreschi; John J. Gleeson; Frank Morrison; George M. Harrison; Morris Hillquit; Roger N. Baldwin; D.B. Robertson; H.H. Broach; John H. Walker; George L. Berry; Victor A. Olander; Edward F. McGrady.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_cac85edaa2782e8652673dcf492e0448" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1934 -1935</unittitle><container id="aspace_1dad103ac78161ab925b88f9562d5e2e" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><c02 id="aspace_4763017aeaa01ba2c3944abc9f7b9853" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1934 [Part 1].</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1934/1934">1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_02cb517b5be3a7abeeafe3532775756c" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d50a808b21bdf35d0807d047a6abf629"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>162 pp.: AFL volunteer organizers; founding of New England Council of Utility Workers; plans for 1934 AFL convention; Geneva Conference of the ILO; AFL state and local organizations; strikes; AFL-UMWA cooperation; NRA codes; UMWA district presidents; legislative programs; AFL general and district organizers; organizing campaigns; FLUs; 1934 UMWA convention; Regional Labor Board decisions; National Labor Board hearings; political activities; Philip Murray; Ray Edmundson; William Green; Frank Morrison; A.D. Lewis; Thomas Kennedy; Van A. Bittner; John B. Easton; R. Lee Guard; Matthew Woll; Martin Brennan; John Fitzpatrick.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b2170adff79755dbb788471f2f06f2c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1934 [Part 2].</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1934/1934">1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_49ca9107d0d61ba60766e57c6936f158" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_531bcac8964250ade2da9d9fecde4d46"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>237 pp.: AFL Building Trades Department; 1934 AFL convention; political activities; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; AFL state and local organizations; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL factionalism and internal politics; unemployment programs; thirty-hour week proposals; UMWA organizers; Order of Sleeping Car Conductors; UMWA contract negotiations; legislative programs; support for industrial unionism; controversy over crafts unionism versus industrial unionism; UMWA support for United Textile Workers of America general strike; economic analysis of industrial conditions; AFL executive council matters; UMWA factionalism and internal politics@United Insurance Writers of America; NRA codes; William Green; William J. Sneed; Adolph Germer; Frank Morrison; George L. Berry; David J. McDonald; Matthew Woll; M.S. Warfield; A.D. Lewis; R. Lee Guard; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; Van A. Bittner; Frank Farrington; John J. Mates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1be1f6dc20f23b69d3c61937dca87202" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1935 [Part 1].</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_ffacba793d1f56688fdd4c69695022a7" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c4c190ed287cb84f40fd5d87c0cb65af"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>374 pp.: AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; UMWA organizers; AFL-UMWA cooperations; AFL state and local organizations; legislative programs; National Labor Relations bill (Wagner bill); thirty-hour week proposals; political activities; controversy over crafts unionism versus industrial unionism; AFL executive council matters; AFL factionalism and internal politics; organization of black workers; AFL Building Trades Department; NRA codes; AFL general organizers; economic analysis of industrial conditions; Workers Education Bureau of America; radio broadcasts; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; Regional Labor Board hearings; collective bargaining plan for the steel industry; South-Wide Labor Conference of Delegates from Central Bodies and State Federations of Labor; IUMMSW contract negotiations; history of AFL-IUMMSW relations; minutes of meetings of AFL executive council; organizing campaigns@United Textile Workers of America; proposed establishment of UAW; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; report on Communists and Communist activities within the trade union movement; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; William Green; William Mitch; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; Henry Warrum; Earl E. Houck; Ellis Searles; A.D> Lewis; John Brophy; Ora E. Gasaway; C.S. Garrison; Charles P. Howard; David Dubinsky; J.C. Lewis; Frank B. Powers; Andrew A. Myrup; Frank Morrison; Ray Edmundson; Samuel Caddy; George L. Berry; Matthew Woll; Edward A. Filene; Henry Ford; P.T. Fagan; Adolph Germer; I.M. Ornburn; W.P. Stacey; George L. Googe; W.C. Roberts; Francis J. Haas; John Green; Philip H. Van Gelder.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bceaca3d7b8a48929d94d168fd4e4ce7" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1935 [Part 2].</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6bc59c5566588ee36d8cc2000c563dd" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed9446e30e6cd3cdae2010f997ca1625"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>281 pp.: Proposed organization of unemployed and domestic workers; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; AFL executive council matters; legislative programs; support for New Deal legislation; AFL state and local organizations; minutes of meetings of AFL executive council; unemployment insurance and relief proposals; organization of aluminum, steel, and auto workers; jurisdictional dispute between International Brewery Workers and IBT; National Union for Social Justice; IUMMSW jurisdictional dispute with AFL Metal Trades Department; controversy over crafts unionism versus industrial unionism; FLUs; Akron, Ohio, Rubber workers strike; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; AFL general and district organizers; AFL and UMWA factionalism and internal politics; International Federation of Trade Unions financial matters; US Supreme Court decision overturning the NIRA; National Labor relations bill (Wagner bill); AFL Building Trades Department; William Green; James Mark; Frank Morrison; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Percy Tetlow; P.T. Fagan; Joseph V. Moreschi; M.F. Tighe; Charles E. Coughlin; A.O. Wharton; Charles P. Howard; Michael J. Colleran; Andrew A. Myrup; Daniel W. Tracy; Robert J. Watt; Matthew Woll; John A. Phillips; John Possehl; Dan Moley; John P. Frey; Steve Nance; George M. Harrison; Luigi Antonini; Selma Borchardt; Kitty Donelly; Thomas H. Brown; Frank Duffy; G.M. Bugniazet; William L. Hutcheson; Daniel J. Tobin; George L. Berry; David Dubinski; Joseph N. Weber; Tom Mooney; Charlton Ogburn.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_1be8c3c03156a4d8f966cda2dcbb267d" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1935 -1945</unittitle><container id="aspace_4824d8620ece247c3bb4f0166c3c1c87" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><c02 id="aspace_198214019c80af9b2683ecd53f9accb7" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1935 [part 3].</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d7529e0abc686eb9ae6758869398cc1" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_909e811939237b104d4bef16af457573"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>258 pp.: 1935 AFL convention; controversy over crafts unionism versus industrial unionism; founding of CIO; an analysis of the mandates of the 1934 AFL convention showing what the convention voted should be done and what the AFL actually did; legislative programs; minutes of meetings of AFL executive council; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; suspension of CIO affiliates by AFL executive council; AFL-UMWA tension; UMWA organizers; American League against War and Fascism; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; AFL local and state organizations; resignation of John L. Lewis from AFL vice-presidency; AFL factionalism and internal politics; unemployment insurance and relief proposals; support for boycott of German-made products; AFL general and district organizers; Guffey-Snyder Coal Stabilization Act; organization of black workers; AFL Metal Trades Department; Labor 's Non-Partisan League; AFL Building Trades Department; lawsuits; Charles P. Howard; David Dubinsky; J.C. Lewis; Frank B. Powers; Andrew A. Myrup; Frank Morrison; William Green;Selma Boarchardt; P.T. Fagan; I.M. Ornburn; Harold L. Ickes; Samuel Caddy; Ray Edmundson; Angelo Herndon; Thomas F. Ryan; William Mitch; Thomas Kennedy; David Fowler; John Brophy; John P. Frey; George L. Berry; Harry S. Truman; Frank Feeney; M.J. McDonough; William J. McSorley; A.O. Wharton; John Coefield; William C. O'Neill; James W. Williams; John Possehl; Richard J. Gray; Daniel W. Tracy; William McCarthy; Herbert Rivers; Thomas L. Hughes; Joseph V. Moreschi.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b9f9952e18c1e2c8bfe792ba4ba4b012" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1936.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_73095bab0da4f12bcebe751ed224a418" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb3347a0dcf81df707bfd108c51a7212"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>101 pp.: UMWA controversy with AFL over establishment of CIO; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; suspension of CIO affiliates by AFL executive council; AFL district and general organizers; AFL Metal Trades Department presentation of charges against CIO affiliates before AFL executive council; SWOC; UMWA payment of per capita to AFL; UMWA organizers; labor planks submitted by the AFL to the 1936 Republican National convention; labor planks in the 1936 political platforms of Republican and Democratic parties; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; AFL Building Trades Department; 1936 convention dates of AFL national and international affiliates; AFL housing and legislative programs; William Green; Walter Smethurst; A.D. L Lewis; Paul J. Smith; Philip Murray; Charles P. Howard; Sidney Hillman; Luigi Antonini; Thomas F. McMahon; Harvey C. Fremming; E.C. Conarty; Max Zaritsky; Thomas H. Brown; Glen W. McCabe; M.F. Tighe; Homer Martin; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Thomas Kennedy; Nicholas Fontenecchio; Frank Morrison; G.M. Bugniazet; Thomas A. Rickert; Matthew Woll; Felix H. Knight; David Fowler; P.T. Fagan; John M. Ross; Harry C. Bates; John Coefield; Michael J. Colleran; Frank Barnhart.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_01a9c86db31e4089df3fbf24c7705586" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1937.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf62dc13e630d388fc5e816b9a72bf96" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_45ec941921cede66df4f9f7b3be73981"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>17 pp.: AFL-CIO controversy; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL news releases; AFL-UMWA controversy; AFL executive council matters; UMWA expulsion of AFL president William Green; AFL legislative programs; William Green; Frank Morrison.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_de17d3b5e58ae76045a473a7ca4e0d81" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1938.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b0097f2e3e83bc5c063a326c2ed8901" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c6453f3c56c8a717abe2717c63700f28"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>98 pp.: AFL-CIO controversy; proceedings of the 1938 AFL convention; AFL legislative programs; NLRB; criticism of CIO chairmanship of John L. Lewis; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; jurisdictional dispute between the Allied Printing Trades Unions and the International Lithographers Protective and Beneficial Association; William Green; Nathan Straus; FDR; Adolph Germer; A.D. Lewis; David W. Davis; Joseph C. Orr.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a36949baa6fbfdca8cd4fd95c57c0af1" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1939.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_cbbb7eaf993b414edee094593a416d4e" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7a82eb34a5dd1e7a3682c3f7f3daf8ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>50 pp.: AFL-CIO peace conferences and unity negotiations; newsclippings; US Department of Labor; summaries of meetings; AFL and CIO peace proposals; CIO executive board matters; The CIO News; 1939 AFL convention; proposals for mass CIO union organization campaigns; AFL-PMWA cooperation; Frances Perkins; Philip Murray; Ralph Hetzel; Len De Caux; Pat McCarren; Kathryn Lewis; James Mark; Gardner Jackson.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_113a3d687fded5ecd4e89677efc5ad48" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1940.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c9051b0bb68fe3d146f15d25e0742de" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_13b6bb21a6e0cfee09643a40d91c414c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>58 pp.: Digest of proceedings of 1940 AFL convention; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; criticism of CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; Smith Committee of the US Congress; NLRB; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; William Green.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0608e8a8e0be06885a65f89e6cce0021" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1941.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_15e9dd5f182f0a52c071d34d3d361525" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_726e08f1e370c0d5724016590b8226ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>51 pp.: AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL Metal Trades Department; national defense mobilization efforts; digest of proceedings of 1941 AFL convention; William L. Hutcheson; John P. Frey.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc4f7c967320b80620baa5eac076cb24" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1942.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_46b909c1b42c81593eae020583a4db94" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2c44f6db6720d8946156a22985d35815"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>91 pp.: Digest of proceedings of 1942 AFL convention; UMWA position regarding AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO factionalism and internal politics; CIO executive board matters; AFL policy regarding AFL-CIO unity negotiations; history of AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Welly K. Hopkins; Joseph A. Padway; Matthew Woll; Philip Murray; William Green; FDR.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1adeac46e053f965692c89f9a87560f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1943.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3705b241eb413f1d13df02131ce9ebf" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f39c86d4de00f56163f6f83d44e571e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>170 pp.: AFL-UMWA negotiations on reaffiliation of UMWA; reaction of AFL unions to application for reaffiliation of UMWA; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; war mobilization efforts; allegations of Communist Influence of CIO; digest of proceedings of 1943 AFL convention; news releases; National War Labor Board; IBT strikes; no-strike pledge; AFL state and local organizations; newsclippings; Daniel J. Tobin; John O'Leary; Thomas Kennedy; Percy Tetlow; A.D. Lewis; John Kmetz; William Green; Matthew Woll; George Q. Lynch; George L. Berry; David Dubinsky; John Hawk; FDR; Victor A. Olander; William Davis; I.M. Ornburn.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_658995694b1799114bdaf61945ab3899" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. [1943-]1944.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1944" type="inclusive">1943-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_53d360a6303058ae03932ae0e22662a4" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_307f366ab683b3c237570841d8a9f097"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>98 pp.: Report of proceedings of 1944 AFL convention; AFL executive council failure to act on UMWA applications for reaffiliation and UMWA withdrawal of application; AFL-UMWA unity negotiations; AFL jurisdictional disputes with UMWA District 50; AFL executive council matters; Thomas Kennedy; William Green; Daniel J. Tobin; George Meany; Matthew Woll; Harry C. Bates; A.D. Lewis; John Kmetz.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cd1b533570738f85ca0db15befe41f63" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. [1943-]1945.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1945" type="inclusive">1944-1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_5bda43e84d8d227dcc9ff7c72705327f" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e9624c748ddb6dc6843b14645d917e40"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>97 pp.: AFL-UMWA controversy and unity negotiations; UMWA application for reaffiliation with AFL; report of proceedings of 1943 AFL convention; AFL executive council matters; war mobilization efforts; legislative programs; AFL jurisdictional disputes with UMWA District 50; Daniel J. Tobin; William Green; Matthew Woll; Boris Shishkin; John T. Mates; George Meany</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_b613266a3d3fa3fec74397c838cd940b" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1946 -1947</unittitle><container id="aspace_09457e2e23701169e5048c90fff14aab" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><c02 id="aspace_c21b7c0043d68f64f7e5dd9f6fb9c31e" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--State Federations of Labor.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_a49ba59b25de34b1120a86f2b45859c3" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1e4003db54ca7996d5df2e79890a41eb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>97 pp.: State AFL organizations; AFL general and district presidents; AFL southern organizing campaign; Labor's Non-partisan League; congratulations on UMWA reaffiliation with AFL; George L. Googe; Joe Morris; David Fowler; John T. Jones.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8905fd471ba355fe83b1c2916c86a8ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--General.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c29b42b1041a069250fb905b587673b" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_adaadeaa33b02d70ccca788f7987bc63"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>265 pp.: Local AFL organizations; UMWA District 50; press relations; political activities; use of injunctions in labor disputes; UMWA contract negotiations; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL executive council matters; AFL-CIO cooperative proposals; international labor relations; southern organizing campaigns; AFL-CIO competition; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Communist influence in the CIO; AFL general and district organizers; political activities; labor racketeering activities; health and welfare fund manipulations; Union Labor Life Insurance Company; legislative programs; UMWA public relations; UMWA reaffiliation with AFL; UMWA payment of per capita to AFL; John J. Mates; Matthew Woll; Harry S Truman; Drew Pearson; Thomas Kennedy; William Green; Philip Murray; George L. Googe; George Meany; John T. Jones; A.D. Lewis; Cecil Owen; I.M. Ornburn; Roy M. Brewer; Ora E. Gasaway.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_86936f6a955cc2b9ec5ebbfc0a5e9d6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Convention.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_746eece94d18e81124b577635cdcf1cd" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f705883c1f5b716ec5ffb079b48a3538"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>84 pp.: Minutes of meetings of AFL executive council during 1946 AFL convention; jurisdictional disputes; AFL state and local organizations; international labor relations; organizing drives; plans for 1946 AFL convention; WFTU; UMWA district presidents; UMWA reaffiliation with AFL; William Green; Jesse Clark; Ed J. Brown; J.J. Duffy; George Meany; H.W. Davis; W.D. Mahon; George M. Harrison; Matthew Woll; William C. Doherty; K.C. Adams.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4cee53a18ad8855631e8d45e4ab458ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Minutes of Meetings of AFL Executive Council.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_7efaf7166538139a67d0425620c51fb9" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d70dc282a7b0413f91a9900021d4a5c0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>January 21-31, 1946. 200 pp.: Acceptance of UMWA application for reaffiliation with AFL; election of John L. Lewis to the AFL executive council; UMWA-PMWA competition; AFL factionalism and internal politics; International Association of Machinists' refusal to pay per capita to the AFL; AFL state and local organizations; legislative programs; jurisdictional disputes; international labor relations; International Federation of Trade Unions (IFTU); AFL Metal Trades Department; AFL Building and Construction Trades Department; postwar conversion plans; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; AFL-CIO competition; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; AFL general and district organizers; statistics regarding NLRB elections, 1941-1945; Olin Industries v. Joseph Barnett, et al. (US District Court for the Southern District of Illinois, opinion by Charles G. Briggle regarding reemployment of World War II veterans); William Green; Frank P. Fenton; John A. Owens; Walter Schevenels; William J. Kromelbein; Joseph N. Weber; A. Persion; William E. Maloney; Felix H. Knight; W.C. Birthright; William C. Doherty; Percy R. Bengough; George Meany.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e3abc8e591d79e5e11a9fc08af5718a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Minutes of Meetings of AFL Executive Council.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_426fdbe428015405fec0c14aee52556f" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3ee44032a57f8c9b37ebf1d66246dde8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>May 15-22, 1946. 133 pp.: International Association of Machinists' refusal to pay per capita to the AFL; jurisdictional disputes; AFL state and local organizations; US Congress anti-labor legislation proposals; political activities; legislative programs; public relations activities; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; international labor relations; southern organizing campaign; withdrawal of PMWA from AFL; NLRB decisions; AFL-CIO competition in the canning industry; IBT; AFL Building and Construction Trades Department; AFL general and district organizers; financial matters; AFL Metal Trades Department; AFL general and district organizers; financial matters; AFL Metal Trades Department; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; William Green; W.D. Mahon; George Meany; Harvey W. Brown; Woodruff Randolph; John Clinton; Earl Evans; Lester Washburn; Joseph D. Keenan; John P. Frey.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ac647a252334a6d9096d100cdf1e996b" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Minutes of Meetings of AFL Executive Council.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_51d774c53cb3ac15654408fd491a99ea" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aef1516cbd5de4a42cc3088ff40dc904"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>August 12-20, 1946. 195 pp.: International labor relations; AFL state and local organizations; Nebraska right-to-work state anti-labor relations; AFL state and local organizations; Nebraska right-to-work state anti-labor legislation; International Association of Machinists' disassociation from AFL; ILO; AFL Building and Construction Trades Department; jurisdictional disputes; IBT; National Farm Labor Union granted AFL affiliation; legislative programs; AFL-CIO competition; southern organizing campaign; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; AFL general and district organizers; AFL executive council report; farmers cooperative; retirement plans; organization of black workers@United Textile Workers of America; financial matters; membership of and payment per capita by AFL affiliates; William Green; W.D. Mahon; Percy R. Bengough; George W. Lawson; H.L. Mitchell; Matthew Woll; David Dubinsky; A.L. Spradling; James C. Petrillo; Daniel V. Flanagan; William L. Hutcheson; Walter Cenerazzo; Felix H. Knight; W.C. Birthright; William C. Doherty; George Meany; Daniel J. Tobin; William E. Maloney; James A. McConnell; George L. Googe.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4cca252cbd78dbcf9b5b4e2c4525c5ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--State Federations of Labor.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5082dfe11e68f91307750608c1dddab" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e5f55c356ec4717cf27cf5dd782d9ae3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>53 pp.: UMWA district presidents; 1947 West Virginia state AFL convention; AFL state and local organizations; Taft-Hartley Act; support for UMWA contract negotiations; Illinois state AFL publications; D.M. Stamper; Cecil J. Urbaniak; William Blizzard; George J. Titler; Ray Thomason; Joseph Angelo; Harry Bennett; R.O. Lewis; William Green; George Meany; Matthew Woll.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5cf1198f1f08ad94a1a5fc664aeeb69d" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL-CIO Unity File.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_03d934b48478bd958737749b8fe23206" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f65d31a745cde0d7040e8af1ce15bb56"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>55 pp.: AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL executive council matters; CIO executive board matters; local union support for AFL-CIO unity; press relations; William Green; Philip Murray; George Meany; William L. Hutcheson; Daniel J. Tobin; Harry C. Bates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3ea5d7e01a1e88458e691da8c48aed35" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Central Labor Unions.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f6f072e06d15f91d24f34fa7816f378" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_08872d041317adc8411d46d7a3a1c696"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>45 pp.: AFL state and local organizations; Taft-Hartley Act; political activities; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; legislative programs; William Green.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_eb27845fac6adc2f7b959a4fae6bd94c" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Central Labor Unions.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_710b4571eb2932637abcf4e4fc84bca5" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de2c7b1d62ccce36f5c9ec11763d4d9f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>16 pp.: AFL state and local organizations; southern organizing campaign; support for UMWA contract negotiations.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_75b0f1638491e6faf6135ba3c8de822d" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--General.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ccd93ab680a9f07d2d437faa08c2dfb" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d8d64de1ee6548c4ea5fea407bfdbc64"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>248 pp.: UMWA re-withdrawal from AFL; Havana Conference on Trade and Employment; international labor relations; National Farm Labor Union strike in Bakersfield, California; 1947 AFL convention; Taft-Hartley Act; UMWA district presidents; UMWA executive board; UMWA refusal to pay per capita to AFL; AFL executive council matters; negotiations with International Association of Machinists for reaffiliation with AFL; AFL housing committee; AFL state and local organizations; AFL general and district organizers; support for UMWA contract negotiations; legislative programs; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; jurisdictional disputes; UMWA District 50; AFL Building and Construction Trades Department; AFL-CIO competition; political activities; public relations efforts; ILO; UMWA loan to National Federation of Telephone Workers; US government legal case against UMWA; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; Labor's Non-Partisan League; William L. Hutcheson; William Green; Lee W. Minton; Lewis C. Thorne; George Meany; Matthew Woll; Harvey W. Brown; Eric Peterson; John O'Leary; A.D. Lewis; Frank P. Fenton; Daniel J. Tobin; David Dubinsky; Richard F. Walsh; Daniel W. Tracy; George J. Titler; Richard J. Gray; Harry S Truman; Robert J. Watt; John Kmetz; Thomas Kennedy; Joseph Beirne; Joseph A. Padway; William C. Doherty; Philip Murray; John T. Jones; I.M. Ornburn; Irving Brown.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_f56a7b1ab9a133ff38976125770ddc3f" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1947 -1955</unittitle><container id="aspace_978ca425d1cc8b50300452fdc14cb13f" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><c02 id="aspace_8c9a37b586f961ffbb0731d608986543" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Convention.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d49224ccd3c2e7d7c756e5b54f3dc82" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_366df7d023bb5df1b5c840b24a6a7249"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>October 1947. 69 pp.: Report of proceedings of 1947 convention; international labor relations; Taft- Hartley Act; AFL factionalism and internal politics; plans for 1947 AFL convention; William Green; Joseph P. Keenan; Thomas Kennedy; Daniel J. Tobin; George Meany; Lester Washburn; David Dubinsky; Harry S Truman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc47c5b26ed6d382ddc3112dd0775bd4" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Building.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6056f741d1f5a904fdc247649571664" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a8a467f1ae51db39e37cfdae8979904"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>26 pp.: Plans for purchase of property in the District of Columbia; financial matters; AFL executive council matters; William Green; George Meany.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c354617fd5c4f72217beaadae749d53f" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Executive Council Meetings.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0dbd57b4288e807b0cacdc9e41d7704" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a24e5df433138f548631f95cbbb17b1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>248 pp.: Minutes of meetings of the AFL executive council; postwar conversion; international labor relations; jurisdictional disputes; international Association of Machinists; Allied Printing Trades Council; legislative programs; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; British Trades Union Congress; southern organizing campaign; US government legal case against UMWA; retirement annuity plan for AFL employees; anti-labor legislation; financial matters; AFL general and district organizers; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; postwar economic conditions in Germany; plans for purchase of property in the District of Columbia; George Meany; Henry Rutz; William Green; George L. Berry; Edward J. Volz; Philip Murray; Joseph N. Weber; Robert Montgomery; Ed J. Brown; Thomas Kennedy; Matthew J. Burns; Richard F. Walsh; Hugo Ernst; William L. Hutcheson; William C. Doherty; Israel Feinberg; W.D. Mahon; W.C. Birthright; Felix H. Knight; Frank Duffy; William E. Maloney; John F. McNamara; Dean Acheson.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5c3f057f8b77dddf1bb3be99d7b2dd83" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1948.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9ce8a40bac10bc3d2e575ca9d22faca" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2c4abee9940c58ccb674acde04d2fde"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: UMWA withdrawal from AFL; 1948 AFL convention; international labor relations; support for UMWA contract negotiations; AFL executive council matters; use of injunctions in labor disputes; AFL state and local organizations; AFL cooperation with UMWA in legal case before the US Supreme Court; AFL educational programs; John Owens; Thomas Kennedy; William Green; Leon Blum; Matthew Woll.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e344945814e6ede9a648ce49078a3531" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1949.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_bbc4d0be706042a7b15ab39557ab28bf" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ec1ac37946e0b3eb80735f791b133750"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>34 pp.: Criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; proposed AFL strike fund assistance for United Steelworkers of America; support for labor unity negotiations; International Fishermen and Allied Workers of America; AFL and UMWA state and local organizations; William Green; J.F. Jurich; Philip Murray; George Griffiths; Thomas Kennedy; Florence Thorne; John J. Mates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9e3256deb81318c275920afa581ff404" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1950.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_5010ccc025af5c3765fc899652da5ef6" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_40721d7d96765868c57a4800586dcf46"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>111 pp.: AFL educational programs; minutes of meetings of Workers Education Bureau of America; AFL absorption of Workers Education Bureau of America; ILGWU-UMWA cooperation; ILGWU strikes; UMWA district presidents; AFL and UMWA support for community chest campaigns; international labor relations; Economic Cooperation Administration; UMWA health and safety programs; labor-management cooperation; labor unity negotiations; economic conditions in Argentina; support for UMWA contract negotiations; AFL-UMWA cooperation; John D. Connors; Thomas Kennedy; Michael J. Kosik; Thomas M. Holleran; Reg Kennedy; Matthew Woll; William Green; Philip Murray; Philip Reed; Serafino Romualdi; A.J. Hayes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_45563e94ae5cbecee638501e9da8ce69" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1950.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_2339bbfdaeb4185b8d4cfa04ef3bf3d8" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_feb6d609a68a8910cff013c9e91c3529"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>24 pp.: 1950 AFL convention; UMWA District 50 competition with AFL; proposed AFL organization of coal miners; 1950 AFL Indiana state convention; UMWA district presidents; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL no-strike pledge; support for UMWA contract negotiations; Louis Austin; William Green; W.P. Kennedy; H.W. Fraser; Alvanley Johnston; A.J. Hayes; Philip Murray; John Owens.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_45f5213943a96ff29da0c0051770a545" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1951.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_823221558b0ad40a637bcd6181924a9c" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7545a58d0891c05ee1cb7d56493ebe97"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>65 pp.: AFL support for community chest campaigns@United Defense Fund support for USO clubs; legislative programs; political activities; the Smith Act (anti-labor legislation); international labor relations; AFL publications; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); AFL-CIO unity negotiations; William Green; Woodruff Randolph; Thomas Kennedy; Justin McCarthy; A. Philip Randolph; Reg Kennedy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3d53cdea079ffef20f161149f9539244" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1951.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_527c8c18536dcac543b61d7c568cbbea" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ed3b0e62b9f52cc24db1609bdd762cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>44 pp.: AFL-UMWA cooperation; US importation of natural gas from Canada; radio broadcasts; AFL publications; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); Taft-Hartley Act; AFL Construction and Building Trades Department; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; 1951 AFL convention; press relations; UMWA organization in Kentucky; William Green; Thomas Kennedy; Harry S Truman; Justin McCarthy; Richard J. Gray.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dbf2fd1ede48cbb3473065dc9c4b73a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1952.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_7849feadf4131ae25285e8d1024007df" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9c0a6da6fc7e6715b4626c8e9458f8d1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>53 pp.: 1952 ACA convention; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; AFL press relations; investigation of the ILA on labor racketeering charges; international labor relations; 1952 AFL convention; Taft-Hartley Act; Labor's Non-Partisan League; international labor relations; AFL-UMWA cooperation; 1952 ILO conference; US importation of natural gas from Canada; Joseph P. Selly; Len De Caux; Thomas Kennedy; John J. Mates; William Green; John T. Jones; George P. Delaney; Paul K. Reed; John Owens.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a8843b4042cb25ffcd8b25921315b820" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1952.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb4f3afa235af8b80e3aeb9574916ee9" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7479b09b4e9abe6c7016041eb7c473e7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>70 pp.: National Committee for Labor Israel; AFL health and welfare programs; AFL health and welfare programs; AFL support for community chest programs; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; international labor relations; Taft-Hartley Act; legislative programs; political activities; AFL and CIO proposals before the 1952 Republican National Convention; UMWA mine safety legislative programs; UMWA District 50 jurisdictional dispute with International Typographical Union; George Meany; Thomas Kennedy; Mrs. William Green; Reg Kennedy; William Green; George P. Delaney; James B. Carey; Walter P. Reuther; John Owens; A.D. Lewis; Woodruff Randolph.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ad8705f7a0367383fe4755a6bf0c0ff0" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1953.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_2453bd6ff9d07aeb39a86334beb32039" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4702dd47a04e801d80ac6c2569340ddb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>35 pp.: AFL-CIO negotiations; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm)@United Brotherhood of Carpenters withdrawal from AFL; 1953 AFL convention; international labor relations; Moral Re-Armament Movement (MRA); UMWA District 50; UMWA-IBT cooperation; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL state and local organizations; UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; ILGWU organizers; Thomas Kennedy; John Owens; M.A. Hutcheson; Dave Beck; William F. Schnitzler; Edward Kennedy; James L. McDevitt.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cc0bb3bacf2c72ba1396d08f84efad02" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1953.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe80676e0f0ccad4ca4a1273f124a593" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd77947f0c69143c533624b2195dcf4f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>35 pp.: International Union of Operating Engineers labor racketeering; AFL Construction and Building Trades Department; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL press relations; television broadcasts; Cecil Owen; George Meany.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4a0598b97b80527d3cc51b9c6390f2b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1954.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_27fae73a7751f7947ad11ae819e19e95" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af0944370b1e3a9f6545ce7822d8c171"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>47 pp.: Support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UAW factionalism and internal politics; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); conference of AFL and CIO maritime unions; Sailors' Union of the Pacific; UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; international labor relations; Jules Kimmett; Justin McCarthy; John T. Jones; Matthew Woll.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_101b4c8f0f35cf2ae543f264bc226259" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1954.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8088f4d3d06f30af780b4348f03d8a5" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c91589965164bbcc34af94d2f037af3f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>114 pp.: ILA-IBT cooperation; NLRB decisions; AFL educational programs; criticism of Senator Joseph McCarthy; legislative programs; political activities; international labor relations; analysis of voting records of US congressmen; AFL support for community chest programs; UMWA pension fund applications; Moral Re-Armament Movement (MRA); UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; American Newspaper Guild strikes; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Taft-Hartley Act; CIO legislative programs; Dave Beck; James L. McDevitt; Thomas Kennedy; George Meany; Martin F. Durkin; Matthew Woll; David J. McDonald; Jacob F. Potofsky; Arthur J. Goldberg; Robert Oliver.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_67761eee15fe8fd4162fe37ecd44ea79" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL. 1954-1955.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1955" type="inclusive">1954-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_57723d966d36000e2ab1b1569882837d" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9e69ad180c946b37ae12da0ce3f909dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[1954-]1955. 50 pp.: AFL-CIO no-raiding agreement; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO publications; AFL-CIO constitution; 1955 AFL-CIO convention; AFL-CIO merger; international labor relations; AFL state and local organizations; Walter P. Reuther; George Meany; David Dubinsky; Anthony Wayne Smith; Richard H. Stroud; J. Scott Milne; Joseph D. Keenan; M.A. Hutcheson; George Duffy.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_5b0377ec2f2d22c98e8200d798a97b36" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Labor Unity, 1942-1956; United Steelworkers of America, 1949-1962</unittitle><container id="aspace_3d06ad475b49dec82546bb76f3b6bd23" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><c02 id="aspace_86b24451164e405ba8daf661427547a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Labor Unity--AFL-CIO merger.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_615e35e8a5d5f40c7e2ee8a61f4e0fe3" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e39088bd131516beaa8862adefe289de"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>December 1, 1955. 165 pp.: Television broadcasts; press relations; newsclippings; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; analysis of AFL-CIO membership, leadership, and organization power of affiliates; Transport Workers Union; UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; AFL-CIO organizing campaigns; M.S. Rukeyser; James B. Carey; Justin McCarthy; Rex Lauck.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cc37cca9027db600a58a3287e07d90a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Labor Unity.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f1b65ea9d52b30b885ea3d86380114c" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f649c2a7ed85cd9b3dd52ae513f67748"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>41 pp.: Newsclippings regarding AFL-CIO merger.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fed4887273c958dc6cee3c2446262940" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL--Labor Unity--Regarding Matter of Loan to CIO from UMWA.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1956" type="inclusive">1942-1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4088970068cd9a4c119c04f07630e72" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6d6233689d85206712001a7a2706fee6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>45 pp.: Newsclippings regarding AFL-CIO merger and UMWA demand for repayment of loans to CIO; UMWA demand for repayment of loans to CIO; UMWA non-payment of per capita tax prior to withdrawal from CIO; report on money owed to UMWA by CIO; statement of financial relationship of UMWA and CIO; James B. Carey; John Owens; Thomas Kennedy; J. Raymond Bell; Philip Murray; Kathryn Lewis.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e5ac1afc3d0b34ff7b8d7a599d39645b" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1952" type="inclusive">1949-1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_c551209eb2e690a947d81a75d350355a" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3f56937a59e653745b6abe749fc40404"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>58 pp.: Local union support for UMWA and United Steelworkers of America strikes and contract negotiations; mass meetings; United Steelworkers of America offer of gift to UMWA during 1950 UMWA contract negotiations; UMWA offer of strike fund assistance to United Steelworkers o f America during 1952 strikes; National Bank of Washington; UMWA district presidents; UMWA executive board members; Philip Murray; William Green; Benjamin F. Fairless; John Owens; Barnum L. Colton; Thomas Kennedy; William Hynes; John J. Mates; James W. Ridings; David Fowler; Ray Thomason; Tom Raney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4135f9db33366c0c88a2d9f413542e4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_49c9472027cfd929b8dbc9baead98cfc" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b07a4c86507a1105a078d48c96911ef1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>11 pp.: Contract negotiations and strike settlement; comparison of pension plan with UAW and UMWA pension plans; Benjamin F. Fairless.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f114d49c394f54d7c948f93b3e86af70" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_a767876dad24e98235efb516192c1c54" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66988900627f5461c09440f1c8a84cee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>16 pp.: Contract negotiations; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); local union political activities; UMWA cooperation; local union support for UMWA contract negotiations; Justin McCarthy; Benjamin F. Fairless; Michael Honus.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_84bca28c2db5174fcbd740a9fb5dfe43" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0b5528c6e0339fff46255d1e9dde694" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dafdff13ce331964aae178421f7d1ebb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 pp.: Southern organizing campaign; strikes; proposed 1952 special convention; John G. Ramsay; Philip Murray.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c2577774e2e62f359fa9a96bc82d25f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_69199b6fcf0748156bb079afa7705a88" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1cc56fcaae23e47ff1fb784cc2f2458c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>145 pp.: Contract negotiations; strikes; Taft-Hartley Act; UMWA offer of strike fund assistance to United Steelworkers of America during 1952 strikes; National Bank of Washington; US Supreme Court decision regarding collective bargaining agreements; Taft-Hartley Act; political activities; UMWA executive board matters; radio broadcasts; public and local union support for UMWA offer of strike fund assistance; public relations; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); US government seizure of steel industry; 1952 special convention; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; John Owens; James H. Terry; John J. Mates; Hugo L. Black; Justin McCarthy; Vincent Sweeney; Stanley H. Ruttenberg.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_50bcc5789908a17a3562cbe0e0926810" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_1911069e5b1def3ed39ce913bfe47a1e" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_acd4fd6087720a2fc60ecc8ad8bfe52e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>6 pp.: Financial matters; UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; newsclippings.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d97c29a06d117c51612d1a36b9e5034d" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2585fcd1b42eeccba8a7b9ff673a3d2" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7205e831632411fb0ae58d2e3d947ae7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>141 pp.: Proceedings of the 1954 convention; UMWA cooperation; UMBWA-IBT- United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; joint political activities; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); unemployment programs; economic analysis of industrial production; contract negotiations; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; Impact of automation on the steel industry; union organization; educational programs; legislative programs; safety and health programs; David J. McDonald; David B. Charnay; Dave Beck; John Herling; Gordon S. Brown; I.W. Abel; James G. Thimmes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dd83e90f82308c84cdcd262784218607" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4948c7401352a45dc33aea15866ba9c" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_03cf4f413e33e381d8c7013d554237d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>19 pp.: Contract negotiations; economic analysis of industrial production; public relations activities; I.W. Abel; David J. McDonald.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a02a65d4f8080ac282bfeedfa92f4638" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_587953e2697aefb46f39284d90f5fc13" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_85e9046858c069760f5b1340d2f7f520"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>79 pp.: Contract negotiations and strike settlement; economic analysis of industrial production; labor-management relations; David J. McDonald; Kathryn Lewis; C.F. Hood.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a98f56265ba3fab4c777355e2fa350ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_eae275f3ee110fb2a02c1d680dd0af13" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b6d0fe0b9b93c732eb28c7b24fb031ae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>86 pp.: Statement before the US Senate Judiciary Committee Subcommittee on Antitrust and Monopoly regarding steel price increases; economic analysis of industrial production; contract negotiations; allegations of irregularities in union elections; adoption of code of ethics on use of union funds; proposed amendment of Taft-Hartley Act; state legislation; financial matters; A. D. Lewis; Robert Howe; Otis Brubaker; David J. McDonald; John Owens; I.W. Abel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_536eb629d990bad82b41a0c777116992" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_823ef6c9df949d94832e548131c9150c" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db2f54e844c008ed9f8f8ac3eba3f626"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>24 pp.: Support for UMWA contract negotiations; UMWA cooperation; report on twenty years of progress (1938-1958) of the Kentucky state industrial union council, AFL-CIO; Labor's Non-Partisan League; public relations activities; David J. McDonald; Albert Whitehouse; Robert Howe; Welly K. Hopkins; Thomas Kennedy; Emory F. Bacon.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_415bee8b85fa0ca46cceb12ecf17f74f" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_675dd96b39515abead77a0e5c4c4175c" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_350a9df0161724c77a272f64fc7f9f7f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>108 pp.: Strikes and contract negotiations; WFTU; Taft-Hartley Act; use of injunctions in labor disputes; anti-Communist activities; publications; economic analysis of industrial production; foreign competition in steel industry; international labor relations; labor-management relations; Meyer Bernstein; David J. McDonald; R. Conrad Cooper; Dwight D. Eisenhower.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8656a7204bf575576dabb4857f9e08bf" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Steelworkers of America.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1962" type="inclusive">1960-1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_d82839651e7fe992dfeada1282fd8cd4" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_062c0e4e50bd6f47779e4be8c6edc245"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>15 pp.: Factionalism and internal politics; ascension of Thomas Kennedy to the UMWA presidency; contract negotiations; David J. McDonald; Thomas Kennedy; Emmett Thomas.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
