<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL04354-003</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.), Working Women United Institute Records<num>/4354/003</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall Tower Road</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 607-255-3183</addressline><addressline>kheelref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-03-26 23:59:05 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.), Working Women United Institute Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="creator" source="ingest">Working Women United Institute</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81063067" role="creator" source="lcnaf">New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>/4354/003</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1986" type="inclusive">1975-1986</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5461dff8fc25ef199100bb6793eebbcc">This collection consists of organizational records, information on programs and publications, research studies, legal briefs, publications, handouts and examples of policy. These records were created and or collected by the Working Women's Institute (predecessor organization's name: Working Women United) between 1975 and 1986.  Working Women's Institute is recognized for publicizing and researching the widespread problem of sexual harassment in the workplace.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">10603868</unitid>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1f62e47e9859f4d90fbfb96e41c119d7">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of meeting minutes, research proposals, publications, program reports and event details related to the Working Women's Institute (WWI) and its efforts to bring attention to the problem of sexual harassment in the workplace. The collection also contains correspondence between WWI staff and the Women's Alliance for Job Equity (WAJE) and the United Nation's Ad Hoc Group on Equal Rights for Women.  In addition, the collection includes examples of sexual harassment policies from a number of colleges and universities including Rutgers University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), University of Pennsylvania and Columbia University.  The collection also includes news clippings about sexual harassment.</p><p>Working Women's United was founded as an independent institute to provide resources to women to conduct research, educational and legal projects broadly relating to the needs and interests of working women. This collection includes documents related to the 1975 Speak Out event held in Ithaca, NY and  organized by WWI founders Lin Farley, Karen Sauvigne and Susan Meyer. Correspondence between the organizers clarifies the role that each played regarding the Speak Out event and Board of Directors Minutes detail the rights of use as they relate to the Speak Out Testimony. </p><p>The collection contains detailed program reports documenting the efforts of the Working Women's Institute as well as examples of their publications, handouts, and flyers. Also included are detailed speakers notes, promotional flyers and posters for the "Sexual Harassment on College Campuses" workshop hosted by Rutgers University in 1982.  Additionally, the collection includes letters, briefs and press releases related to Supreme Court case 477 U.S. 57 (1986), Meritor Savings Bank vs Mechelle Vinson. This case was the first of its kind to reach the U.S. Supreme Court and would redefine sexual harassment in the workplace.  In a 9-0 decision, the Court recognized sexual harassment as a violation of the Civil Rights act of 1964.</p><p>The collection includes pamphlets about and policies related to the issue of sexual harassment in the workplace; newspaper clippings and correspondence between WWI and Women's Alliance for Job Equity (WAJE); United Nations Ad Hoc Group on Equal Rights for Women; and, the Federal Government's Equal Employment Opportunity Commission's (EEOC) proposed amendment to add sexual harassment to its guidelines on sexual discrimination.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_15d6685f536be542c5e9494dc3fd6008">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Working Women's Institute was originally founded as Working Women's United in June 1975.  The organization was founded by Cornell University faculty members as an independent institute with the goal of researching and publicizing the wide-spread problem of sexual harassment in the workplace. The organization relocated from Ithaca to New York City in 1977 and changed their name to Working Women's Institute in 1978.  Working Women's Institute was a recognized leader in the fight against sexual harassment.</p><p>Founding organizers, Karen Sauvigne, Susan Meyer and Lin Farley worked at the Women's Section of Cornell University's Human Affairs Program (HAP) in 1975 when they were approached by Carmita Wood. After years of harassment by her boss, Carmita Wood resigned from her position at Cornell University and was denied unemployment benefits. She met with the staff at HAP to tell them her story. The women decided to help her, but first they had to find a name for Carmita's experience. The group settled on the term "sexual harassment." As a direct result from their experience with Carmita, the group formed Working Women United and decided to host an event bringing women together to, "Speak Out," about their own experiences with sexual harassment in the workplace. </p><p>Lin Farley was the director of Cornell University's Women's Section and a lecturer for a course called Women and Work. She is recognized for coining the phrase, "sexual harassment," and testified in 1975 before the New York City Human Rights Commission Hearings on Women and Work.  Farley is the author of Sexual Shakedown: The Sexual Harassment of Women on the Job. </p><p>Karen Sauvigne is a recognized pioneer for her work on sexual harassment. She has gone on to hold faculty and management positions at CUNY Law School, John Jay College and Baruch College.  She is currently the Director of Education in the Department of Geriatrics and Palliative Medicine at Mount Sinai.</p><p>KC Wagner is a former Director of the Working Women's Institute. She is the current Director of Workplace Issues at Cornell University's ILR School and the co-chair of The Worker Institute's Equity at Work Initiative at Cornell University. She has testified as an expert witness in landmark sexual harassment cases on a range of topics.</p><p>The New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations (ILR) is one of the many schools and colleges that make up Cornell University.  Unlike most of Cornell's schools, however the ILR was created by the state legislature in 1945 and is part of the SUNY (State University of New York) system.
One of the functions of the ILR School is extension (continuing adult education) and public service. Funding for these activities, comes from state support, modest charges to participants, and grants and contracts.
The School's Division of Extension and Public Service is administered through a headquarters staff in Ithaca and offices in Albany, Buffalo, Long Island, New York City, Rochester, and Westchester. The Metropolitan District Office, which serves the five counties that make up New York City as well as Nassau, Suffolk, Westchester, and Rockland counties, focuses on programs and services for trade unions and other employee organizations, workers, community groups, and government agencies.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7801fc11482a97dffbc5a6e6f223b556">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Collection processed by intern Sarah Tronkowski, under the supervision of the Technical Services Archivist, as part of the requirements for receipt of a Masters of Library Science.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_54cce8b18590eeb869baf88ed1f4707a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_761f02534bff366ddf85fe5d5359df93">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <custodhist id="aspace_8678a99a0a863ece7fc69eabd696ddda">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>This collection was originally located at the Barnard Center for Research on Women (or earlier, the Women's Center). The records were donated by KC Wagner, Cornell faculty and member of the Working Women's Institute. The Barnard Center for Research on Women maintained a large feminist ephemera collection, a collection of periodicals, parts of their own institutional records, and some additional special research collections in their office. After its closing, the majority of their materials were transferred to the Barnard Archives. The Working Women's Institute Records were one of these collections. They were held by the Barnard Archives, but never accessioned into their collection. The records were returned to KC Wagner at her request for deposit at the Kheel Center in November 2018.</p>  </custodhist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2010112889" source="lcsh">Sexual harassment in universities and colleges -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="ingest">Sexual harassment</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85120671" source="lcsh">Sex role in the work environment</subject>
    <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78025313" source="lcnaf">Farley, Lin</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Cohen, Marilyn (Working Women's Institute)</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Crull, Peggy, PhD</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Robinowitz, Robin</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Wagner, KC</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81063067" source="lcnaf">New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no97011062" source="lcnaf">New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Metropolitan District Office</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79021621" source="lcnaf">Cornell University</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Cornell University. Human Affairs Program</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">United States. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85364480" source="lcnaf">Meritor Savings Bank</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n84141953" source="lcnaf">Ad Hoc Group on Equal Rights for Women</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Women's Alliance for Job Equity</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Working Women's Institute</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">10603868</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_3427f6a30f206559b2b5ecfa6d5992a0" level="series"><did><unittitle>I: Organizational Records</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1985" type="inclusive">1975-1985</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f888e2eba0d8935692248ce8fd1543d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the organization's founding documents, correspondence between founding members and its organizational structure. Annual audits of programming provide a look at ongoing projects, priorities and research.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_25df8b9fd4a586106a9182ad305902ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Organizational Structure</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c5625523df28089b1007d8b73201198" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_134a61f22c7fdbde7775a7ef77b77a84" parent="aspace_5c5625523df28089b1007d8b73201198" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_758d0bfb5343205e7747c242e9aa7d6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">1975-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_e91794da894f61c0ca63d8103276c216" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ff734d105e37cf4c724d6b20f7fdf4d0" parent="aspace_e91794da894f61c0ca63d8103276c216" type="folder">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_22f2c757d4c64f87d1d750013211480c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_d69a840f5cd436dc982c6603a35b283e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3053eaba1ee0fcdbafe52bc3c2749e16" parent="aspace_d69a840f5cd436dc982c6603a35b283e" type="folder">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4987009eadaa9b40290aa5ce6b88dd52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personnel Policies and Operational Procedures</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_7826be9a23d1175d3ee72bb4e5379538" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6ee741a34ba124b1fd854e9e964aa4a7" parent="aspace_7826be9a23d1175d3ee72bb4e5379538" type="folder">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cb7228feafbec545bad1917ec4630d7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs and Projects</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1980" type="inclusive">1978-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_4b8044f32cd9c7e1f0391f004b6bf546" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_25dcc36b5430973f110b707470505e0f" parent="aspace_4b8044f32cd9c7e1f0391f004b6bf546" type="folder">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6a6e68dd8b6e36827261b6e4a9bfebc1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs and Projects</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1985" type="inclusive">1981-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5b9ea33d4f4e68a80c037067b8c223c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_743206dc7b34a5e9f60773b5a89a623d" parent="aspace_f5b9ea33d4f4e68a80c037067b8c223c" type="folder">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f56834bf0d6c3fc34563876f4649d2e9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Budget</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_be84e2a2618dc0f5af8b56e5d8caf69b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_003c6579e8170ee5a78e7d92fab8f25f" parent="aspace_be84e2a2618dc0f5af8b56e5d8caf69b" type="folder">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bf0220080cf63afe8c5390cb901f301d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Directors</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1983" type="inclusive">1982-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d799eb66b8521882e544f20d6f76cc9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_70ffb74e3a278946d7a86895b695bf6d" parent="aspace_7d799eb66b8521882e544f20d6f76cc9" type="folder">8</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_2c46bf8d412686647a2556a36bcd3792" level="series"><did><unittitle>II: Programs and Publications</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1986" type="inclusive">1975-1986</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8e70598f4e4b92bbdac99c51e0e6f959"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains research proposals, reports, newsletters, handouts and a legal materials checklist produced by WWI. The series also contains records about a "Sexual Harassment on College Campuses" workshop hosted by Rutgers University and an amicus brief written in support of Mechelle Vincent for the Supreme Court Case, Meritor vs. Vincent. Attorneys for the WWI as Amicus Curiae are Laurie E. Foster and Ellen M. Saideman of the law firm Lord, Day and Lord.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_1a922917617399d0c81fd1242997e6de" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment on the Job</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d48dbef49ffee18a875f5b6669f0f12" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5b50b8f0905f1e68a06d7957bc93218d" parent="aspace_3d48dbef49ffee18a875f5b6669f0f12" type="folder">9</container></did><c03 id="aspace_94e025b5141f7aa3377ea564c2407eed" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment on the Job newsletter</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_ebe4d4173d8f7e3c47ff3e83a9599665" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_58528a49554513c1eb7897baf4e2d9fd" parent="aspace_ebe4d4173d8f7e3c47ff3e83a9599665" type="folder">9</container><container id="aspace_5b4eebbec8f9f73eb3bff0d5c4168e86" parent="aspace_58528a49554513c1eb7897baf4e2d9fd" type="item">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d6a15c0aee502d46c56c8df5314f259b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Results of Preliminary Survey.</p></scopecontent></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_6cea67eec7db7e431a9da9d319304273" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment on the Job - Proposal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_891513a2ad55808b1cddca4148586901" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_582ce992f9db6c489d5158c0bea8594d" parent="aspace_891513a2ad55808b1cddca4148586901" type="folder">10</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6c3cf59f3f21f3c7fe945adf9da21f45" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1983" type="inclusive">1978-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c9676e4d8eb6e4a8e13c61a4332f741" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_9c5f91da82273a391d71704d3f80d653" parent="aspace_4c9676e4d8eb6e4a8e13c61a4332f741" type="folder">11</container></did><c03 id="aspace_1d70d6f55ccc5a5b197faead16f63263" level="item"><did><unittitle>Responses of Fair Employment Practices Agencies to Sexual Harassment Complaints: A Report and Recommendations.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_208c69a3245d149b1cea958037ddbd02" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c5ba9fc339afc433a7ae4f7b414b11a7" parent="aspace_208c69a3245d149b1cea958037ddbd02" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_415c1cdd6efa8d2e9d3b999896502c4b" parent="aspace_c5ba9fc339afc433a7ae4f7b414b11a7" type="item">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b5fc2f71a4c0f4f04b1a5e380b0a7a1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Research Report No.2, WWI, Fall 1978.</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_1f65f58aa05c67c12dd263ef6de4ede8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Testimony of Working Women's Institute and the Women's Legal Defense Fund before the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations of the House Committee on Education and Labor on Pressures in the Workplace</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_6fad0685caa7a3e26d60246d8a6f4d8c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_22be26211026ac512d37deef6e243df6" parent="aspace_6fad0685caa7a3e26d60246d8a6f4d8c" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_4845a26df5e90a0fbd9d06b4a2640aeb" parent="aspace_22be26211026ac512d37deef6e243df6" type="item">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96e76be5d05cb4c21190b73df17835f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Testimony</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_24be87965327cf464b9a9b9c490b4c7a" level="item"><did><unittitle>The Impact of Sexual Harassment on the Job</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d0b6322ea381e25fa9a9106802a7df3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5db520f507fc1eff52026d275fd892b7" parent="aspace_3d0b6322ea381e25fa9a9106802a7df3" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_f7471a5b742b5a77d069787915ebb097" parent="aspace_5db520f507fc1eff52026d275fd892b7" type="item">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_59e3259a251e1af745d87d2fc0da80f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A Profile of the Experiences of 92 Women</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_b959a6116b84b6df16c51ebc1121eb7f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment on the Job and in Education</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_89a442afb39135c0ab9366d7e3fbdc13" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_165b20c65588685066d2c229b8a10339" parent="aspace_89a442afb39135c0ab9366d7e3fbdc13" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_a5cccdc365a72eaeb42073b8f57e204f" parent="aspace_165b20c65588685066d2c229b8a10339" type="item">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_39bc1966d74610ccb64db127bdf996ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A Comprehensive Bibliography: Addendum</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_70f9550fe50fc468e25631999ca9b8c0" level="item"><did><unittitle>The Stress Effects of Sexual Harassment on the Job</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_258fb91501aa0d593f7ff68b3f4f77ef" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_691a071e08888aedeff0a4b507e2e6d9" parent="aspace_258fb91501aa0d593f7ff68b3f4f77ef" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_b45c32cb5d319734866de3a20828428b" parent="aspace_691a071e08888aedeff0a4b507e2e6d9" type="item">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_409f147256006039c4990ece730452b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Peggy Crull</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_971d7359f633cee964724f44fe368ea3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Statement Regarding Proposed Amendment to New York State Unemployment Insurance Law Related to Sexual Harassment</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_422a54386ff9fd69957e3faf911bfbbd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_245418ba576786f87db2e25c69556fe3" parent="aspace_422a54386ff9fd69957e3faf911bfbbd" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_8145802244ff4b6dfd5ec64ea808122d" parent="aspace_245418ba576786f87db2e25c69556fe3" type="item">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6d1ab8b29429c89274d06fb6fe333ae5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Statement of support</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_4c6148b3817433faa345d8b25bc14e12" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sexual harassment on the Job and in Education</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5eb557403cde1bdb7af4a8e4efae3e9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_77e859059af05200c104c1494fb54d5a" parent="aspace_f5eb557403cde1bdb7af4a8e4efae3e9" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_49997940ab2c53e74eaeb0761342b27c" parent="aspace_77e859059af05200c104c1494fb54d5a" type="item">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2044d3d44819e03a783455068d22a7c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Comprehensive Bibliography</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_73005799e9acc9959afda798392c1979" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment on the Job</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce81f2c92c2c7555a038ff2b522f850d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d3b54b8ef1992a16df4fea5e5d3050f7" parent="aspace_ce81f2c92c2c7555a038ff2b522f850d" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_b65ee687ea6693210d0107cc1fbca03b" parent="aspace_d3b54b8ef1992a16df4fea5e5d3050f7" type="item">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_047aba471f595b6f23d2f5bfaa3bf435"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Questions and Answers</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_6566387085f5a4746a98e5a094fd612a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Research Clearinghouse</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9a80b6ba798819986e06f5ef3453713" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d8ce8a15039dba2b7ffa929f4779bf7a" parent="aspace_c9a80b6ba798819986e06f5ef3453713" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_92ba0b78b07a864d0376885c0c5cc93e" parent="aspace_d8ce8a15039dba2b7ffa929f4779bf7a" type="item">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5aa76fb40a028b1f03a5fc4da19c1c05"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A list of people conducting research on sexual harassment.</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_96a1cdb7ee4546c703d3848a7a74dcce" level="item"><did><unittitle>Expanding the Definition of Sexual Harassment</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_43a0cc3f8ce482038c8d62a7780ff789" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d766866f8c8d770c041931e6df7f2fd0" parent="aspace_43a0cc3f8ce482038c8d62a7780ff789" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_15fb268309332fdb6feef3c7ba71a123" parent="aspace_d766866f8c8d770c041931e6df7f2fd0" type="item">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b4f67b50f959d56b323944f52cfff23"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Peggy Crull, Marilyn Cohen</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_50a880ac286544465792b08124d52c28" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment, Stress and Women's Health</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_47615e2917d08d8cc367e605d3fc214e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6219ddc13347aafc4a47419d2c47e541" parent="aspace_47615e2917d08d8cc367e605d3fc214e" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_67eebb988c5b55ffc374bf872ac161ce" parent="aspace_6219ddc13347aafc4a47419d2c47e541" type="item">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3dd7aa29dc06daed66fd86cc8e40a00f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>To appear in Double Exposure: Women's Health Hazards on the Job and at Home</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_34e3c672300704ba00aec114bc43e1c7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Prospectus: Perceptions, Strategies and Outcomes in Sexual Harassment Situations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_1975b72942cf0a491d1deaced9507e5c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5911a1edfcd4fc6d06626f645e7e6b2a" parent="aspace_1975b72942cf0a491d1deaced9507e5c" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_1710133f7f1ddf5dbde1167e95890c5f" parent="aspace_5911a1edfcd4fc6d06626f645e7e6b2a" type="item">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a9d68f3e427b4473e76aa4c9b84d8e6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Interviews with 69 Women, Peggy Crull</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_3961dd84609e8d14150bec632c85ba45" level="item"><did><unittitle>The Stress Effects of Sexual Harassment in the Office</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_e504b8a85e479928f8d130038fc6e761" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5710505ea4869d8cc880072ce7a1474a" parent="aspace_e504b8a85e479928f8d130038fc6e761" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_f2d4a458c6e2a3daf0a16ef858a6e8dc" parent="aspace_5710505ea4869d8cc880072ce7a1474a" type="item">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c220dbf6fe6fa2e38f25fb7a64da90ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Peggy Crull</p></scopecontent></c03><c03 id="aspace_c2c37620f5e95a0e80cba70100637ffa" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment and Male Control of Women's Work</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_cbdc6f49a83b8e37cd9d8a804184f41c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d8c582fcb66cdcd1e37dc8add6cc089f" parent="aspace_cbdc6f49a83b8e37cd9d8a804184f41c" type="folder">11</container><container id="aspace_42f027c52fc7b124740fdf8af990ac17" parent="aspace_d8c582fcb66cdcd1e37dc8add6cc089f" type="item">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d226b412822b5cdf4a15ded6730257e2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The effects of sexual harassment are varied and severe.</p></scopecontent></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_e14bcacf1ccc71bb79d9cec85397240e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Handouts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1983" type="inclusive">1978-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_c99dee039264bfa212d66c44b8815764" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_9709a559536c855b765cbf1a158c3ec1" parent="aspace_c99dee039264bfa212d66c44b8815764" type="folder">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c2bc1560a1b70635d418aaafbf57bb4a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview Study</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_2fecc60e954333a175bacf0c8cacc004" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ab3996b7c4f223827b8bf886cecb78f7" parent="aspace_2fecc60e954333a175bacf0c8cacc004" type="folder">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3156b8b6eeb1ca70d2ef0f4826fab118" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal Materials Checklist</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1982" type="inclusive">1980-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_0258150e6859caabcf808951dc7603d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c0c3568aa29144eec1272a586303e3a7" parent="aspace_0258150e6859caabcf808951dc7603d6" type="folder">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8852a2fc284a08b870ece0a54435ff67" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment on the College Campus (Rutgers Workshop)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_122947e6f8ea0a73c13d09c1f7fc9b9f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d01b20a7853df973ba478ecb36ece0a3" parent="aspace_122947e6f8ea0a73c13d09c1f7fc9b9f" type="folder">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1655b6b0399f11d619525859f8f612b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment in the FAA</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a93781f697c34392a196d0f52e1f2cb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_19947af35dff01f80009f3ca03852c8e" parent="aspace_5a93781f697c34392a196d0f52e1f2cb" type="folder">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1a64af921c84cf8a8d2a0926f498b7f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meritor Savings vs Mechelle Vinson</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1986" type="inclusive">1985-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_2937170cd380059ba97f8c5b19610f69" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5c7feb5727b30e4015204a541d35eabf" parent="aspace_2937170cd380059ba97f8c5b19610f69" type="folder">17</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_071c7a0c4c2b95da8748b60610a64c9d" level="series"><did><unittitle>III: Sexual Harassment Subject Files</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1986" type="inclusive">1975-1986</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_702b1993d27c3ae9509f17bec8ebaf90"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains news clippings that feature Working Women's Institute and their staff; sexual harassment; and, changes to sexual harassment policy at federal and state levels. Correspondence between the WWI and the Women's Alliance for Job Equity (WAJE), and between the WWI and the U.N.'s Ad Hoc Group on Equal Rights for Women may be found in this series. The series also includes handouts and guides regarding sexual harassment in the workplace as well as additional amicus briefs and requests for information. Examples of sexual harassment policy from a number of colleges and universities are also included in this series.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_c2efd4c3fcac964da497f1db03df4be3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1986" type="inclusive">1975-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_11bc303fe70eda6cec3a46c3e32f16e3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_eb958107954c3340275806872530aab6" parent="aspace_11bc303fe70eda6cec3a46c3e32f16e3" type="folder">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_34d78b9e87a9f94368d42fe2f42f7c6c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Survey of Staff Attitudes on Sex Discrimination in the United Nations Secretariat</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_3bd28e9200571cefe1c3cfc93c20e0f3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_dea6b3069c80c7b354b601a794c5e8be" parent="aspace_3bd28e9200571cefe1c3cfc93c20e0f3" type="folder">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_81ae38d2695e222c2dedf5da1da45cd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment: A Hidden Issue</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_8dd67e75393141e189beee3090c65584" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_66fe299fa0b310e45a1af93cd9e763cd" parent="aspace_8dd67e75393141e189beee3090c65584" type="folder">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_efcc994c6a6d7441bd421b7fb0b0bbf8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sexual Harassment at HUD</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_078c021e07967058c25b74f5d6dc08ab" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_8cc90f9217a450dbd786c23af58da50e" parent="aspace_078c021e07967058c25b74f5d6dc08ab" type="folder">21</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4e9f43cce6db7e49be72176bcb4c325d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Women's Alliance for Job Equity (WAJE)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1986" type="inclusive">1979-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_2eed0b65a4244a51dde23dfa2bdaf874" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_87b09d28885cd2c1a6c3155978a0fe40" parent="aspace_2eed0b65a4244a51dde23dfa2bdaf874" type="folder">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a50afd727ae358c7cda927e25d3c23c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>UN Ad Hoc Group on Equal Rights for Women</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_41b71e6832f3a5574000c862ad7c41b5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_8f8550c5ced44857438115636fbacc98" parent="aspace_41b71e6832f3a5574000c862ad7c41b5" type="folder">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_df22598298b7cc3f9abbc3c23814d1a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal Briefs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd8a85884e02dc13d9469214d5f96374" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6906aea2593ce1933c535f6c61fbb7f4" parent="aspace_cd8a85884e02dc13d9469214d5f96374" type="folder">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_307480cc2a6dc0777dc7a57d5b9b0183" level="file"><did><unittitle>Comments on EEOC Amendment</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_2307f57fd097309b199451dde9ee076e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_0765b85fc9fb6f9cfa58d4d25569efbb" parent="aspace_2307f57fd097309b199451dde9ee076e" type="folder">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a69ebe749a59ec912ec6a1a45d342389" level="file"><did><unittitle>Handouts on Sexual Harassment</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1984" type="inclusive">1980-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_28620cabad2306b66fa8c7e316cea2c1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1735a9bd745a4338737a4e1095e1b5bf" parent="aspace_28620cabad2306b66fa8c7e316cea2c1" type="folder">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0e88a1dce28751652152221c64e8242f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Examples of Sexual Harassment Policy</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1985" type="inclusive">1981-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d18848a9ef939518ffb4fb8f1154fef" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4b109d120e4f2659c672f232a1291700" parent="aspace_7d18848a9ef939518ffb4fb8f1154fef" type="folder">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_aea4c33d07e866baf8ab83b134104b84" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence in re Army Times Article</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_32b2efdbad03a2e9c00590ae6af41610" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_e74f447b8955498a0526069c84f60b36" parent="aspace_32b2efdbad03a2e9c00590ae6af41610" type="folder">28</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
