<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL06174-007</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>NYSUT New York Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education Files <num>6174/007</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by P. Leary</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>October 31, 2013</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall Tower Road</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 607-255-3183</addressline><addressline>kheelref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-08-26 00:42:37 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>NYSUT New York Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education Files</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname role="creator" source="ingest">New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>6174/007</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1976/1994" type="inclusive">1976- 1994</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_64848aa19aed23fee31f060f010aebdf" label="Quantity:">2 linear ft.</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_6c7daed1a5830378a6a2b938971e8fd5" label="Forms of Material:">Reports, pamphlets, correspondence.</physdesc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b0c61dea3dded7d20755e776d2f3a362">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">7163993</unitid>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_038ceacd2cc54f566fd2e9ebbeccbbda">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) was created in 1972 by the merger of the New York State Teachers Association (NYSTA) and the United Teachers of New York (UTNY). NYSTA had been affiliated with the National Education Association (NEA), and UTNY with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). UTNY was the statewide organization whose United Federation of Teachers (UFT), led by Albert Shanker, was the predominant teachers' union in New York City. In joining with United Teachers and affiliating with the AFT, NYSUT also became a member union of the AFL-CIO. </p><p> In 1976, NYSUT voted to disaffiliate with the NEA. Some locals left NYSUT and created the NYEA (New York Educators Association), which became the state affiliate for the NEA. In the early 1980s, NYEA changed its name to NEA-NY. </p><p> NYEA/NEA- NY viewed association with the AFL-CIO's industrial unions as undermining the professional image and independence of teachers. The two organizations also differed strongly on aspects of the governance structure, particularly with respect to ethnic minority representation, with NYSUT opposed to mandatory minimums. The rivalry between NYSUT and NYEA/NEA-NY in organizing new locals expended a great deal of resources for both labor organizations. </p><p> While competition with NYEA/NEA-NY was a constant focus of NYSUT's organizing efforts for teachers, NYSUT was also organizing college faculty members, nurses, and other non-teaching personnel. Once members were organized, NYSUT continued to advocate for teachers' and other workers' rights through contract support and legal services at the local level and political involvement at the state and federal levels, supporting candidates and legislation that protected funding, due process, and working conditions. </p><p> NEA-N Y merged with NYSUT in 2006, by which time NYSUT had grown to more than half a million members, becoming the largest union in New York State.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a2898bfdd23b2f0efe092e5ad587e2da">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Covers the period 1976-1994. The NYS Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education (also known as the Rubin Commission or Rubin Task Force, named for its chairman, Max J. Rubin) was created to make recommendations for a state aid formula that would more fairly fund school districts, taking into account the great disparities in local wealth throughout the state. Materials in this collection focus mostly on the NYSUT committee that tracked the task force's work, the NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding. Meeting agendas and minutes, position papers, and correspondence comprise the bulk of the files, along with analyses of the 1978 NY Supreme Court decision (and the Appellate Division decision in 1981) in Levittown v. Nyquist, which found the current school aid formula unconstitutional. Files also include materials of the Task Force on Creating Career Pathways for New York State Youth, appointed by Governor Mario Cuomo in 1991 and co-chaired by NYSUT president Tom Hobart and Regent Walter Cooper of Rochester. The task force examined school-to-work transitions for students at risk of dropping out, including a proposal to replace the Regents general diploma with a Career Pathways Certificate at age 16 and establish alternative learning environments for students beyond the age of mandatory attendance. Finally, a large number of files reflect the work of the Curriculum and Assessment Council and its many subcommittees, which advised the State Education Department on its school restructuring initiative, A New Compact for Learning. Detailed critiques by NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese, who was a member of the group, give insight into the level of concern by the teachers union for rigorous academic standards.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_26e128ff422660cef9df91b25e4ed877">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9b62069fa4609b58337612321341d234">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_bb46e6664b587455e4edd750a1c53095">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>NYSUT New York Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education Files #6174/007. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_204386a1b4ff20eadc630bf5b201c588">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related Collections: All other 6174 collections</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <odd id="aspace_7eb2df90e463412fd8b7d78c43d5bd33">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheelref@cornell.edu">kheelref@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel">https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>P. Leary, June 13, 2012</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Randall Miles, October 31, 2013</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Teachers' unions -- New York (State)</subject>
    <persname audience="internal" source="local">Cortese, Antonia</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="ingest">Hobart, Thomas Y. Jr.</persname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">New York State United Teachers</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">New York State United Teachers, New York Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">7163993</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ce653f6a268acc1e0be1fc33ff23ee9a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Readings/Reports Related to Task Force on Creating Career Pathways</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/1991" type="inclusive">1990-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf70ad28848fb054a9a5398a20e45d73" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d674cb0770ae156d442270a0ded122da" parent="aspace_bf70ad28848fb054a9a5398a20e45d73" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a1590af1885999316b82f197c659091"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>U.S. Department of Labor publication, "What Work Requires of Schools: A SCANS Report for America 2000," by the Secretary's Commission on Achieving Necessary Skills, June 1991; U.S. General Accounting Office Report to Congressional Requesters, "Transition from School to Work: Linking Education and Worksite Training," August 1991; NYS Job Training Partnership Council Workforce Preparation Evaluation Program Plan, June 25, 1991; report, "A World Class Workforce for Wisconsin," recommendations of the Governor's Commission for a Quality Workforce, April 1991; report, "Partnership for Excellence: The Virginia Plan for Strengthening the Commonwealth's 21st Century Workforce," Governor's Advisory Committee Workforce Virginia 2000: A Partnership for Excellence, March 1991; testimony by president of National Alliance of Business before the House Ways and Means Committee, "Education and Human Resource Factors Affecting U.S. International competitiveness," June 5, 1991; report by the National Youth Employment and Training Conference, "At Risk: A Nation and Its Youth"; position paper by National Council on Vocational Education, "Integrating Occupational and Academic Education Grades K through Twelve," May 1991, with cover letter to NYSUT president Tom Hobart; related briefing papers</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_09e4a201122ac4dacf6acc1a3c88662d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Creating Career Pathways for New York's Youth</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1f589830ba586a379d0b4675b8a046b" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_24277da09f170e19e702030e4822e4aa" parent="aspace_d1f589830ba586a379d0b4675b8a046b" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_27078332638010ac40951e5c27389bf0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda; list of members of task force; description of study</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_6248be4343980b7a46a3aafda5f9e730" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Creating Career Pathways Meeting</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ac513726edf1a3e1be047ede14c10ca" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f5e40915294c28b29143236cc26219c4" parent="aspace_9ac513726edf1a3e1be047ede14c10ca" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e31bae13bf0058acdfb23f836326c27c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>August 28, 1991. Description of study; briefing paper re the underlying issues involved in the deliberations of the task force, April; selected excerpts from other briefing papers; briefing paper re Skills Opportunity Centers; text of enabling legislation, March 20</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2e6868b34a1bcfb42dd4a385455a44fb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Creating Career Pathways Meeting Oct. 7, 1991</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a49d428e11bdfe44d6aa820e6832be9" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7def3c200a5427da50915747bc2d339c" parent="aspace_4a49d428e11bdfe44d6aa820e6832be9" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c64a8686b73c224a6f4291977ba2bfb6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Outline of Proposed Recommendations and Recommendation Options of the Task Force on Creating Career Pathways for New York's Youth; draft Proposed Recommendations and Options, September 24, 1991; draft report of task force</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_20bff374374ad1df1a7384dcfee33eaa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Creating Career Pathways Meeting-Outstanding Issues October 31,1991</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf88a16c0120adba8369d5e570fecd97" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_641951e91bccd2c867cae3e60119dd2f" parent="aspace_bf88a16c0120adba8369d5e570fecd97" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e1daff77b6a0af24af480169fcf94bad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda for November 25, 1991, meeting; memo re agenda for October 31 meeting; Funding for Fairness: A Report of NYS Temporary State Commission on the Distribution of State Aid to Local School Districts, December 1988; Report on the Task Force on Creating Career Pathways for New York's Youth, November 1, 1991, prepared by Division of Research and Educational Services, NYSUT; State Education Department press release re child labor laws, September 5; memo from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to NYSUT Board of Directors re child labor law, August 26</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_831e4eb2b1d83ab3871353fad8da2a49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Creating Career Pathways Meeting-1/9/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac370f8499b71ecf0aa30090750e6a79" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f82f26a29a655a3fc6e1cc5794a49bf1" parent="aspace_ac370f8499b71ecf0aa30090750e6a79" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1b773eba5378351c406000cc898b5e61"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda; meeting materials, including paper on creation of alternative learning environments for dropouts, i.e., Skills Opportunity Centers</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c98c48c02b8e482487c3bcc82e18d8ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Creating Career Pathways Subcommittee Meeting-2/12/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a911f44aa6d68da7373791dc1936b63" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_42aefa07b14b1d4221606073fd5302f6" parent="aspace_5a911f44aa6d68da7373791dc1936b63" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fa1e0c5b74d7be6f3863872e1992ce65"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Recommendations of Subcommittee on New Career Pathways; findings; handwritten notes from meeting; related memos</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d3864f9a19049db360bb8df17fdf5e68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Job Training Partnership Council (JTPC)-Career Pathways Task Force 2/24/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_c12ce75dac2b454e8b456f921de51728" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_fd79122cca521f057e66fda1c6924940" parent="aspace_c12ce75dac2b454e8b456f921de51728" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_84b6b27b9edef53478262b2be16a17cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Letter from Lt. Gov. Stan Lundine to Louis Grumet, executive director of the New York State School Boards Association, answering wide-ranging concerns about the work of the task force, July 2; letter from the Business Council of New York State, Inc., to Regents Chancellor Carlos Caballada, praising the work of the task force and proposed Career Pathways Certificate, July 9; notice of February 24, 1992, meeting, with attached materials re Youth Centers, Skills Center, and Standards Board, and newspaper clippings; letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to Assemblywoman Aurelia Green, assuring her that raising standards would not encourage students to drop out, April 2; letter from Greene, January 8; Regents discussion item, Education for a Productive Workforce, including description of restructuring initiative, A New Compact for Learning, February 13</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_979d632ce6edfe2a8ae0fb05e9a09f23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Creating Career Pathways Meeting-5/11/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_38de7831310d4e5281006c8ac66e5e73" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cbde2ef8e1532ff170367244762b5d23" parent="aspace_38de7831310d4e5281006c8ac66e5e73" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8bbba8b0ceb015e8ee998c7e3bbd3a6b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Draft discussion paper by New York State School Boards Association, "Successful Transitions from School to Work," January 1992, with cover letter to Education Commissioner Sobol, April 6; comments on task force draft report, "Education That Works"</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_1122cf1cccc4a4e334d47ff492761a54" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education That Works: Creating Career Pathways for NYS Youth</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1993" type="inclusive">1992-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_d52c613e2e4436a6250e083cfdcb1f95" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_494db9fe02401ab1b288e03b7f8afaf1" parent="aspace_d52c613e2e4436a6250e083cfdcb1f95" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b253acce3263ddc70ff05dbb17779022"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Final task force report, "Education That Works: Creating Career Pathways for New York State Youth," September 1992; summary of recommendations; letter from Regents re Preparing Youth for the Workforce, April 1993</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_0848d215d1b80252bede3201819408bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council-3/2-3/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_9418f4774f1efa40f5ad89188ecf730a" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4ef31609cd402f79fb17be93790cd6a5" parent="aspace_9418f4774f1efa40f5ad89188ecf730a" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_06511ca5b1f5cff3126dfd182d202014"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda; list of members; notes from January meeting; draft principles for an assessment system; draft principles for curricular frameworks; other background materials</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f9c22c0f57612267af64bf444b63acf4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council-5/11-12/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_8adadd2daf7aee7a5a479fe0c1b51782" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5848921a61de9a0e20183e3da144d20e" parent="aspace_8adadd2daf7aee7a5a479fe0c1b51782" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c6f11260357396a1187a4d92958e56cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda and minutes of May 11-12 meeting; presentation re CUNY College Preparatory Initiative, March 20, 1992; status report of the Curriculum and Assessment Council and committees, April 1992; comments from NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese and others on the draft Principles for Developing Curriculum Frameworks; draft Statement on Philosophy of Language; Social Studies and Assessment Committee Report to the Council, May 12; Curriculum and Assessment Committee for Languages Other than English, March 23-24</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_0b368402a3c66756c3cc0223596213f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council-6/15-16/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d450f80442262ec26a7d72b8ad0ca15" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cf24c2619a376b48df531dd2da5c9d47" parent="aspace_9d450f80442262ec26a7d72b8ad0ca15" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_38bfb7e7aa66718ee9e4e268382f9926"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda and minutes; list of working groups; status reports and draft documents by committees (mathematics, science, and technology, English language arts, social studies)</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_17d36d08b757cf67a3193a1a1142ac39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council-Patrick Flynn-Aug. 1992</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f6fa0c45e671de181a24dd5ef8cecb9" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2b7b42cd9b565a7aa24ef31dfa6b125e" parent="aspace_6f6fa0c45e671de181a24dd5ef8cecb9" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ac6d112e56a2ce7092c510c049c329b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda and minutes; interim report by committee on mathematics, science, and technology, August 20, 1992; handwritten notes from meeting; reports by Accountability and Implementation Group, Assessment Working Group</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_439532d4b07ce96de71a5d18422810cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting with SED on "Standards"-10/20/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_57cd12bd3cd1031da4c7eb4b4dcaa77d" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_42f413844070e8ae72c917742c833ce5" parent="aspace_57cd12bd3cd1031da4c7eb4b4dcaa77d" type="folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_29c532217f067459d376e9ed5d5dd1b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Document, Connection between the New Compact for Learning and the Curriculum and Assessment Council; minutes of October 20 meeting on the role of standards in school restructuring, with cover memo, November 3</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9c214ef2bb54de4294755cb5924fcf34" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council-11/23/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5f5cb6dbde81c4ccfa471312f6d96f3" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_43dad62d6fcae1e8f1101b2bb03a0afc" parent="aspace_c5f5cb6dbde81c4ccfa471312f6d96f3" type="folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_edd1129df278afc35b4e4946cc6e9792"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda; condensed notes; newspaper clippings; report by Subcommittee on Math, Science, Technology Curriculum, "Education Outcomes," May 1992; meeting materials; materials re curriculum frameworks; lists of committee members for English language arts, social studies, and mathematics, science, and technology; initial comments on the draft interim report of the Curriculum and Assessment Council, from NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese, October 2; interim reports for mathematics, science, and technology, social studies, and English language arts</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9d32cdff68c87cbfb698223d0db5d6f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council Subcommittees Meetings 12/14/92</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_23080da14a16fb738acac3dde890c93c" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ef73df975fcd062b3903204b200e7d1a" parent="aspace_23080da14a16fb738acac3dde890c93c" type="folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_75b8ea7b20ccb9fe7fb2b8dde670ceb6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Meeting agendas; notes</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7c33bc970c4b905ceeee90dee4830167" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council Meeting 3/22/93</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_ceb7863edbba042b3cb76f395024a559" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_8a8564b02b489e6bb8c32d502ef75c06" parent="aspace_ceb7863edbba042b3cb76f395024a559" type="folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a9d80d489b785c727f8a90cd4ed78252"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda; notes; summary of public comment on interim report, February; report of the Assessment Working Group meeting, February 23; report of the Implementation Working Group; interim report of the committee for technical and occupational studies, March 17; report of the Curriculum Working Group meeting; interim report of the committee for health, physical education, and home economics; interim report of the committee for languages other than English, "Communication Skills for a Changing World"; report of the SUNY Task Force on College Entry-Level Knowledge and Skills, March 22</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d8652b7da72460b3ac8ac9cd83e4cab6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council Meeting April 19, 1993</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_210c0e2fe9c0788c7acb069680900820" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3488279ce940d7e090ae5ae386e06ce9" parent="aspace_210c0e2fe9c0788c7acb069680900820" type="folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_155208f5278dcb417595a30e513e2b2f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda; notes; notes from March 22 meeting; interim reports of mathematics, science, and technology committee, English language arts committee, and social studies and assessment committee</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_1e0bc8f727bb2138baaf615de3c1957e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council 6/14-15/93</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_828bef3eb533d43417d8bfdaa6a68e0a" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5d1ff7fb3603e17a85b915de655ae182" parent="aspace_828bef3eb533d43417d8bfdaa6a68e0a" type="folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_06e943cf2d8cb60597efd4039d363dfd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Notes ("two key issues, ten other considerations"); reports of working groups</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e29670c044448e5ecd0d062e1cdbeaa9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council Fall 1993</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_f60d141eced7d626b8425c1e5e6b8bef" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_23418abf001c9642b6b932e7036a6fc7" parent="aspace_f60d141eced7d626b8425c1e5e6b8bef" type="folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_da44c3e34236eb0cb91453acaf56a9f5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Memo, Creation by NYSUT of Positions/Strategies for Council Approval, August 16; draft Program Evaluation Guide: A System for Planning and Program Improvement in Secondary Occupational Education, with cover letter from NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese to Commissioner Sobol, expressing concern over low standards, September 15; other critiques by Cortese; NYSUT Review of the Format of the Draft Math, Science, Technology Curriculum Framework; related materials</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_5bd8d7e6860323c7673808945b127a2c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summary of Curricular Entitlement and Its Context in NYS 10/15/93</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d0d4650343e7cd8128b2dfc7f9e17b4" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f685b21f9cbfe0c44c1a11bfb8eeb55f" parent="aspace_4d0d4650343e7cd8128b2dfc7f9e17b4" type="folder">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_166f33ba6ed1a15546c165bb5b295bb8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Summary for discussion with the Board of Regents, prepared by Pat Flynn, NYSUT; memo from Flynn, comparing and contrasting the MST curriculum framework and the NCTM and 2061 standards, December 2; NYSUT review of the draft math, science, and technology (MST) curriculum framework</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_de28e8dadcf5e1eec75aa04095d2ccdc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council Meeting 10/25/93</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f511b9a8e162f56ff26d2dddef5a033" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ff9aa363ee29cff2554099d175e33fd0" parent="aspace_5f511b9a8e162f56ff26d2dddef5a033" type="folder">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_524bedcb90a82912a80722df3ad91267"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Draft reports by committees (English language arts, social studies, technical and occupational studies, arts and humanities, languages other than English, health, physical education, and home economics); related memos</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f138d15cf71019392d84c7f9836cd4af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council Meeting Jan.-Feb. 1994</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994">1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_3213a14bab1904b83f9eb8e0d6b9aedf" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3c63df8011b77be60953fc482a6dbe51" parent="aspace_3213a14bab1904b83f9eb8e0d6b9aedf" type="folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_17f67c5c441afb952ca60fb6ddcc3b20"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Memo from Pat Flynn, NYSUT, re diagrams and summary of council recommendations, January 7, 1994; proposed agenda items for Feb. 14 council meeting; notes from meeting; notes from Regents meeting of January 14; notes from meeting with David Green, critiquing State Education Department and New Compact for Learning; summary of notes from strategy meetings on public and educators review of the council's report and MST curriculum frameworks; notes from Regents' discussion on assessment; related memos from Flynn; list of states engaged in performance assessment, with descriptions; council recommendations on curriculum and assessment and implementation through a new state assessment system</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a796e3409342a78d5cc34c67af1d1d14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994">1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_d55f4a453df07bdb0875d092c7a9d305" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_bbfb0424e61ac5417977e0b86f5a7b13" parent="aspace_d55f4a453df07bdb0875d092c7a9d305" type="folder">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67da79224f2140ebac05856bf206bddc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spring. Commentary from NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese and others on the English language arts curriculum framework; memos from Flynn re social studies curriculum framework; related correspondence</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_5911551757b77f0f748a4622bedf1721" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council Report</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994">1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c37308c221d89a10ed4e471f6664276" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_e4bac736d7956227bf3a1136facc42b1" parent="aspace_9c37308c221d89a10ed4e471f6664276" type="folder">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_245d18119c9d0f70f5de976c3876b5ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>April. Report of the New York State Curriculum and Assessment Council, "Learning-Centered Curriculum and Assessment for New York State"; summary and full report from State Education Department for public review</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_5f56839f98c254615582ee918eeb168a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Essential Skills and Dispositions</unittitle><container id="aspace_4f26d9a353e25af9106e3c70493d28b8" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_89fb0b2be2c56aadbef9d94917369024" parent="aspace_4f26d9a353e25af9106e3c70493d28b8" type="folder">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ccacf759595baca8a35368cefcfd935d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Document drawn from Curriculum and Assessment Council's Curriculum Working Group</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3a03c8ad05ef637361b0298bddb42de0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council 5/16/94</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994">1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e497aff878a41b0762f226bee95cc72" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_82033f6bbd0b7a3a50021a726f3f261f" parent="aspace_6e497aff878a41b0762f226bee95cc72" type="folder">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_069cd9eccfa805929b8fd93817f82e61"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda; NYSUT commentary on 3/10/94 draft of the social studies curriculum framework; memos by Pat Flynn to NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese and others re notes from May 16 meeting and issues needing to be addressed</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_6f943f76e8c1c7f8f4264298034e8d88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Curriculum and Assessment Council 10/31/94</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994">1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_a23409964f70f38d814beb9a4d6b6d71" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3b6f5ec606aaf7dd26e931564915dbe8" parent="aspace_a23409964f70f38d814beb9a4d6b6d71" type="folder">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_137b037906fc961d0bfcb5f172d5d9f3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>NYSUT commentary on English language arts curriculum framework; report to the National Educational Goals Panel, "Promises to Keep: Creating High Standards for American Students," November 15, 1993; AFT Criteria for High Quality Standards; cover letter from Antonia Cortese suggesting review criteria, October 28, 1994; memo to Cortese from Pat Flynn with attached document, "Strategy to Introduce and Make Explicit Core Content Knowledge in the NYS Curriculum Frameworks"</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_be4e3fcfd43bb0a9385ceb4efc86a6c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Commission on Equitable School Funding (1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1981" type="inclusive">1979-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_6cd6c81f3547892b9faa95a5417a2f3a" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_0f7a6b24ae6b4fecb23f34edc76e16ea" parent="aspace_6cd6c81f3547892b9faa95a5417a2f3a" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fbb3f0cd25888feb8f704538614a187c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"A Policy Report to the Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education Related to the Problems of City School Districts Subject to the Constitutional Tax Limit," Education Commission of the States, January 19, 1980; other reports by commission, "Analysis of New York Income Measures," "Alternative Measures of School District Fiscal Capacity," "Cost of Education Indices"; draft report prepared for NYS Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education, "Who Bears the Cost of New York's Schools? Understanding the Tax Burden," September 1979; list of members of NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding; Responses of Thomas Y. Hobart, Jr., President of the New York State United Teachers, to the Survey-Questionnaire of the Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education, September 1981; Summary Brief-in-Chief of Defendants-Appellants in Levittown Appeal; NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding: Review of Rubin Retreat: Issues, January 6, 1982; printout of estimated impact of NYSUT state aid proposal on 1982-83 state operating aid, by district</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_676cef2d8302dfc5896b2dd32c3cf48f" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Commission on Equitable School Funding (2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1979" type="inclusive">1976-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_b0fdc6a232d965f2a66e86d0fe5cc537" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_3291d853e936cdcd4cae605f3e903910" parent="aspace_b0fdc6a232d965f2a66e86d0fe5cc537" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c0fc5286f091c3e07ab8ea0432fb78a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"The Search for Equity," Interim Report of the NYS Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education, May 1979; "The Equalization Rate in the Property Tax: What It Is and What It Does," State Board of Equalization and Assessment, December 1976; Division of Equalization and Assessment paper, "Legislative and Administrative Response to the Hellerstein Decision - Progress toward Full Value Assessment," November 10, 1978; NYSUT Information Bulletins, "State Aid for Elementary and Secondary Public Schools in the 1979-80 Executive Budget," February 1979, and "State Aid Proposal of the New York State Regents, 1979-80," November 1978; legal memorandum by NYSUT general counsel James Sandner re impact on teachers of Levittown v. Nyquist, University of California v. Bakke, and NLRB v. Yeshiva, August 23, 1978; paper, "Overview of New York State's System for Financing Public Schools," Division of the Budget, November 2, 1978; memorandum from assistant attorneys general to chair of Task Force on Equalizing Educational Opportunity re Levittown v. Nyquist; Summary of Levittown Decision as Regards Urban Plaintiffs-Intervenors; State Education Department booklet, "Public School Enrollment and Staff, New York State 1977-78"</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_aed552b358b904b5e2dd4fcec00fe646" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Commission on Equitable School Financing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_449ea11cdb3b518cc71ae3c28bccc1e3" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_13e3762d5aacf26da14290d3892f36be" parent="aspace_449ea11cdb3b518cc71ae3c28bccc1e3" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c75d8f098182a61d0d25da85d74eb6d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10/4/80. Memo from Tom Hobart to NYSUT Commission on Equitable School Financing re second interim report, upcoming meeting, September 18; letter from Hobart to staff director of NYS Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education (aka Rubin Commission), inviting her to meeting</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_1c0d4ebbbf467beb29aeac32d58b9505" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Commission on Equitable School Funding-March 1979-March 1980</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7fa81faf471d49d64313c7c00201728" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_b59354e31b0be698e325bd91a506bd4d" parent="aspace_f7fa81faf471d49d64313c7c00201728" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_85fd120e384442fcc0f7b17caa50503e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>List of members of NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding; tentative agenda of March 23, 1979, meeting; correspondence with president of Rochester Teachers Association re appointment to commission, March 1980; commission document, Selected Data on School Finance, March 2-3, 1979</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e303eab8a9306c8e7176159a9d6434e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education-Albany</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_675666c2b3acafa9ecea826554a58a5d" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4df8d36fb4359fb74e2354cdf9c75561" parent="aspace_675666c2b3acafa9ecea826554a58a5d" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0857a464d7b4b4faa89bc0c98a31f163"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3/5/80. Invitation to assistant attorney general to attend meeting of NYSUT Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education; memo advising that assistant attorney general would not be attending, per decision of the solicitor general; reports by Education Commission of the States; handwritten notes; materials re Levittown decision</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2d89a0a6da63203b1215da1ef634acb3" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT-Education Commission of the States Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ec852c9e836b7716dcf1054e06ba39a" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_1347c9354291cd9d3ba516a859d405e4" parent="aspace_4ec852c9e836b7716dcf1054e06ba39a" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_45d062c7e0c615d4255b1065ae4c126a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Invitation to assistant attorney general to attend meeting of NYSUT Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education; invitation to representative of Education Commission of the States to speak at meeting; reports by Education Commission of the States</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a09ea41f88a9c799435cd40c068e7293" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT-Division of Research and Educational Services-Various Publications</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1979" type="inclusive">1976-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_04f70bc3a81210aef45b514bbf1b9b32" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_b83f250f5494326257db81ec923be52b" parent="aspace_04f70bc3a81210aef45b514bbf1b9b32" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5233e0d0e696726fe277bd7ebd34aaad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Reports by NYS Budget Division re measuring the wealth of school districts, 1978; State Education Department publication, "Understanding Financial Support of Public Schools," 1978-79; NYSUT-generated financial data; agenda for meeting of NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding, March 2-3, 1979</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_93c183c98a4f59c1707256aeb536b207" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding-NYC, Biltmore Hotel</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_edc0728a7c0a9279ba77040955574af9" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_45932bb9de6fb9ac55333f6a431b54d1" parent="aspace_edc0728a7c0a9279ba77040955574af9" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2edabdab0224a72f0a285ec4a815a79"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>March 23, 1979. Agenda; memos from Tom Hobart; NYSUT Information Bulletins re state aid for public schools in the 1979-80 executive budget and the state aid proposal of the NYS Regents, 1979-80; Urgent Message to Flat Grant Districts from the Association of Flat Grant Districts of New York; discussion guide by Farm Bureau: school financing after Levittown; 1979 Policies, New York Farm Bureau</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_47f61660a014358cb851af031c503750" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding-March 23, 1979</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_893d87b3393a6a32301bb3197afd1273" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_ec3f822a0fb0390b74248b749f53d94c" parent="aspace_893d87b3393a6a32301bb3197afd1273" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5c9f366118591c06cd5237743d37ccdd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agenda; correspondence; materials for Long Island Presidents' Meeting, "Implications of Levittown School Financing Case," February 9-10, 1979; NYSUT-generated basic financial data in major operating school districts, 1976-77; NYS Budget Division report, "Measuring the Wealth of School Districts for the Apportionment of Aid to Public Schools in NYS: Full Valuation vs. Personal Income," August 1978; handwritten notes</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_6b6ff8273c786bfcd40dafd8055f4975" level="file"><did><unittitle>Teacher Education Conference Board (1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1984" type="inclusive">1981-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5f38ceba64e641d8f19a0a6f6326507" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_466671a0e563a556059202aac6b82be0" parent="aspace_f5f38ceba64e641d8f19a0a6f6326507" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b511ca407a45a697522eda102de36cd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Meeting agendas and minutes; 1983-84 and 1982-83 membership lists; constitution; staff consultant's report, 1982-83; materials by Regents re teacher disciplinary procedures and other issues</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2ff75ff97d27c7aae534a4fd240806f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Teacher Education Conference Board (2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1983" type="inclusive">1980-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ce511f4f1a68c3d059478c77830722d" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_8a4a8017cd33df4f1acc243b1e4f053b" parent="aspace_2ce511f4f1a68c3d059478c77830722d" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_37a8e711ba59472c954c1d1e50a6b905"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Agendas and minutes; draft position papers on computers in schools, November-December 1982; membership lists; related materials</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ec8e0930903fc0ba0c44961b2032b23b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Teacher Education Conference Board (3 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1983" type="inclusive">1980-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3f2ff3f729e189e7ace61ec1d38ec21" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_e7f5084f90be78c734c3b3508e972455" parent="aspace_d3f2ff3f729e189e7ace61ec1d38ec21" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d10be0293e2dbda73a08840e3051f1d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Minutes of Board of Regents meetings; TECB position paper, "The Effective Teacher"; membership lists; agendas; memo summarizing special meeting with Commissioner Ambach re federal education budget cuts, March 16, 1981;</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_994d48f12471e2525def6d2d6ee15243" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding 1/6/82</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_6baf2eee6133a20b97829b5713a658c0" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_d1ad5cdd9859eb2feaaa33edac8aefb8" parent="aspace_6baf2eee6133a20b97829b5713a658c0" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_34bf9f782772ace30b1d05fcd4fbbf5a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Responses of Thomas Y. Hobart, Jr., President of New York State United Teachers, to the Survey-Questionnaire of the Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education, September 1981, outlining NYSUT position supporting increased state aid and minimum spending incentives, opposing spending caps, and related issues; Recommended NYSUT/ECB (Educational Conference Board) State Aid Proposal for 1982-83; estimated impact of NYSUT state aid proposal, by district; NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding: Review of Rubin Retreat: Issues, January 6, 1982; handwritten notes</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_386a5be07fa63ce98cee761c4e365baf" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Task Force Legal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_97384aa3f3598d3eb9715172db61668b" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_134e439599a73d4351295b7a41d7b6a2" parent="aspace_97384aa3f3598d3eb9715172db61668b" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b9505cc9f4e0df019ed7e529d34e046b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Legal brief, Levittown v. Nyquist, October 26, 1981; letter from Hobart with attached summary of the five spending plans that emerged from the work of the NYS Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_0ddc99ab47d961767d91698e706f2c89" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding 1/6/82</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_bd11d20379e694e126e440df07b10b88" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_27a6107c90246a457a659cee83f1f3ab" parent="aspace_bd11d20379e694e126e440df07b10b88" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1417694737321fe05d972cc56d90a572"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Letter from Hobart to members of the NYSUT Commission on Equitable Public School Funding re special meeting on January 6, 1982, to discuss Levittown decision, work of Rubin Task Force (NYS Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education), December 2, 1981</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
