<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL05124</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Distributive Office and Processing Workers' Union Arbitration <num>5124</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>March 07, 2019</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall Tower Road</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 607-255-3183</addressline><addressline>kheelref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-11-20 00:03:16 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Distributive Office and Processing Workers' Union Arbitration</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="creator" source="ingest">Distributive, Processing, and Office Workers of America</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>5124</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.33 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_10b47a4df19725137caef852deb083b2" label="Quantity:">0.3 linear ft.</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_f5538889c2126328225854e6b273d092" label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents).</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_4bcc9ed94cdabf51f317203bb3eeadd3">Proceedings of arbitration hearing between District 65, Distributive, Processing and Office Workers Union, and Gimbel Brothers.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_55a259fd08eea8d904f9af570a768f1f">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">5555661</unitid>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_27532a75043164de65b0dfc251c78588">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>On May 27, 1952, upon request from District 65, Distributive, Processing and Office Workers Union, The American Arbitration Association appointed David L. Cole to arbitrate the wage dispute between Distrlc 65 and Gimbel Brothers. The hearings began in New York City on July 17, 1952. </p><p> The issues in the dispute are concerned with wages (minima, progression, automatics) classifications, and changes in vacations and holidays. From February 1, 1952, when the contract came up for negotiation, until May, when Mr. Cole was called in, no agreement could be reached on the issues. Throughout this period, however, the employees remained at work. </p><p> The union maintains that the wages paid at Gimbels are far below the wages paid at comparable department stores, and that these wages are insufficient in terms of the present cost of living. Basically, the union is concerned with cutting down the wage differential which exists between Gimbels and the other large department stores in the city, by attempting to force Gimbels participate in industry-wide bargaining. The union is seeking a wage increase commensurate with increases in other department stores. The company claims that its financial condition prohibits a wage increase at the present time. The company also claims that it is impossible to make wage adjustments comparable to other stores; there are too many factors which must be taken into consideration - there is no simple relationship between the various stores.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2f24c7119514dd25528326917d6e8bef">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>On May 27, 1952, upon request from District 65, Distributive, Processing and Office Workers Union, the American Arbitration Association appointed David L. Cole to arbitrate the wage dispute between District 65 and Gimbel Brothers. The hearings began in New York City on July 17, 1952. </p><p> The issues in the dispute are concerned with wages (minima, progression, automatics) classifications, and changes in vacations and holidays. From February 1, 1952, when the contract came up for negotiation, until May, when Mr. Cole was called in, no agreement could be reached on the issues. Throughout this period, however, the employees remained at work. The union maintained that the wages paid at Gimbels were far below the wages paid at comparable department stores, and that these wages were insufficient in terms of the present cost of living. The union was concerned with cutting down the wage differential which existed between Gimbels and the other large department stores in the city, by attempting to force Gimbels to participate in industry- wide bargaining. The union sought a wage increase commensurate with increases in other department stores. The company claimed that its financial condition prohibited a wage increase at that time. The company also claimed that it was impossible to make wage adjustments comparable to other stores; there were too many factors which must be taken into consideration - there was no simple relationship between the various stores.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1a36bf485ec42860b16c4d99c0ae97a5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_92e8b56aa1dbc2d512d52efe0253c959">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d318f57acce1b9966d7e2e033e209599">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Distributive Office and Processing Workers' Union Arbitration #5124. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_e7a15940db61c19399b5bb490ef40846">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related Collections:  /3012: Alice Cook Papers  /4212: Kheel Center Current Documents Correspondence  5012: Saul Wallen Papers  5131: Sidney A. Wolff Arbitration Files  5206-PR: Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records  5305: Benjamin H. Wolf Papers  5477: Benjamin Wolf Papers  5538: James C. Hill Arbitration Files  5539: Benjamin H. Wolf Additional Arbitration Files  5548: I. Robert Feinberg Arbitration Records  5588: David L. Cole Papers  5619/004: ACTWU President Jacob Sheinkman Files  5619/007: ACTWU Organizing Department Files  5619/018: ACTWU Secretary-Treasurer's Office Files  5619/023: ACTWU Social Services Department Files  5619/036: ACTWU President's Office Murray Finley Files  5637: Sidney A. Wolff Additional Arbitration Files  5712: Burton B. Turkus Arbitration Files  5733: Peter Seitz Arbitration Files  5736: Barbara Wertheimer Additional Files  5780/014 P: ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Photographs  5780/143: ILGWU James Parrot Papers  5780/203: ILGWU Jay Mazur Papers  5787 mf: New York State Labor Documentation Project on Microfilm  5917 P: Joint Board, Fur, Leather &amp; Machine Workers Union Additional Photographs  5933 P: Local 1199 Photograph Files  5940: International Workers Order Case Files  5961: John W. McConnell Additional Arbitration Files  5981 P: ACTWU Labor Unity Photograph Files  6030: Archival Collective Bargaining Agreements File  6034: Rare Pamphlet Collection  6046: Archives Union File (AUF)  6091: Marcia Greenbaum Papers  6092 MB: Labor Action Coalition Memorabilia</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <odd id="aspace_9365483e1e97f606e6ded50061950fe3">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheelref@cornell.edu">kheelref@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel">https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>Kheel Staff, November 01, 2007</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Department stores -- Employees -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Wages -- Clerks (Retail trade) -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Department stores -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining -- Clerks (Retail trade) -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <persname source="ingest">Cole, David L. (David Lawrence), 1902-1978</persname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Distributive, Processing, and Office Workers of America</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Distributive, Processing, and Office Workers of America. District 65</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Gimbel Brothers</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">5555661</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_1f3d7d0d4c9b156d90502c2ebb634b5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Arbitration Association, Between District 65 and Gimbel Brothers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_a86c6829e003d73955675892da7736b5" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6919f98e4640dfc96d4f8a93593f58fe" parent="aspace_a86c6829e003d73955675892da7736b5" type="folder">1</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
