<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL05300</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Railway Labor Executives' Association Miscellany <num>5300</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by E. Parker</author><sponsor>This collection was processed with the help of generous funding from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC).</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>August 08, 2017</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall Tower Road</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 607-255-3183</addressline><addressline>kheelref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-11-20 00:05:02 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Railway Labor Executives' Association Miscellany</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="creator" source="ingest">Railway Labor Executives' Association (RLEA)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>5300</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1909/1969" type="inclusive">1909-1969</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_c16f6e5a89ea303aaafca7c979a4e1fd" label="Quantity:">1.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_dc5d9a14067a84b88e4f3535457b6a4e" label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents).</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_09e282f15a57ed00a263d1eefed4dd91">This collection contains select records of the Railway Labor Executives' Association.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_4d037b483451433cc3e514d8409a3e8f">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">5596505</unitid>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_096a7fb8fe4ef45066c62e99845fce20">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The RLEA was founded in 1926 in response to the passage of the Railway Labor Act. Prior to 1926, there had been an informal association between the railroad labor organizations so that the various chief executives of the different unions could work together to form a unified course of action that would benefit all of their members. This group became more formalized immediately after the end of World War I. The U.S. railroads had been nationalized as part of the war effort, and the railroad labor organizations wanted them to remain under federal management, both because of increased productivity and because of better labor relations with the industry. The effort was ultimately unsuccessful, and the railroads returned to private industry; however, the railroad labor organizations had realized the need to have a united front to counter the carriers and industry groups and lobbyists. </p><p> On May 18, 1926, the chief executives of the railroad labor organization met in Washington D.C., formalized their association with By-Laws, and elected officers to serve the newly created RLEA. The original purpose, codified in the original preamble, was co-operative action to obtain and develop consistent interpretations and utilization of the Railway Labor Act. The RLEA was comprised of the chief executives of the 21 railroad labor unions, including the president of the Railway Employees' Department of the AFL, and each member got one vote, regardless of the size of their union. The organization was voluntary, so no member organization was bound by its decisions. Over the course of its existence, various member organizations withdrew and then re-affiliated with the RLEA. </p><p> From 1926 to 1938, the RLEA did not maintain an office, but the amount of work and its importance led the RLEA to open an office in Washington DC and employ a full-time Executive Secretary-Treasurer to run it. The RLEA did not engage in collective bargaining itself, but rather lobbied on behalf of its member organizations, securing such achievements as the Railroad Retirement Act and limiting unemployment for its members during the Great Depression. The RLEA's various areas of interest, such as retirement, safety, legal matters, were broken down into committees, each of which reported back to the executive board on the steps being taken in those areas. </p><p> Post World War II, the RLEA played a central role in the Marshall Plan, working with non-Communist labor organizations in Western Europe to establish labor policy and also assist in the work of rebuilding the European railroads. The RLEA was also a major factor in international labor union federations, and its decision to affiliate with the International Transport Workers' Federation [ITWF] and to encourage the ITWF not to join with the Soviet affiliated World Federation of Trade Unions was seen as a major victory for the west. </p><p> The RLEA, like its member organizations, did not allow African-American members. As such, it was only representing the interests of white railroad employees; black railroad employees were forced, for the most part, to work without recognized union protection. The exception to this was the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters [BSCP], who in 1948 began a series of successful legal challenges to the jurisdictions over various classes of work. As BSCP's successes in the courts mounted up, and the RLEA's member unions and the RLEA itself were being sued for discriminatory practices, the RLEA finally capitulated in 1950, and accepted the BSCP as a member organization. </p><p> In 1950, the RLEA joined with the AFL, CIO, and International Association of Machinists to form the United Labor Policy Committee. This committee oversaw the labor representatives of the Wage Stabilization Board. </p><p> In the latter half of the 20th century, the importance of the RLEA declined alongside the decline in the railroad industry itself. As its member unions either merged into single entities or disaffiliated from the RLEA its influence waned, as did the number of its members. The RLEA attempted to counter this decline with the purchase of a railroad at least three different times in the 1970s and 1980s, though they were ultimately unsuccessful in this venture. Ongoing internal battles between the remaining chief executives of the railroad unions further weakened the RLEA until in 1997 it disbanded, handing over its responsibilities to the newly formed AFL-CIO Transportation Trades Department.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d9d9872c7e41b93ad71842573fed74a6">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Inclusive date range: 1909-1969 </p><p> Bulk dates: 1945-1966 </p><p> This collection consists of miscellaneous records from the Railway Labor Executives' Association. The majority of the records found in this collection deal with the issues faced by railroad labor in the 1950s and 1960s when the major carriers began to merge and to abandon lines. The applications of the carriers to the Interstate Commerce Committee [ICC] are documented in the Finance Docket filings. Also of note are the speeches by various railroad labor chief executives in which they speak out against the mergers because of the effect they would have on the nation's economy and on local communities whose tax bases depended on the railroad industry. This collection also contains drafts of a study commissioned by the RLEA about railroad mergers. Also found are public relations materials from the RLEA addressing the mergers as well as pushing back against accusations of featherbedding by the carriers. Finally, the correspondence files contain bulletins and circulars issued by the RLEA about various cases that effect the employees represented by their member unions.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0e66a3ea437ffe7af8ec2557db8be29f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c640c66534deb462cff9eef0406698fa">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_adeeb413e5bbde0ea73b608d6a4e3c75">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Railway Labor Executives' Association Miscellany #5300. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_3603e1a6318d29ebaf5f465bc24e0179">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related Collections:  /3007: Maurice Neufeld Papers  /4055: James O. Morris Office Files  /4212: Kheel Center Current Documents Correspondence  5001: American Association for Labor Legislation Records  5001 mf: American Association for Labor Legislation Records on Microfilm  5034: Switchmen's Union of North America Records  5034 MB: Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia  5034 P: Switchmen's Union of North America Photographs  5060: U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records  5084: Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records  5139: UTU Records  5141: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Records  5149: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Records  5182: William J. Doble Papers  5204 mf: Southern Tenant Farmers Union Records on Microfilm  5300: Railway Labor Executives' Association Miscellany  5347: Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees, ICC, and Erie Lackawanna Briefs Regarding the Railroad Merger  5351: International Association of Machinists vs. S. B. Street Records  5405 mf: Switchmen's Union of North America Constitutions on Microfilm  5478: AFL-CIO Railway Employees' Department Records  5478 mf: AFL-CIO Railway Employees' Department Records on Microfilm  5484: Railway Labor Executives' Association Records  5484 AV: Railway Labor Executives' Association Audio-Visual Material  5487: Vernon H. Jensen Collection of International Longshoremen's Association's and Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen's Materials  5488 A: BRAC Chicago Files  5488 B: BRAC Records  5488 C: BRAC Additional Records  5541: Philip Taft Papers  5552: Railway Labor Executives' Association Additional Records  5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5  5622: UTU New York State Legislative Board Selected Files  5663 mf: Collective Bargaining Agreements on Microfilm  5728: Railway Labor Executives' Association Additional Records  5735: BRAC Additional Records  5833: James A. Paddock Additional Papers  5976 mf: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm  5989 mf: Blacks in the Railroad Industry on Microfilm  6030: Archival Collective Bargaining Agreements File  6040 P: Railroad Collection Photographs  6046: Archives Union File (AUF)  6047: Archives Information File  6118 AV: Kheel Center AV Collection</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <odd id="aspace_53c4b1d68d48f1c46c32f1fd00d168b2">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheelref@cornell.edu">kheelref@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel">https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>E. Parker, August 08, 2017</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>E. Parker, August 08, 2017</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2003009609" source="lcsh">Railroads -- United States -- Employees</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008110423" source="lcsh">Railroads -- Mergers -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroads -- Legislation -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining -- Railroads -- United States</subject>
    <persname source="ingest">Keyserling, Leon H. (Leon Hirsch), 1908-1987</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Lyon, Arthur E.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Leighty, George E. (George Earle)</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Beattie, Donald, S.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Harrison, George M. (George McGregor)</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Kennedy, W. P.</persname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Railway Labor Executives Association</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81008280" source="lcnaf">United States. Railroad Retirement Board</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79029236" source="lcnaf">United States. Railway Labor Act</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126245" source="lcnaf">United States. Interstate Commerce Commission</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">5596505</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_901ff8de33872605b59a24fd33eb7b29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Representation Authorization Cards, SUNA, Missouri Pacific Employees</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1952" type="inclusive">1951-1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_98d7cac39938c6d16f0215d6e298c498" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_39ca98e9238adfd4888e320b1d278052" parent="aspace_98d7cac39938c6d16f0215d6e298c498" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_331d1d32138a93b3f83d3b899a54059e" level="file"><did><unittitle>RLEA pamphlets: speeches by executive board members</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1961" type="inclusive">1959-1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_64dd6af711618239bfc89bcc32e7ea5e" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a603bc49380caaed7ee78c740612a4b3" parent="aspace_64dd6af711618239bfc89bcc32e7ea5e" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b31806c7502b2e1d313df8ff77f5ec54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>W. P. Kennedy, BRT; George M. Harrison, BRC; G. E. Leighty, RLEA Chairman</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_8364bced92d6cb5cc4497055df202d5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Why railroad men are losing their jobs." Gordon C. Harvey, Switchman, Rock Island Railway</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_34cc7635910302a70b64ab06ffce39ff" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_204bc2d25bf6ad64ac962308f8ca485d" parent="aspace_34cc7635910302a70b64ab06ffce39ff" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af8163572889f1192002835619ff0fe0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>circa 1937</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_490be3c0798cbcbb55d648c71670cb26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Niagara Frontier Committee for the Defense of America, correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1943" type="inclusive">1940-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb81e171e14e0d798d561f84a2c3e0cc" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_267da8daffabd6c9e6afff35372e68bf" parent="aspace_fb81e171e14e0d798d561f84a2c3e0cc" type="folder">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_97ebae4acc4936ebd9c1fc5f4db8dda1" level="file"><did><unittitle>RLEA Description and General Explanation of S. 1911 and HR 4805</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_9060b91aa811424fdf6b7def6f95ef33" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_afe17156cd8224ab27730f7b62830500" parent="aspace_9060b91aa811424fdf6b7def6f95ef33" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd43dc3ab2186c331300a31e0806d511"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Amendments to Railroad Retirement Act</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e32544fef98fbb07983a315a0f77fd7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mergers, general: Press Releases, Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1963" type="inclusive">1950-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ed93d6a4431b526c147eb8fafac4f22" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_78bf2335035ca18e0e91ec5bc59e19b9" parent="aspace_0ed93d6a4431b526c147eb8fafac4f22" type="folder">6</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_66e1684127ce8ee504930fc85216e0f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interurban Electric Railway, abandonment</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_54adae5603743943b94d7ad9b056a915" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7702231218032386f440518ed9e273c6" parent="aspace_54adae5603743943b94d7ad9b056a915" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_122f0b5e1a07068ab0526d007253d8ad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>ICC Finance Docket No. 12792</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ccfa22a36e39ec941b32c0375f4ebdaf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Merger: Missouri-Pacific Railroad and Chicago and Eastern Illinois Railroad</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_8fd72fcb9127dc627a635406d394761e" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_319c0a41bb62ffadaf50bae85894404c" parent="aspace_8fd72fcb9127dc627a635406d394761e" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b947251de73207e30cb5c0cf9a9520a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>ICC Finance Docket No. 21755</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_4e77325a59485b7d545f788c447f781c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Merger: Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad, Baltimore and Ohio Railroad</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad8021f9708c446d947b04c31eff31ca" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_00610c97b78e2171bf55f4b20c404618" parent="aspace_ad8021f9708c446d947b04c31eff31ca" type="folder">9a</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_78c3454497f57eb4b67108bbc4ca6ca1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>ICC Finance Docket No. 21160</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f54685d0bc2500dee08de206b9501746" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rutland Railway, abandonment</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1963" type="inclusive">1962-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_b724b9b4856781b9dee957a779210166" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1f79e69ecd4779797ecd40eb24aff280" parent="aspace_b724b9b4856781b9dee957a779210166" type="folder">9b</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_42e81da1cd519b8e0a6c2a8c269e3a2e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>ICC Finance Docket No. 21870</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_391adb1e943f9f63e0842fe7cd284ac5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Merger: Seaboard Air Line Railroad and Atlantic Coastline Railroad [folder1 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1964" type="inclusive">1962-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a0cbc65d9e355fc692afa904b32ba68" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_e7ccda8d673588c25b4953708bb9df24" parent="aspace_8a0cbc65d9e355fc692afa904b32ba68" type="folder">10a</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c6813ef2a697e859b49dbf3ea0996cc4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>ICC Finance Docket No. 21215</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7a6ce742af61ef3d085e2c285daba498" level="file"><did><unittitle>Merger: Seaboard Air Line Railroad and Atlantic Coastline Railroad [folder2 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1964" type="inclusive">1962-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_a9759ca2f835c9e735d1d13c70813921" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ce069aa6cceea06c69107606800a278b" parent="aspace_a9759ca2f835c9e735d1d13c70813921" type="folder">10b</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3ebb0fcdcbf443751a1a6543d1845b0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>ICC finance Docket No. 21215</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_6567ea1c78aecc6e8202171de4cc3311" level="file"><did><unittitle>RLEA Voting Record: How did your U.S. Senators and Congressmen vote?</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_82941105d81c19cb226c5d7c9052c2b6" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_35345b076146af4b481e00542bd9168b" parent="aspace_82941105d81c19cb226c5d7c9052c2b6" type="folder">11</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_38959f502b9496190245d33b46838f4a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Featherbedding: press releases, correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1963" type="inclusive">1945-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_2481f4a71162eda7b3d47a5a323fb29d" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_18a3767f17dcc990efa2652ba6aabd1e" parent="aspace_2481f4a71162eda7b3d47a5a323fb29d" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0df5cf7089ea7483a3e3740bd4184ebd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Merger: Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad and Chicago and North Western Railway</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_d60275f9f0256a842906253586549a69" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_11eabc9c77bcb5d11d49a617434e0155" parent="aspace_d60275f9f0256a842906253586549a69" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b443697737ab4164b3ee29c7e3ea6636"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Dispute re assignment of conductors in Escanaba Yards, Michigan</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_05379b9c3cd6be8f76ff70ea8b06abad" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Railroad Merger Mania: Its Causes and Cure" [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5ed4aa373bebe471c2b616c16daab46" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_49e28204c89ad8137e8f70e2a4b08cd8" parent="aspace_c5ed4aa373bebe471c2b616c16daab46" type="folder">3a</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_29665e32b4af604f390c6796cddc9a37"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A background manual concerning railroad consolidation and the public interest, from the Railroad Labor Executives' Board.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9f5c69aad9f844a8426250a332fe4789" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Railroad Merger Mania: Its Causes and Cure" [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b7d34ff11bc281ebd00374dfdf0fe29" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_e4200b6d7beebedbf1dbe663dead3d84" parent="aspace_2b7d34ff11bc281ebd00374dfdf0fe29" type="folder">3b</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63ac8f6f49d5d011add7e3aa3dd034e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A background manual concerning railroad consolidation and the public interest, from the Railroad Labor Executives' Board.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_709f4a5f216093a87ba8fbf0d79944b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>RLEA, Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1932/1945" type="inclusive">1932-1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5ec0a20882373ed50831cf307dc7e1f" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_0fff8128f387b21691cb624def7bada1" parent="aspace_b5ec0a20882373ed50831cf307dc7e1f" type="folder">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0dd888b5792e52b2300599b1bc2b4425" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minneapolis and St. Louis Railroad, potential merger and abandonment</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1934/1937" type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_d026f0b168aba91f90d414f6992c4f81" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_ca2a91edc26a04474965dc5304c3a7ea" parent="aspace_d026f0b168aba91f90d414f6992c4f81" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_add88f4eca7a4a3ddaf32d2430e61688"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>ICC Finance Docket No. 10947</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b8ac48642d0191190bff12bc98f0548d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brief filed by RLEA in front of ICC, in re Oklahoma Railway Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_961e02a91c656183d34541d3fe710b2d" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_6628796e7442d6b36e30f3477b9791ee" parent="aspace_961e02a91c656183d34541d3fe710b2d" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_14e7d4ad600d7633ffb34cd20ff81387"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Railway Labor Act Docket No. 15</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_0074227ae650fa1eac886c69b0320015" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1944" type="inclusive">1936-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_d36a9fb7e991cc99beeaa94856f8e117" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_d96c4ef9722b9e4f6e4abf76c0f6712e" parent="aspace_d36a9fb7e991cc99beeaa94856f8e117" type="folder">7</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fe5dcf761d4189be31a711889d94da2f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1952" type="inclusive">1947-1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_43ea60870e295a93fadda1e89c28aa5d" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_d2dd0cff3fe5bc80bda79fe223db465d" parent="aspace_43ea60870e295a93fadda1e89c28aa5d" type="folder">8</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fb2ae89f74848720292041322a102786" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1956" type="inclusive">1954-1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_84bab7b8d8c82f3f08593646f97e4ff8" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f0bf7a03e1e844daaeff863932d5d944" parent="aspace_84bab7b8d8c82f3f08593646f97e4ff8" type="folder">9</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1cc1e769550493a9365071794c2ec8cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1961" type="inclusive">1959-1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_efa779a6b22e2117d4a24cc2df63a625" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_c7a3b95aaea251197aaef4222aeb65e0" parent="aspace_efa779a6b22e2117d4a24cc2df63a625" type="folder">10</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_cc1e2cda44c6cd708f55c0d9ae258171" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a391e2aa88938bbeabcbb1c5062cac4" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_04554d740cfacb87b6261934ecf51fe9" parent="aspace_6a391e2aa88938bbeabcbb1c5062cac4" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_75247c73b69a8f64e56286d6240ab9ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_02e5d8720e0a18bc25543e3f1caa1806" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_b726e51c6e76c16b948b4b1480a5e335" parent="aspace_02e5d8720e0a18bc25543e3f1caa1806" type="folder">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fe11106f7e3c2f1a737849745129b279" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1969" type="inclusive">1966-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c2c897be64552ca4d93c41b5edc2187" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_e9a3ef10d7530e2135ab8fa1c445dda3" parent="aspace_2c2c897be64552ca4d93c41b5edc2187" type="folder">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_70226f1352a8ac331bfe1b1f981e882e" level="file"><did><unittitle>ICC Finance Docket No.s 22102 through 22198 [folder 1 of 4]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1966" type="inclusive">1962-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_1225b5df6ff0f007a608e9581bcdd126" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_f0e4991046cf645e310f4db32baa2c67" parent="aspace_1225b5df6ff0f007a608e9581bcdd126" type="folder">4a</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9b6bebffffa293e2a331bac667400924" level="file"><did><unittitle>ICC Finance Docket No.s 22102 through 22198 [folder 2 of 4]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1966" type="inclusive">1962-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f8a7ca3f5dfcdf49ecb4fd6cc2a36c1" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_d50d68189d73ace643abd6d9b3cb7763" parent="aspace_8f8a7ca3f5dfcdf49ecb4fd6cc2a36c1" type="folder">4b</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9456553e5a521015e3d59fa671187cd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>ICC Finance Docket No.s 22102 through 22198 [folder 3 of 4]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1966" type="inclusive">1962-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_56e10fe803974faf0a24cbdc004d201c" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_c8759fd475b990bf0f5853d3be9358ff" parent="aspace_56e10fe803974faf0a24cbdc004d201c" type="folder">4c</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_01e2f58fa575dc6d1d7e81d80e289cc2" level="file"><did><unittitle>ICC Finance Docket No.s 22102 through 22198 [folder 4 of 4]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1966" type="inclusive">1962-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_d17d0948f26cd10d0f80d56e930c47ea" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_c88ef87a1dd16e07ab3edfcd5cb2c449" parent="aspace_d17d0948f26cd10d0f80d56e930c47ea" type="folder">4d</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3bda334063f026b8041f6ddea86292b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letter from the American Railroad Employees and Investors Association</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1909/1909">1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_99d131ba52e68f3f74448b971606b0bf" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_0d207885babd99c675ebbc084d9676e9" parent="aspace_99d131ba52e68f3f74448b971606b0bf" type="folder">5</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d61ca81ed0b4ff5fa111368635560d48" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous Agreements, 1945 and 1967</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1967" type="inclusive">1945-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_70747f12cec0ca7c2abcc6d30425afa5" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_b1ade6c51428676e4b17e2edd9e857b5" parent="aspace_70747f12cec0ca7c2abcc6d30425afa5" type="folder">6</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
