<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL05206-pr</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records <num>5206-PR</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by CB</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>February 21, 2017</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall Tower Road</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 607-255-3183</addressline><addressline>kheelref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-10-10 00:05:18 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="creator" source="ingest">Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="creator" source="ingest">RWDSU Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Employees Union</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname role="creator" source="ingest">Davis, Leon</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>5206-PR</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1943/1975" type="inclusive">1943-1975</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_dd18193fedd3b08c92ac52b46e8fb576" label="Quantity:">14 linear ft.</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_706d7683923a298eb0ca8660733dda81" label="Forms of Material:">Records (records).</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_47f695c0c3f4a315ccffbc3633ef408f">Records of the National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees document the evolution of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store drugstore local, representing pharmacists and drug clerks in New York City, into an international union of non-professional and professional workers in voluntary and non-profit health institutions, including hospitals, clinics and nursing homes, as well as drugstores.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_328f9fdcbaed35829b33269f0b491c98">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">6694259</unitid>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2b1b121ee9ac7136808ef8d58f40d152">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Between 1933 and 1957, 1199 functioned as a drugstore local with its membership growing to 5,000 workers employed in independent and chain drugstores throughout the New York metropolitan area. With its success in organizing workers in Montefiore Hospital in New York City, the union began a massive campaign to organize workers in voluntary and non-profit hospitals in the New York area, a large proportion of whom were black or Hispanic. </p><p> In 1973, the national union was established with locals in other states, including Pennsylvania, Maryland, South and North Carolina, Connecticut, New Jersey, and Massachusetts. The union combined organizing efforts with civil rights organizations, in an effort to achieve mutual political goals. Throughout the period of these records, the union was led by Leon Davis (president of Local 1199 and of the national union) whose administration guided the union's political and social activities.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c0762e5f1112e004852666ab67fac0bd">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b31d26ccfdaf8d1700f627d85cc5b740">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_44dec63c4822bee8f756070bb059bee5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records #5206-PR. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_08991516e66f067ef3797a0548e046bf">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related Collections:  5206: Local 1199 Records  5206-G: Local 1199 Guild Division Records  5206: Local 1199 Records  5206-S: Local 1199 Executive Secretary Moe Foner Records  5206-X: Local 1199 Clippings and News Releases  5457: Mark Lillian Collection of Roosevelt Hospital (NYC) vs. Local 1199, 1962 Representational Dispute Documents  5510: Local 1199 Records  5520m: "Building a Union in the Hospitals: the Organization of Local 1199 at Montefoire Hospital, 1948-1958" Manuscript  5525: Local 1199 Additional Files  5651: Local 1199 Additional Records  5768: Sidney Cahn Collection of League of Voluntary Hospitals &amp; Homes of New York vs. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union Arbitration Files  5680 OH: Local 1199 Oral History Project  5854: Local 1199 Additional Records  5871: Local 1199 Additional Records  5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records  5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials  5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia  5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs  5933: Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union News files  5933 P: Local 1199 Photograph Files  5938: Local 1199 Leon Davis Additional Papers  5945: Local 1199 Additional Records  5948: Local 1199 (Rochester, N.Y.) Records  5984 AV: Local 1199 Additional Videos  5984 AV: Local 1199 Additional Videos  6016: Local 1199 National Benefit and Pension Fund Records  6062: Paul Friedman Collection of National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, Local 1199 Miscellany  6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files  6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets  6140: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project  6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings  6140 P: Local 1199 Moe Foner Photographs  6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files  6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials  6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia  6169 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs  6209 AV: 1199SEIU Audio-Visual Materials  6209 PUBS: Local 1199 Publications  6281m: Local 1199 Biography files  6347: 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Records  6347 PUBS: 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Publications</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <odd id="aspace_537c140e1d84dc466ee20710e6b037db">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheelref@cornell.edu">kheelref@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel">https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>CB, September 05, 2003</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Randall Miles, February 21, 2017</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="local">Labor unions -- Health facilities -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Strikes and lockouts -- Health facilities -- United States</subject>
    <persname audience="internal" source="ingest">Davis, Leon, 1907-1992</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n83059948" source="lcnaf">Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees. District 1199</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Employees Union (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">6694259</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_a9cadecb3a80ccc2cd550ec9e499f154" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anti-Poverty Program</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1968" type="inclusive">1963-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_be4ab016cdf86561b6872e3c2f6e0d52" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_f93c19359a47f0e5108f68c27cd4114f" parent="aspace_be4ab016cdf86561b6872e3c2f6e0d52" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60f51eb149bd8635c45012a9ce4a6f5f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with educational institutions, city officials, local courts, non-profit organizations, U.S. Department of Labor, AFL-CIO, and Robert F. Kennedy regarding educational, local and national programs and initiatives to alleviate poverty. Collection also contains dinner invitation, proposals, form letter, and memorandum regarding anti-poverty programs.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_03b40542ea91acb72b2cce9e4be8c180" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anton Refregier Mural Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_54e39641c9bd0ff91b9a82c707d7abfd" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_647ecdc2d8961bcabbf0b7f5bd095767" parent="aspace_54e39641c9bd0ff91b9a82c707d7abfd" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63921bad9275f55abbe94d486d5a1bf4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with Anton Refregier concerning the design and construction of a mural for the new 1199 building (310 West 43rd Street, New York, NY).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a968554431ff38eab477aa85276c169e" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Ardeon Realty Corporation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1969" type="inclusive">1965-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_7518ea983d7325bf1148081c1787e8d4" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ebc30b62c7ffaf8acf8b0a4b6e2b0833" parent="aspace_7518ea983d7325bf1148081c1787e8d4" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49a54e3e6897c79d1623d50060131706"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains financial reports, resolutions, statements of financial condition, appraisal report, and agreements regarding 1199's ownership and dealings with Ardeon.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_0c125bd8324751e5539fd2e8a132f00c" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Ardeon Realty Corporation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_faeacf4dd22f259b44ab13ee7d3d053d" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d0a5dbefbb11d2e618e65b2f1659cfff" parent="aspace_faeacf4dd22f259b44ab13ee7d3d053d" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35dd62bd440ebaf80e97cde989705ba6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers and real estate agent, financial reports, a resolution and a memorandum regarding loans and sales of Ardeon property, and the financial situation of Ardeon.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_1cf37bd08b7274f3e0fb7effb91e3664" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Ardeon Realty Corporation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad5addac1a6157b20e1b43071d04f05d" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4116391c76e828db7101a6bc21a52b48" parent="aspace_ad5addac1a6157b20e1b43071d04f05d" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0f9a8ef028ffb075a581bf42f993e59e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and a loan guaranty agreement between 1199 and First National City Bank for a loan made to Ardeon.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_4d2f9763c8b06c1d91c1e0d7a2898546" level="file"><did><unittitle>Association of Voluntary Long-Term Care Agencies</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_042ebf33928139729f70472030aa731d" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_99e9d0c9e55478bff03814169aee12f5" parent="aspace_042ebf33928139729f70472030aa731d" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0a5c5f54a30f1156e7c9790d9d10136e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers and the Association of Voluntary Long-Term Care Agencies regarding expiration of contracts and new contract provisions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_df3f1a548bbc7fbc151cafc2451fc2bf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Building (new) correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_65ae28d3b082c5cf1497c01e1086f155" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ef361d62e75a03d62d49db4903faeeea" parent="aspace_65ae28d3b082c5cf1497c01e1086f155" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0de4cd2aea24cd372570f7b45745daae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with First National City Bank regarding a loan, architect, electrician, and painter regarding building construction. Also contains memorandum on building color scheme, meeting minutes on layout of new building meeting, union expenses other than building construction. Lastly contains correspondence from an accountant regarding undocumented payments.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_eb86a6411580cc03e6bba6039ca262b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Building (new) Refregier</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea888fbeec5f0c1f8a53187ec4ac78d9" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a85688fce73c577f0658237c099e259c" parent="aspace_ea888fbeec5f0c1f8a53187ec4ac78d9" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a1ae5b367ad627322e88913c4f6169b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Leon Davis and Anton Refregier regarding completion of the mural and payment for mural design. Also contains brochure and price listing for wallcoverings.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_57481ee00e4d6eba9ad35781bddb09f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charleston Hospital Strikes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_a92a5cea478aba7ddca02e71bdc94f88" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_63e2dbb027ee26df592f3c0b789639c9" parent="aspace_a92a5cea478aba7ddca02e71bdc94f88" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6025e5a5efdf1409bb53e5fc5f6c08c4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with various religious groups, union members, unions, city officials, and other organizations either asking them to donate money or thanking them for their efforts in the Charleston Strike. Also contains handwritten notes by Julia Davis recording various New York City 1199 member's contributions to the Charleston Strike. Contains financial report on how much money 1199 obtained to help the strike. Contains correspondence between Leon Davis and Charleston Strikers. Contains correspondence with Leon Davis during his time in the Charleston Jail, including a leaflet with one of his letters in it. Contains letter to UAW discussing their support in the Charleston Strikes, Walter Reuther and some "disagreements" that are going on in the labor movement. Contains correspondence with George Meany, AFL-CIO president, Walter Reuther, Henry Van Arsdale, Rev. Abernathy, the NAACP and Harvard University in reference to the strike. Contains an advertisement by Coretta Scott King in support of the Charleston Strike. Contains airplane charter and list of passengers for 1199's journey from New York City to Charleston. Contains legal correspondence and memorandums regarding what happened at the Charleston Strike. Contains telegrams from Leon Davis during the strike. Contains angry correspondence from UAW to another union regarding their representation of the Charleston Strike to the public. Correspondence with Mount Sinai Hospital thanking them for treating Mary Moultrie (president of 1199B). Contains a meeting advertisement from 1199 to talk about the strike.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7e07daeaa79a8848d40850e5e32a19cb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Civil Rights</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_aaa7eb05a2fba6592fcf302faf2d84f4" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_b05f9a7c5f3910a958d04b35c44ca566" parent="aspace_aaa7eb05a2fba6592fcf302faf2d84f4" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_05d34da18b70f665a73287d6427b56e0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondence with student group, and telegram to Davis regarding Danville, VA segregation. Memorandum to 1199 members about participating in Martin Luther King jailing protest. Correspondence with President John F. Kennedy, NAACP. March on Washington, NYC Central Labor Council, and National Urban League regarding Birmingham bombings. Contains March on Washington organizing manual, flyers, 1st plan of operation, and form letters. Contains resolution adopted at NYC Central Labor Council Civil Right Rally, and invitation to Central Labor Council's 3rd Annual Civil Rights Conference. Correspondence and attendance cards for 1199 members regarding March on Washington. Contains 1199 leaflet.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b522cd2eaed64a4cf0bd4affdd1636c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Civil Rights</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1960" type="inclusive">1957-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_436f8eb1cee53a398c8e601f9792ff58" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_b59dddc664c4d4a03ffb7b13ccba574e" parent="aspace_436f8eb1cee53a398c8e601f9792ff58" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f40f9786462159dba25722d4eda1ba0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and press release regarding 1199 Negro History Week Celebration. Contains correspondence, a resolution, a public statement, a report, a subscription, pamphlets, lists, telegrams, speeches, flyers, a press release, a petition and invitations regarding conferences, meetings, dinners, monetary contributions, rallies and marches for civil rights and civil rights legislation. Contains correspondence and telegram from Davis to President Lyndon Johnson regarding civil rights, including response from the department of justice. Contains correspondence with several civil rights leaders from various different organizations, government officials and companies. Contains Leon Davis' certificate of life time membership to the National American Negro Freedom Movement.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_1e82879a9379e314cc8b2f9b87e729a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Civil Rights</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1966" type="inclusive">1960-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_15281e20562e1f85e3a1db83ebe1c567" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_38fb2bed66fc5aac716d2a7fd6c69ec7" parent="aspace_15281e20562e1f85e3a1db83ebe1c567" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e80cedd9c60f7e1766fe180ab4239ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and press release regarding 1199 Negro History Week Celebration. Contains correspondence, a resolution, a public statement, a report, a subscription, pamphlets, lists, telegrams, speeches, flyers, a press release, a petition and invitations regarding conferences, meetings, dinners, monetary contributions, rallies and marches for civil rights and civil rights legislation. Contains correspondence and telegram from Davis to President Lyndon Johnson regarding civil rights, including response from the department of justice. Contains correspondence with several civil rights leaders from various different organizations, government officials and companies. Contains Leon Davis' certificate of life time membership to the National American Negro Freedom Movement. Contains correspondence from Davis to Martin Luther King Jr. regarding Lawrence Hospital Strike, and an annual report, form letter and telegram from Dr. King. Contains correspondence with actor Ossie Davis who is upset with the magazine The Liberator for publishing an article accusing Jewish people of hurting African American's. Contains a few copies of The Liberator including the above mentioned article.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a09198b52867ea37638705b7fc3e8fd7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Columbia School of Social Work</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a8f9b66c981ab8197ac4490b9c2efe4" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_52ed28dbb9ec60d941479e64d45588b2" parent="aspace_5a8f9b66c981ab8197ac4490b9c2efe4" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_062c75225da880e0132dfaadf2049932"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with professors, journalists, and 1199 members, plus an agreement, a list of students, form letters, invitations and flyers about the Community Organization Program sponsored by 1199 and the Columbia University School of Social Work.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3508de738330fe18a8f193bd37aeecd1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Congressional Hearings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1953" type="inclusive">1948-1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b235c8431c0c7a337b53ed8f71d7286" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_6ed262e3f4654841bc64f9070c6a2bfc" parent="aspace_6b235c8431c0c7a337b53ed8f71d7286" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70b6dfdecda01bb7cfcfc0510ab64cc5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains public congressional hearings investigating communist activities in labor organizations. Contains statements by 1199 members who accompanied Davis to Washington when he went in front of the Hartley Committee. Contains Davis' testimony in front of the Hartley Committee. Contains telegrams from Davis supporters. Contains clipping about communism in labor unions. Contains 1199 press releases from 1948 when 1199 and the Bronx County Pharmaceutical corporation shut down 650 Bronx drugstores in support of Israel.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c3a0c212b5e3cc833cd188df518db6ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Constitutional Amendments</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1969" type="inclusive">1964-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_e791a70c0e6f05779f54297c438a79a0" label="unspecified" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_d66145f8e105c7d1a71b88fae640ef06" parent="aspace_e791a70c0e6f05779f54297c438a79a0" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_299664a30048237202619b2ee55bcb05"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains proposed amendments and actual amendments to the Constitution of Local 1199. Contains correspondence regarding, and meeting minutes from meetings discussing, amendments to the 1199 Constitution. Contains ballots regarding union dues schedule for 1199 Drug Division employees, including ballot results.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a281e979a4268b6ae0b1cb5d5365dc52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contributions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_03a4704adc3df31cd2c7dbad31c1a0fd" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_b8772c44557bfdc616eacbe13485b3e8" parent="aspace_03a4704adc3df31cd2c7dbad31c1a0fd" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_998abb464c614df0f3d7a9340ea98458"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and form letters regarding Local 1199's contributions (via monetary donations, ticket purchases, memberships and advertisements) to various civil rights organizations and leaders (including Martin Luther King), unions and other organizations. Contains requests for contributions in the form of correspondence (including information about the organizations such as reports, financials, brochures, and clippings) press releases, contribution receipts, and invitations and flyers for events. Contains meeting minutes from an organization that mentions Davis and local 1199. Contains memorandum regarding New York Shakespeare festival. Contains form letter from Theodore W. Kheel to local 1199 for their contributions. Contains handwritten notes regarding contributions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_794587ad72e1b0f6993ba82d8ed33134" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contributions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_0bd1a6ec258b62ad3f05ee7514d41713" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_5905fcf392930d5a0b35c9bb53ae57f2" parent="aspace_0bd1a6ec258b62ad3f05ee7514d41713" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8cc2d3683189f9cc2ba2a6da42fb9e34"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, telegrams and form letters regarding Local 1199's contributions (via monetary donations, ticket purchases, memberships and advertisements) to various civil rights organizations and leaders, unions and other organizations. Contains requests for contributions in the form of correspondence (including information about the organizations such as financials, brochures, and agendas), contribution receipts, and invitations and flyers for events. Contains handwritten notes regarding contributions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2ff1f8acf934f2c2fefd6d0ae3de41c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contributions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1971" type="inclusive">1966-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_335c3b4ac612f8cbc3cae7ba7fa41737" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_298cd6602cdea9f42d9c8e28a89a672d" parent="aspace_335c3b4ac612f8cbc3cae7ba7fa41737" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_319be6895347dbf264e6fab257a75a33"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, telegrams and form letters regarding Local 1199's contributions (via monetary donations, ticket purchases, memberships and advertisements) to various civil rights organizations and leaders, unions and other organizations. Contains requests for contributions in the form of correspondence (including information about the organizations such as financial need, and brochures), contribution receipts, and invitations and flyers for events. Contains handwritten notes regarding contributions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_30048618e008be1a3ecae3dec7a6d552" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contributions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1967" type="inclusive">1966-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_509b5f4374ba8234c242e575887e4a57" label="unspecified" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_3aa8d6bfc29dd3c8f00041aac11dbe7f" parent="aspace_509b5f4374ba8234c242e575887e4a57" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_343a1b87e5cc4752bfe67c284204d5e7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, telegrams and form letters regarding Local 1199's contributions (via monetary donations, and ticket, calendar, membership, and advertisement purchases) to various civil rights organizations and leaders, unions and other organizations. Contains requests for contributions in the form of correspondence (including information about the organizations such as financial need, agenda/goals, clippings and brochures), contribution receipts, and invitations and flyers for events. Contains handwritten notes regarding contributions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e286bef7ba8258e28050eeaad65e7a56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contributions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_21f419a5b2e40a04b58151dc304db6ee" label="unspecified" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_eb035e345e92883823b4c4a33ee10ae7" parent="aspace_21f419a5b2e40a04b58151dc304db6ee" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60735e70d45836a0ed26b96e2a830322"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and form letters regarding Local 1199's contributions (via monetary donations, and ticket, membership, and advertisement purchases) to various civil rights organizations and leaders, unions and other organizations. Contains requests for contributions in the form of correspondence (including information about the organizations such as financial need, agenda/goals, clippings and brochures), contribution receipts, and invitations and flyers for events. Contains handwritten notes regarding contributions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_390dae6484ef135f69e47403f2aed6fb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contributions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1970" type="inclusive">1968-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d1e06654d7156a1ec7ce52b908b6771" label="unspecified" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_4d31a0695544a816d9e45d645d116bd7" parent="aspace_7d1e06654d7156a1ec7ce52b908b6771" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9d281cb42b8dbc2e7c6e1fedd27f90f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and form letters regarding Local 1199's contributions (via monetary donations, and ticket, membership, and advertisement purchases) to various civil rights organizations and leaders, unions and other organizations. Contains requests for contributions in the form of correspondence (including information about the organizations such as financial need, agenda/goals, clippings and brochures), contribution receipts, and invitations and flyers for events. Contains handwritten notes regarding contributions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_32734347635a70a6bf2c1d163b29670f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contributions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_301cde6694c80fef0f7ed30750f1b6bf" label="unspecified" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_8491aa4b567e5326337a391fb5d0872c" parent="aspace_301cde6694c80fef0f7ed30750f1b6bf" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8263a0d91e4e897c15b419fa594d33a1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence. memos and form letters regarding Local 1199's contributions (via monetary donations, and ticket, membership, and advertisement purchases) to various civil rights organizations and leaders, unions and other organizations. Contains requests for contributions in the form of correspondence (including information about the organizations such as financial need, agenda/goals, clippings and brochures), contribution receipts, and invitations and flyers for events. Contains handwritten notes regarding contributions. Contains a petition from the Black Panther Party.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f50db3abde64a49c4fcfc219fa35fd01" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contributions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a7ad3b89f4e5696e65dfd8a80ca3eb1" label="unspecified" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_08bf2324db87632ba7e0f401e62cb3d9" parent="aspace_0a7ad3b89f4e5696e65dfd8a80ca3eb1" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b6f57d26bcec38abefd6d4dcf3b2e1f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence. memos and form letters regarding Local 1199's contributions (via monetary donations, and ticket, membership, calendar and advertisement purchases and conference attendance) to various civil rights organizations and leaders, unions and other organizations. Contains requests for contributions in the form of correspondence (including information about the organizations such as financial need, agenda/goals, and brochures), contribution receipts, and invitations and flyers for events. Contains handwritten notes regarding contributions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_eab607cf6e3780e01fbb041e49b95469" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence "Crank Letters"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_3aecb2bacd2fc681f6febe7ad97d0778" label="unspecified" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_c5c01c8505d24873f7db1606f08ac422" parent="aspace_3aecb2bacd2fc681f6febe7ad97d0778" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b17665f6cf078824cc408fbbcbff9187"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains letters from Union members and citizens, attacking Local 1199.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_43a49e6e9002a44539fe928f28bf1037" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence "Crank Letters"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_503aa57aa53c20728fb874fbf460dacd" label="unspecified" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_37cff48cb96d24f2434893d892289e9b" parent="aspace_503aa57aa53c20728fb874fbf460dacd" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_27f7e94a4f83ddfca48b3b2072b1f946"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains letters from members to Davis, news clippings, flyers, newsletters and statements denouncing Davis and Local 1199.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_930a27cf417067a950731650b886eb41" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence "Crank Letters"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_70cd3cff36aa2c03abac094b2e5a4e03" label="unspecified" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_ddc7086b26e42e8e3e4d5cba17d25ec3" parent="aspace_70cd3cff36aa2c03abac094b2e5a4e03" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_286d4b628ae3bec552d038b0b490625e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains letters from members, news clippings, flyers, newsletters and statements denouncing Davis and Local 1199.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_eeafd828bde83ac7c5b27a545d22bb8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-L.J. Davis</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca2c57625eed7ab82c327924f491a1ac" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_eecff93dc1114431f8b7e53db8d4ae98" parent="aspace_ca2c57625eed7ab82c327924f491a1ac" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4a2be0cd97b0c39c5d7bb8ffaaaf7129"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and telegrams between Davis and various parties (such as lawyers, Mayor Lindsay, graduate students, Cornell-ILR students, government officials, hospitals, friends, arbitrators and union members). Contains news clippings. Also contains correspondence from Davis via his secretary.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d437901295ede3f4fbb7a7b2c7ee888d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Moe Foner</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ec3c1c6b27b313f4f81810019d87925" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_2f1f873c24f84c822b108a9314a30248" parent="aspace_2ec3c1c6b27b313f4f81810019d87925" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b72c678d02415a77833829ad1e5667d4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence regarding requests for materials by Moe Foner for 1199. Contains correspondence regarding requests for 1199 materials from students, other unions, government officials, etc. Also includes an advertisements and a telegram, as well as references to theater. Contains correspondence in regards to future visits and dealings with people, including an invitation to the Governor of New York to speak with union members. Contains correspondence notifying individuals of the Unions status on a subject.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_12dff1026cb77cb56e3d022ad83bb8db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foreign Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1968" type="inclusive">1965-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb9f54e5e08a63e8a8f0aa91f63cfac4" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_1ae89768dd5bcde680a4cb235f506480" parent="aspace_cb9f54e5e08a63e8a8f0aa91f63cfac4" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_962e998626973c4e930927169aa24f0b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains lists of people in the U.S.S.R and Israel to write letters to. Contains letters to unions, hospitals, government organizations and others in the U.S.S.R thanking them for their hospitality and letters regarding the anniversary of the October Revolution, and the Vietnam War. Contains original and translated correspondence between Davis and Medical Workers Union in Moscow. Contains correspondence with foreigners regarding visits and sending books and other goods. Contains a business card, a memorandum and photos.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_33ee3997efff198f3c60940955cd84d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foreign Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_e266bbebc05fc2dc7165159239c07062" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_ff105a4ff2495c9da40516b2d16bf503" parent="aspace_e266bbebc05fc2dc7165159239c07062" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f05eff1f1639a4af7e015384c8cbcb4f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with people from Japan, Singapore, Hawaii and Poland regarding future visits and past visits. Contains lists of people's addresses in Japan, Singapore and Hawaii.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_be593d4c5083426b48274daa115c741d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foreign Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_0bdb91244fd07a62dac32b70f98f1710" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_451f08a58431b398181b901de3ab8b0e" parent="aspace_0bdb91244fd07a62dac32b70f98f1710" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00225a50651807613e228ed85cb3f7b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with people and telegrams from Israel, Japan and the U.S.S.R concerning future visits, and current events. Also includes the agenda of a group of medical students going to the U.S.S.R. Contains correspondence regarding bringing over nurses from Singapore, including a nursing school's syllabus and news clippings from Singapore.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_41310e49b8f40764fbc30968fae9c042" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foreign Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed16c4a8e506ab4eb7198beabbbebfd1" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_506b2d1ce6b452738a4a3842689fdb73" parent="aspace_ed16c4a8e506ab4eb7198beabbbebfd1" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b25b6cd5b942c4298fcd6321895ed051"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and telegrams between Davis and Medical Workers Union in Moscow regarding Local 1199 member's upcoming visit.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_eef70877feafd84257ef4a1f8bac4730" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1969" type="inclusive">1967-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_f11de723bb56353ec63b6f7a22980c7b" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_466d344a3528ef0a15aa8d09d4e14bf8" parent="aspace_f11de723bb56353ec63b6f7a22980c7b" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9776070f1f7a31fd5e9523c1a38ff301"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with universities, businesses, government officials, hospitals, and unions. Contains invitations, pamphlets, and flyers for events in conjunction with the correspondence. Contains a resolution from the United Public Workers. Contains a biographical sketch of Leon Davis. Contains a photograph of Leon Davis. Contains business cards of individuals who live in Tokyo, a detailed itinerary of Leon Davis' upcoming trip to Tokyo, and correspondence with people from Japan regarding his trip.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_1796206679e5dfb86607370f9162a453" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1960" type="inclusive">1945-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_03a4cae0a69660e993bacae6ff840d71" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_9919ca185d8fa0d378d761f2290c3df5" parent="aspace_03a4cae0a69660e993bacae6ff840d71" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d95481be295aa0a855be96b85e6f099f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the New York Times, lawyers, union members, unions (including District 65), arbitrators, magazines companies, prison inmates, accountants, government officials, hospitals, consultants, universities, non-profit organizations and drug companies. Contains references to Whelan Stores Corporation strike. Contains a telegram.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_97f33f1eb3a9e4720251638311d49384" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1968" type="inclusive">1960-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea17b2969f3ebaf2f8ae381162db6198" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_5037c1d83dcd7ec182a1e127a02249fd" parent="aspace_ea17b2969f3ebaf2f8ae381162db6198" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dba38dfae69a3da1a19d9d9e3b13afb1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the New York Times, lawyers, union members, unions (including District 65), arbitrators, magazines companies, prison inmates, accountants, government officials, hospitals, consultants, universities, non-profit organizations and drug companies. Contains references to Whelan Stores Corporation strike. Contains a telegram.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b0b6d84ba3318664fac513eae7b99e71" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1972" type="inclusive">1969-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_85a0bf1be848435f94762fbf683e0992" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_236d9371f829ed8796fe8414b20f2071" parent="aspace_85a0bf1be848435f94762fbf683e0992" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_791e26b466dc2a60e420d0c86f163849"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with consultants, arbitrators, non-profit organizations, government officials and departments, unions, union members, colleges and universities, drug companies, lawyers, hospitals, newspapers, and artisans. Also contains flyer, student rights handbook, a telegram, newspaper articles, a report from Princeton University, and a letter from Davis to president Nixon.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f0dd0b45436f78c2afbc37b16d7879e0" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff92b879ee2f46164d7487bf3147d6cc" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_58693bfb712bd542589ad9e130895ff0" parent="aspace_ff92b879ee2f46164d7487bf3147d6cc" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8bff775998c6e239c1bd0737bc5e3d67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with arbitrators, non-profit organizations, government officials and departments, unions, union members, colleges and universities, lawyers, newspapers, and banks. Also contains flyer, a telegram, and a letter from Davis to the New York Times.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3f8b1dc101b34b861909af190090c359" level="file"><did><unittitle>Israel Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_93ac6c1ac0f99790f9459ab06c0415f6" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_040e044e38c4e50d29a4c75d60e6de33" parent="aspace_93ac6c1ac0f99790f9459ab06c0415f6" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_93631bfe27bad2710671c87a7adee4de"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with Israeli groups, non-profit organizations, unions and union members, and friends regarding support for Israel during the Israel-Palestine conflict. Contains donation receipts for money given to Israeli support groups. Contains pictures, a biography of a Jewish leader, handwritten notes, a telegram and cablegram, and a collection sheet for union members to donate money for Israel.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_fba8ccf6c94674e9e1bb3c6338c64f50" level="file"><did><unittitle>Israel Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_d93780ae95dc3cbf1fda5aef5a70e654" label="unspecified" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_ecd8e252ab16fbc1f48ff2e1f5809de5" parent="aspace_d93780ae95dc3cbf1fda5aef5a70e654" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb6a21cc10ec4fab90ab3b8ca2a57b94"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with Israeli groups, non-profit organizations, unions and union members, and friends regarding support for Israel during the Israel-Palestine conflict, monetary donations, and visits to Israel and the Soviet Union. Contains donation receipts for money given to Israeli support groups. Contains pictures, postcards, and a brochure.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_0cd5f182f2f902defd25fe9fc157c1ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal Opinions Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1968" type="inclusive">1960-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c1c3fe201c3346cbdd4f7399151e485" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_3982d484c7eda95e0667cc903ea57d36" parent="aspace_1c1c3fe201c3346cbdd4f7399151e485" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b353cda9a5a07019069ca92d49d42e35"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers, unions, union members, and the NLRB regarding new laws, court cases (NLRB case and Civil Court case). Also includes legal documents such as memorandums, legal proceedings, and law journal articles.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_8403690bfba01f02c98d0d5e90d8e963" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal Opinions Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1960" type="inclusive">1948-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2fe93481113eb59202221436afe20b2" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_473a7578d50c70dcdfd3e1823ba041de" parent="aspace_e2fe93481113eb59202221436afe20b2" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2133ac0174be81124b5aa0a9c0dbefc4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers, unions, union members, and the NLRB regarding new laws, court cases (NLRB case and Civil Court case). Also includes legal documents such as memorandums, legal proceedings, and law journal articles.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_40885d304c9dad3e4aa0ae655b1f9bc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Membership Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1956" type="inclusive">1947-1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_390fd36e2453b61dbd9b22836a106b0b" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_5ce8bcfbda01d30c1944cbabfff90d6e" parent="aspace_390fd36e2453b61dbd9b22836a106b0b" type="folder">1a</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2d678b94474579b84cf03dea048e034b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also lawyers, government officials, and newspapers and magazines regarding union issues such as unemployment insurance, complaints against fellow union members, reinstatement, union meetings, contract provisions, strikes (Liggett), elections, anti-Semitism, union member conflicts, pensions, theft, communism, and back pay. Contains press releases written by president Davis.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3d229c8b997192e47c3b4ace58419d11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Membership Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_01b32a10d194a963b4918127582f454c" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_f9f579955a295e7376ef042a3713431f" parent="aspace_01b32a10d194a963b4918127582f454c" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6539b44b7f1faed6d0b129a238fb5027"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also lawyers, government officials, and newspapers and magazines regarding union member issues such as employment, complaints against fellow union members, pensions, contract negotiations and terms, benefits, credit union, 1199 News, member deaths, dues, membership cards, resumes, resignations, and member recommendations.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c048866c04180684759772d3554528a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Membership Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_df3315ca63de315b42777ccd751de820" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_b4b58d69805d3e82b701da9eb6fa1c7c" parent="aspace_df3315ca63de315b42777ccd751de820" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e896c85e5b4affa4e08ff19737524d8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with union members regarding complaints and conflicts, organizing, union constitution, employment, benefits, initiation fee, vacation, pension, salaries, and dues.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_73f9811cd1ffa4cef3a17f27bb2d76e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Membership Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1970" type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_65d18184ef15c21f05ba0afb4f60fdf8" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_a81071f84487f641d0c16f99e7727c37" parent="aspace_65d18184ef15c21f05ba0afb4f60fdf8" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9c05ac4084c8085dc3be7de4247d39c9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also other unions, government officials, hospitals and universities regarding union member issues such as employment, complaints and criticisms, elections, union constitution, thanks, death of members, human rights, membership, contract provisions, strikes, elections, pensions, scholarships and recommendations. Contains press releases written by president Davis. Contains telegrams and flyers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_31dea651d47453105af43058817e1dd2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Membership Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b4f82d939e33762f6d19dbcb4f71e94" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_68f44b02f51bd949a41a180591195da5" parent="aspace_1b4f82d939e33762f6d19dbcb4f71e94" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e528ba8133f2b3e4aa5e157a54815e5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also lawyers, the district attorney, and the NYS Human Rights division regarding union member issues such as police, employment, complaints against fellow union members, scholarships, classification, laws, politics, pensions, contract negotiations and terms, benefits, credit union, 1199 News, anti-Semitism, conduct, member deaths, dues, membership cards, organizing, AFL-CIO, resignations, and member recommendations. Contains flyers, photos, memorandum, conciliation agreement, poem, and telegram from Davis to a member's mother.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b6fce4dafe867007ad9ce0963b745099" level="file"><did><unittitle>Membership Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_465ed316bf4b489f193e58b7efd2cc8c" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_88428d1518a64f8d002c737b4222de84" parent="aspace_465ed316bf4b489f193e58b7efd2cc8c" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_856945f6e2d8a399816da0e828747f09"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with primarily union members but also the government officials (the mayor) regarding union member complaints, benefits, salary, membership cards, thanks, 1199 News, Credit Unions, illnesses, the Brotherhood Fund, contract negotiations, training, and politics (Jimmy Hoffa).</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_4f4ab5a68dd3c5dfa1a9aba39a765d1a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1966" type="inclusive">1963-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5117a7ec1897d3bdb95e5d8c525ce30" label="unspecified" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_1a5f45cfd3d530841c472e621b7081e1" parent="aspace_f5117a7ec1897d3bdb95e5d8c525ce30" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67f6aee637ca20f66e4423337244c2e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with colleges and universities, lawyers, hospitals, government officials, unions, and non-profit organizations inviting Davis to attend conferences, dinners, banquets, etc., asking him to speak at events, and thanking him for speaking or attending. Contains telegram from Governor Rockefeller inviting Davis to dinner. Contains draft of a speech, brochures, invitations, memorandums, flyers, and hand written notes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_acabadb2d7d795abd078b4a508b84ba5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-New Jersey</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_60c06f46f040c2488b02c70278ef5de9" label="unspecified" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_8f3e4fec2e26e22035ccc5419be0819a" parent="aspace_60c06f46f040c2488b02c70278ef5de9" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b1fe1904972564f42a323e1ad70c2f8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with various New Jersey Labor Organizations in regards to events and support. Contains invitations and donation receipts.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d1e4683dae86e0920c42e115e37c5f1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-NYC Central Labor Council</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_09b978ecd5a3e17708986092e340681b" label="unspecified" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_2560ea371cca541a281c951dd81366bd" parent="aspace_09b978ecd5a3e17708986092e340681b" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_640b42703b020db0dad461c252948494"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains telegrams, form letters and correspondence with NYC Central Labor Council regarding meetings, elections, current events, rallies, strikes, resolutions, civil rights, committees, and conflicts with 1199.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_efe1a03df2d6cca7bdafb802ad745170" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Organizations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1966" type="inclusive">1963-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc7181ceb602dbfd607f7a5b660948b0" label="unspecified" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_f88c6cf30c415cda117c2c2fbfce3120" parent="aspace_bc7181ceb602dbfd607f7a5b660948b0" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6d92c7784c34450b9478560900e3f77e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains telegrams, handwritten notes, flyers, brochures, memorandums, form letters, bulletins, receipts, and correspondence from many organizations including the NAACP, Jewish Labor Committee, colleges and universities, lawyers, American's for Democratic Action, League of Women Voters, and many more. The majority of the communication is in regards to current events, meeting and dinner invitations, honorary memberships, donations, and conferences. Contains a telegram from Davis to President Lyndon B. Johnson regarding the protection of Martin Luther King Junior.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_31e7b83709d3e801074f3f6c9825dec6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Organizations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1969" type="inclusive">1967-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_8688dafd77c03566b8dd194e0b257127" label="unspecified" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_a902e8a1ca8081896762be7b3ecc10d4" parent="aspace_8688dafd77c03566b8dd194e0b257127" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8f72b92191c98d60a71b161770987e83"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains form letters from New School, American Committee for Democracy and Freedom In Greece, United Federation of Teachers, and the Rank and File Committee regarding current events, and financial contributions. Contains correspondence via letters and telegrams with the Japan Council against Atomic and Hydrogen Bombs, and GHI regarding invitations to a Conference and a Forum. Contains announcement from League of Women Voters. Contains project proposal from the Black and Puerto Rican Student Community of City College. Contains telegrams from Davis to Mayor Lindsay and Board of Education regarding President of United Federation of Teachers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_1b602bbb1ae905d93a7b079f929c8f4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Organizations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_597a78215c596745d45c8295031320b2" label="unspecified" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_01d97e332b3dc1c8fdf98905d0485d97" parent="aspace_597a78215c596745d45c8295031320b2" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_327ce86808acabda865c571db8c4b4a0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with IUE and other unions in regards to the Strike with General Electric and the Local 1707 Strike. Contains correspondence with other unions and local groups in regards to conference invitations and monetary donations. Contains correspondence with various unions asking for copies of their constitutions. Contains CLASC News, 420 News Bulletin, A. Phillip Randolph pamphlet, a copy of the Local 144 Settlement, and "The Disaffiliation of the UAW" pamphlet.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c7fb51a998ede9d3e342859ea4d8c89e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Organizations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_e00c54ac2164df1980fb1805db36eca6" label="unspecified" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_33b6c2ed2d6f7527036a56dfdb19a98d" parent="aspace_e00c54ac2164df1980fb1805db36eca6" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35327d99f9780b6ad430b8aa9bbbb75d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and form letters from various political groups, civil rights groups, unions, health organizations, government organizations, and colleges and universities regarding conferences, monetary support, requests for information, the employment of ex-inmates, forming a new college, rallies, the Young Lords, Black Solidarity and the Vietnam War.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_849326a1217f90dc6dc180d9bafe9718" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Organizations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_dbcb2ce7fb93d62703b2f6d1f72d69c6" label="unspecified" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_b507abbd7498124022c6f07676501f99" parent="aspace_dbcb2ce7fb93d62703b2f6d1f72d69c6" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c1445248ef2cd229e54670faa163cd80"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence and flyers regarding conferences, Local 1199 as a Harvard Business Review case study, monetary support of a Child Development Center, and a pharmaceutical program.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_aa2b819e49feb9b3af4e64fc8b4958f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Sidney Von Luther</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_f59402a074be4a1127c70bb96351bf3d" label="unspecified" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_1746970e162a19cec9f4db1164189223" parent="aspace_f59402a074be4a1127c70bb96351bf3d" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a90a8e491db8df6b66a6d8fa0e2ddffa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis and Von Luther, news paper articles and press releases, and Local 1199 Executive Council meeting minutes regarding the election of Sidney Von Luther as Senator, his consequent leave of absence from 1199, and his eventual permanent leave and severance pay from 1199.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_5e5efffe82aa2e7b463a9ebb5dc97f92" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Unions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_6cbfeab5067214255c758c828a78464a" label="unspecified" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_51e404bf2ea55caf7d2fcaa7c6770034" parent="aspace_6cbfeab5067214255c758c828a78464a" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b17e12dbba341560300e825b8682118"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with unions, non-profit organizations, the National Labor Relations Board, the Mayor, and the State of New York regarding employment, employment conditions, training, strikes (grape growers and teachers), requests for information, monetary contributions, dinner and funeral invitations, laws and bills, elections, conventions, rallies, and advertisements. Also includes telegrams, invitations, a news clipping, flyers and handwritten notes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d8e22e01658173429908fa6967cc3e07" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Unions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_7625440df097708caa55424fc23b00e6" label="unspecified" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_6d35b4d689adf8e2a6604df64709fba1" parent="aspace_7625440df097708caa55424fc23b00e6" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_216eb32fff32d365b11a2bf65014e0f8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with unions, students, the mayor, James Hoffa, and non-profit organizations regarding invitations, organizing workers, strikes, congratulations, collective bargaining contracts, thanks, working conditions, elections, monetary donations, advice, and injunctions. Contains newsletters, handwritten notes, a news clipping, telegrams, a pamphlet, a leaflet, a statement, a sample membership survey (ILWU), and a policy statement on the jailing of James Hoffa.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ca2479987d17328bebf2b1c6f16c3cd1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Unions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1971" type="inclusive">1963-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac8d5aa1193fedf9e49b4f7a8ad735be" label="unspecified" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_8c33af90a443da85c82b5af9a2bfb01f" parent="aspace_ac8d5aa1193fedf9e49b4f7a8ad735be" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70c0b639f468cbb9b1346af8922d802b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with unions, universities, government organizations, non-profit organizations, lawyers, and the NLRB regarding requests for information, thanks, sympathy, conferences, strikes, invitations, federal employees, advice, conventions, collective bargaining, monetary contributions, Local 144, advertisements, Vietnam War, education policy, and loans. Contains AFL-CIO proceedings, telegram from Davis to president Nixon, pamphlet, memorandums, statements, news clippings, form letters, press release, speech, pension information, court invitation, and a legal service plan.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3030e84e44f9c0892fc4a33944668c4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence-Unions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_f04d1111421b6b94bf61a95ff51f7a2d" label="unspecified" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_3fd2cc6c6b31a746e436cbac212f8ac2" parent="aspace_f04d1111421b6b94bf61a95ff51f7a2d" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d61315194a7f9ea9b496bfee44ab3f7e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers, unions, government organizations and non-profit organizations regarding boycotts, thanks, negotiations, the pay board, Local 77, and 1199 News. Contains an agreement between Local 144 and Local 1199, UAW financial reports, handwritten notes, news clippings, SEIU resolutions, SEIU amendments to the constitution, and SEIU officer reports.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ad02924c85e8c499b775237dbcba80fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Credit Union</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1968" type="inclusive">1964-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ef5e3ffed67fc21860fe2da26f3d059" label="unspecified" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_943975654f190b18570600ebd798fcd6" parent="aspace_6ef5e3ffed67fc21860fe2da26f3d059" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_26b7215b39912b59b8d02bd9f5937aac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains information about Local 1199's credit union including monthly credit union statements, annual reports, and treasurer reports.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3b57634451aa4613a5c6fd8f1efbbfe8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Lectures, Seminars, Articles, etc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1963" type="inclusive">1959-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_2484e4e8b618e3a1d4d4f26e2556372a" label="unspecified" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_74395b479914c5877ac200c33be1399a" parent="aspace_2484e4e8b618e3a1d4d4f26e2556372a" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9f865ecfee97e3cf0cd63c455b4a352e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains Davis' correspondence of a personal nature with hospitals, lawyers, accountants, and friends regarding travel, thanks, taxes, his father's health, and his daughter's employment during college. Contains letters from union members wishing him a speedy recovery from the hospital, as well as a letter from Davis in the hospital to a friend Max Steinbeck. Contains correspondence with unions, union members, non-profit organizations, colleges and universities, and lawyers regarding monetary donations, workman's compensation, meeting requests, invitations to speak at events, honors received by Davis, 1199 News, requests for information, and research studies. Contains transcript of Davis on a CBS television show. Contains reports, speeches, handwritten notes, and a biography of Davis from a calendar.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9df83f4cddfcc3ea827fc76011c5a3f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Memorandums</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1969" type="inclusive">1966-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f24941f2efa3c59c3259dcbddb8014c" label="unspecified" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_9afc28cbfdcccc0c35c94de73144e14c" parent="aspace_7f24941f2efa3c59c3259dcbddb8014c" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2fb50e3730f416e797bcee25ac204e1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums from Davis to union members, secretaries, organizers, executive council members and staff regarding meetings, member attendance, strikes, picketing and union policies and issues. Contains a copy of the 1199 Benefits Plan brochure, a meeting flyer, financial statements and car rental forms.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_254e4cfa08bc059ad3c39da591e7b060" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Memorandums</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_76ddba35b93a06bb96e4b7fb378cca9a" label="unspecified" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_9a8e85c859eb3f019e430e4d3e314630" parent="aspace_76ddba35b93a06bb96e4b7fb378cca9a" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc411c8b37385ba522123afe9f8c55a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums from Davis to union members, secretaries, organizers, executive council members and staff regarding meetings, member attendance, strikes, picketing, boycotts and union policies and issues. Contains a meeting agenda and form letters about meetings.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_cfd5b17e5a2d6fcf74aacb97cf0f031e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Memorandums</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_957129db0137d4baedc658f0cc345bbd" label="unspecified" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_11747e551c3c08b117004fd80c6a21fb" parent="aspace_957129db0137d4baedc658f0cc345bbd" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b99a44d207f76b5f2cc7696a9ebe621"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums from Davis to union members, secretaries, organizers, executive council members and staff regarding meetings and events, notifications, training classes, elections, member attendance, strikes, picketing, boycotts and union policies and issues. Contains a copy of a letter, a hiring request form, a contribution form, a petition, news clippings, and a copy of a publication--" The Modern Hospital."</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7fa1213865bc1b96e977642639d481ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Personal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1951" type="inclusive">1943-1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_d952d404d62a0a16f0952589ccecbf9c" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_5ba08b83f42d4441bebf1322f0b15b04" parent="aspace_d952d404d62a0a16f0952589ccecbf9c" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60cc768e18e91df696d0e010211a4dbc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with Bill Anderson, an 1199 officer who is stationed in the Pacific during WWII. Contains correspondence with companies, union members, friends, banks, and government departments regarding personal matters such as mortgage payments, the Taft-Hartley Act, a book club, stolen items, a bounced check, a broken pen, magazine subscriptions, advice, home insurance, and buying a new car. Contains a post card, a greeting card, a court summons, a picture, and a resolution.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_4c6f6059567bb798ddcd153981d008de" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Personal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1968" type="inclusive">1964-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_e007424a17d7aa4b7187eba3380bb3fc" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_679b0cd9b16a37a072e769f037b92fcf" parent="aspace_e007424a17d7aa4b7187eba3380bb3fc" type="folder">1a</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60ab8a516692823cce4508e0c4e555d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with government organizations, companies, accountants, lawyers, artists, friends, college professors, etc. regarding personal matters such as stolen credit cards, driver's license renewal, pictures, a pet, daughter's wedding, buying a brownstone home, and awards among other things. Contains individual income tax reports for Davis' daughter and himself and his wife, workers' compensation forms, a telegram, greeting cards, a letter to the New York Times, and a biographical sketch of Davis.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_885e04dcdac23a97d36bd49f1306333d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Personal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_3255f571415edbb5a154d3fb67afeae5" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_4de0ea5ce3c9c035aeb4b2d635a58ba6" parent="aspace_3255f571415edbb5a154d3fb67afeae5" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_53672f15e2d4962a7df610a02d666e4f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with hospitals, friends, union members, a man he got into an accident with, artisans, banks, oil companies, the American Embassy in China, and the Peking Violations Bureau regarding personal matters such as a car accident, a parking violation, guest from Sweden, a mug, bills, credit cards, visit to China, and an invitation. Contains an accident report, and a biographical sketch of Davis.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7f38e77589da75563c353076c7b26cd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Personal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_d18c52ff4cfd86c58f4ecc03b88cdb5d" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_b062d90e198981c873e079d560c56630" parent="aspace_d18c52ff4cfd86c58f4ecc03b88cdb5d" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5f2f8aca4cbc628722bc66fd8786bb62"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the Department of Consumer Affairs, union members, a hotel, and family of union members regarding personal matter such as a memorial service, a credit card bill, complaints, and directions to a party. Contains auto mobile accident reports, a jewelry receipt, a subpoena, and an insurance form.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_410f7762428c7dc3364810d89b22e10c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Personal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_93c842f9ee154c9450bd2e38dcff49f6" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_ed4d960acea452132193636a2bcb39c2" parent="aspace_93c842f9ee154c9450bd2e38dcff49f6" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c569eaf0115bfa7c1460042819ba5696"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with senators, congressmen, lawyers, the house of representatives, the New York Post, and community organizations regarding the deportation of Stoyan Pavesic. Contains handwritten notes, a telegram, and a news clipping about Stoyan Pavesic.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e77a37c0d0ac6233f55b23c4eca77787" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1949" type="inclusive">1947-1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed36ce51d09d2c461ef21a1e43e32f34" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_1dedfa97fd110c77ab9abbaa17000bd1" parent="aspace_ed36ce51d09d2c461ef21a1e43e32f34" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c27933595a60de293e626e86390644aa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a report to membership on current union issues (Taft-Hartley Act and Liggett and Whelan strikes), a report on Local 1199 discussing the history, purpose and structure of the union, a speech for the Store Chairman's' Dinner talking about organizing 1199, and a report to the Executive Board regarding current union issues.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_5b577beee959ebf08e75b7c5b073107b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ef5ba49492c501dbfc49d90fa6e45be" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_61e07b7735bb3b5f6412dd825da18f13" parent="aspace_7ef5ba49492c501dbfc49d90fa6e45be" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a403600ca4c3293a31e20cf92b55205"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a report on DPOW National Executive Board discussing the creation of the DPO, a report to 1199 Drug News regarding the content of the newsletter, a report on the reorganization of the divisions of 1199, a report to Convention of Distributive Workers Union regarding challenges of the union, an introductory report on "the state of the union" regarding the struggles of 1199, a report to Liggett and Whelan Steward Conference regarding the purpose of unions, and a report commenting on Negro History Week regarding race relations in the U.S.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a737fb240388fb4560cc3f5e3c36549e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1953" type="inclusive">1951-1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_199f1b846108dc10bea5cffab2dec6a3" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_480b519ea6af9a1bbb3b5b87107d5d9f" parent="aspace_199f1b846108dc10bea5cffab2dec6a3" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a759f548daf932f6d12670ec6addb191"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains reports on "the state of the union" regarding past and current 1199 activities, a speech for the National Pharmaceutical Convention regarding the current situation for workers in the pharmaceutical industry, a report to the DPO Convention current 1199 activities, a report on the Organizational Drive for 40-5 discussing the prospects of a forty hour five days a week work schedule, and a report to Officers' Meeting DPO.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c3989eefb80d01acf33df29a73ac8b5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Seminars</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1969" type="inclusive">1966-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_f64a7eee9ad10d1aeaa68bfd100c6aea" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_439376925e8e8280df7c394d36f579bd" parent="aspace_f64a7eee9ad10d1aeaa68bfd100c6aea" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_80502d16e193071854bfd65eb82b898d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a pamphlet of the American Assembly-Columbia University's Report on Black Economic Development. Contains correspondence with Columbia University regarding Davis' appointment as Associate in the University Seminar on Labor. Contains correspondence with individuals regarding the seminar and contains a participants guide to the seminar. Also contains a participants' book entitled "Challenges to Collective Bargaining."</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_75a0eaa339b5f7b9dd36d734d458a465" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Speech</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_f71b872ae06ce7390662865cd1620fe0" label="unspecified" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_6f55172264288f1ae5ba7768a465b44f" parent="aspace_f71b872ae06ce7390662865cd1620fe0" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_03521c584ba6ff729c911d156ba5ecfe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains an outline of a statement, and the actual statement written by Davis and presented to the Permanent Administrative Committee regarding union policies.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2b0adbaf2d0ac2be0ee3814aa49aecb4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Sponsorships, Seminars, Invitations, Study Groups, etc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1970" type="inclusive">1960-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f05e15f54584bf422be5f5e17279be4" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_5444a10aded85f6c9dfa181b150e9fa1" parent="aspace_5f05e15f54584bf422be5f5e17279be4" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7272652d9eef3b241c631f71dcc3a96b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with publications, unions, religious groups, non-profits organizations, civil right groups, government departments, lawyers, hospitals and colleges and universities regarding invitations to events or conferences, invitations to speak at events or to be a guest lecturer or panelist, receiving awards, invitations for membership, and requests for interviews. Also contains a brochure, Davis' tax filings, a transcript of one of his speeches, a flyer, a formal invitation, and telegrams.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_198d8f70548d324be350f98971fbb995" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Sponsorships, Seminars, Invitations, Study Groups, etc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1971" type="inclusive">1968-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_32b27f1514f3718225615b48c8385f7c" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_08aecaed5068f1d402107bdf78b21540" parent="aspace_32b27f1514f3718225615b48c8385f7c" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dbcc0824c8c6466430cb312c8c6a2d9b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with publications, unions, religious groups, non-profits organizations, civil right groups, government departments, the house of representatives, a radio station and television station, lawyers, hospitals, colleges and universities, A. Philip Randolph, and Ted Kheel regarding invitations to events and conferences, invitations to speak at events or to be a guest lecturer or panelist, receiving awards, invitations for membership, elections and requests for interviews. Also contains a copy of an article written by Davis, form letters, an event program, a transcript of a Davis' televised debate, and proposal for a new college from CUNY.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a632a14c078ea578f678fcc7e1302f29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-Sponsorships, Seminars, Invitations, Study Groups, etc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_266cbe1c44a7f3691ec9dd118be1d777" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_425bbce7373f022eed89450c595957b3" parent="aspace_266cbe1c44a7f3691ec9dd118be1d777" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f30d62b8efd9c79979035095506bed1d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with unions, non-profits organizations, civil right groups, government officials, lawyers, hospitals, colleges and universities, regarding invitations to events and conferences, invitations to speak at events or to be a guest lecturer or panelist and requests for interviews. Also contains a newspaper article and an outline for a book on labor.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_17e3fadf5dfca07153ef002df7b73c0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-State of the Union Message</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a078b6c1cc888c4f641fd0f38e9347e" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_ba50963c3de1b89d5e44db342edfa295" parent="aspace_8a078b6c1cc888c4f641fd0f38e9347e" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c4c4a98d9b5021e6ea4793c7ae5bb5fd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a copy of Davis' State of the Union Message entitled "Where is 1199 now?" Also contains a summary of the State of the Union Message.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d3865c62fc3eb822518dde72f4cff469" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis-State of the Union Report</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_edb9c706c6f72779af728cf4654f7c39" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_32dc2abe50dc62d697b1b2042a248f60" parent="aspace_edb9c706c6f72779af728cf4654f7c39" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_913b3be7c86509d84a1c5010caf9469e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a copy of the Summary of President Davis' State of the Union Message, "Where is 1199 now?"</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_39b7aead879e4ead6284378099746d95" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis- Statement to Congressional Committee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_68108697db1ff5bf49d41e448f265531" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_3d0a0c503269fe58557515f4d2478284" parent="aspace_68108697db1ff5bf49d41e448f265531" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0fa5bd66bb0a0b6aa83042b978cf1235"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a copy of a statement submitted by Davis to the Congressional Committee regarding working conditions in voluntary hospitals.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9e0481b18fbaef2d4579ed578b062027" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leon J. Davis Testimonial Dinner</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_00eb3d92e5f60848a6ff9861fb9e5c8b" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_746d438efdce9d3727381097e06b4819" parent="aspace_00eb3d92e5f60848a6ff9861fb9e5c8b" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cab6177ec89fd562accd454a3803e0e1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums, remarks by Davis at the testimonial dinner, a copy of the actual dinner invitation, lists of reservations, seating lists, remarks by William Michelson at the testimonial dinner, correspondence with people invited to the dinner and with the organizers of the dinner, the financial report for the dinner, ticket forms, list of contributors, telegrams, ledger of dinner donations and tickets sold, a dinner tally, and a brochure.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_4df2a4d94a7d8f6b634bdec98f055fd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Drug Industry Petitions to Wage Board</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_dff80c20d6af54622728d9b6669b7b55" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_bfa902bc4700e15f972d79de5adc44e6" parent="aspace_dff80c20d6af54622728d9b6669b7b55" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_80a8372121b669fefd0733a16f4f2153"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with various drug and pharmaceutical companies informing them that 1199 is going on strike. Contains correspondence with lawyers. Contains correspondence between the Pay Board and the drug and pharmaceutical companies.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ad14e0b53e8e74751c04bad0253a6ccb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Drug and Hospital News</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_0955545865112c806b21458b1c56c896" label="unspecified" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_4f4ffe2e2a6b2038d45f89fb9c63ad8e" parent="aspace_0955545865112c806b21458b1c56c896" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ef0251a86385916f4815362262547766"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains typed up copies of articles from the 1199 Drug and Hospital News.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e39ec1deda364f0940f85d4cb7910d0a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Election Board [folder 1 of 3]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_c65985adfa46f8d50b575d6c718fcf7d" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_3e2da970a545528d238871aecde1067a" parent="aspace_c65985adfa46f8d50b575d6c718fcf7d" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_19ca89cf9b8786df4dbd69800fc04f96"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence regarding opening a post office box for the election board. Contains an election summary, 1199 election guide with pictures of candidates, a memo from the committee on political education, copy of election issue of 1199 Drug and Hospital News, election schedule, election ballot, election flyer, oath for new 1199 officers, election board meeting minutes, and an election board report.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d920001f4ea6ad717cacf2b763d915bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Election Board [folder 2 of 3]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_b0f919b0aae35f53f7e53fb62d760385" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_ab89e07d45eee4738353675f861ca8cc" parent="aspace_b0f919b0aae35f53f7e53fb62d760385" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4acc5ef2b48ea99978569f0536433624"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains an election board report, election board meeting minutes, election ballots, a brochure for election consultants, list of voting locations, election schedule, election summary, a from letter with election details, memo to all area directors from election board containing election instructions, voting machine directions, voting machine locations, 1199 election guide with pictures of candidates, copy of election issue of 1199 Drug and Hospital News, election flyers, election facts sheet, list of election materials needed, nominating petitions, reimbursement forms for lost wages during election voting, monthly wage report, and first election board meeting agenda.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d8d426d3dd9ba504d9e4a65f510013f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Election Board [folder 3 of 3]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2d9293bc47c1e3f299b1d0c074ae883" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_176d4dc7bf38cb93b61c6abbfd94cf58" parent="aspace_f2d9293bc47c1e3f299b1d0c074ae883" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d8bfd43fded4848fd5af0d8bf1cf3748"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains nominating petitions, local 1199 delegates election reports, list of election deputies, delegate voting schedules and petitions, election summaries, election tally sheets, election ballots, 1199 election guide, official delegate nominating petition, election flyers and signs, memorandums, election fact sheets, secret ballots, voting machine directions, materials needed for election, election board members, and an attendance list.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_153052c28762ace6d194013f84568243" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elections</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1972" type="inclusive">1952-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_76d81f9b90ef31d46e1f4a9931c07760" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_74ec44805a0ada22c99d9262350f0c70" parent="aspace_76d81f9b90ef31d46e1f4a9931c07760" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_414ccd0797173ae06c80362045d5df86"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains election board report, membership composition report, form letter sent to members reminding them to vote, sample ballot, election board meeting minutes, correspondence between Davis and the election board, voting advertisements, a notice to vote, election summary, election campaign statistics, 1972 elected delegates, correspondence with various community leaders regarding elections, and reports to delegates assemblies.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_52398323eb8183c7dd28bae27aaee17d" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Benefit Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1960" type="inclusive">1953-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_6fcd9f6fb003c102ee66cba0d81cf82c" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_56091f75579a23071dd41ea9a34bd9bc" parent="aspace_6fcd9f6fb003c102ee66cba0d81cf82c" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fabe9e17c4e6242c8bc123012424e16d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains local 1199 benefit plan brochure, local 1199 benefit plan annual claim experience report, local 1199 benefit plan financial report, a memorandum regarding benefits, 1199 benefit plan resolution, local 1199 benefit plan statement of financial condition, local 1199 benefit plan meeting minutes, local 1199 benefit plan pension fund administrative budget, benefit plan director's annual report, and local 1199 benefit plan rules and regulations.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b15afe1eeb144c5ffea8567b67ab23c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Benefit Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1965" type="inclusive">1960-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff3344a6eacb35cca8b1814999015d59" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_b76469f3a21f784cc35e5c19af82539f" parent="aspace_ff3344a6eacb35cca8b1814999015d59" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_32459640cfe70762785d5a83d6275237"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains local 1199 benefit plan brochure, local 1199 benefit plan annual claim experience report, local 1199 benefit plan financial report, a memorandum regarding benefits, 1199 benefit plan resolution, local 1199 benefit plan statement of financial condition, local 1199 benefit plan meeting minutes, local 1199 benefit plan pension fund administrative budget, benefit plan director's annual report, and local 1199 benefit plan rules and regulations.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_79d250c482cf4f4e6c757db6ee62f6f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Benefit Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_8463cd780ce0b2cb385c24524c4a2c8d" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_ac25570e49abfa7b886a31e1d0efb88a" parent="aspace_8463cd780ce0b2cb385c24524c4a2c8d" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b149492bd31ee30bf6279459631f05b8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains local 1199 benefit plan brochure, benefit plan director's annual report, local 1199 benefit plan meeting minutes, letter from accountants to benefit plan, local 1199 benefit plan statement of financial condition, and local 1199 benefit plan report of the Amalgamated Bank of New York.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b756d89f1056a7232cb4b1097fb69129" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Benefit Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1972" type="inclusive">1966-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_298ab06a138dcc1773cb06a106341ca9" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_cac905eba94975c69904d0e84e2cbdfe" parent="aspace_298ab06a138dcc1773cb06a106341ca9" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f6a75a99db383eeaa3a333257cad7a8c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contain dental program and prescription program brochure, the local 1199 benefit plan brochure, an agreement and declaration of trust, local 1199 benefit plan report of the Amalgamated Bank of New York, local 1199 benefit plan meeting minutes, local 1199 benefit plan rules and regulations amendment, hospital listing for claims department, the local 1199 benefit plan, local 1199 benefit plan financial report, schedule of benefit plan members, and schedule of telephone charges. Also contains correspondence with lawyers and others regarding meetings, and alterations to the benefit plan.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d247c766aeeb054c365b02e3b1d00bd6" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Benefit Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1975" type="inclusive">1973-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_e30ecc83ac487dde886b0f9946c40427" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_8dee46b4a70c4b9414e505c31ef31cb8" parent="aspace_e30ecc83ac487dde886b0f9946c40427" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b966682128464289c7b64bbafe5ea4f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contain dental program and prescription program brochure, the local 1199 benefit plan brochure, an agreement and declaration of trust, local 1199 benefit plan report of the Amalgamated Bank of New York, local 1199 benefit plan meeting minutes, local 1199 benefit plan rules and regulations amendment, hospital listing for claims department, the local 1199 benefit plan, local 1199 benefit plan financial report, schedule of benefit plan members, and schedule of telephone charges. Also contains correspondence with lawyers and others regarding meetings, and alterations to the benefit plan.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_39cb354c0eaab39f359f6ae0d2aa9465" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Benefit Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_ba475c6884a6dc34e3c04d567dcd9317" label="unspecified" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_811d9fd28ec1de111b85eb3253913cf7" parent="aspace_ba475c6884a6dc34e3c04d567dcd9317" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6defb67d3bde292e87224c9a48db3482"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains local 1199 benefit plan financial report.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a892e453fc5183b25da12e3e648d4bfd" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Credit Union</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5a98fb71bcfaf2878c6fed48c5e9c39" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_e248eeef7df5648aa7e3d5b92b488cd0" parent="aspace_a5a98fb71bcfaf2878c6fed48c5e9c39" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6c9a3b13d29b6d3e033d0b9f8ef0b18d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a report on the credit union.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_6302790cc8c4a22fa7198b4172e1c406" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 News</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_310aff3f1e7bab4ffc4bc201007a8cd2" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_5d90a001013557478aa21f52bc6f53ef" parent="aspace_310aff3f1e7bab4ffc4bc201007a8cd2" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60b055d51dcd4d6ee56af56473613e60"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains several rough drafts of articles for the 1199 News.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_fbcbceff586589dacc2dbcd82b5c91d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Pension Fund</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_a085a8a86c952608944aee9537d295a5" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_3aa57413298d851a1364a1079a9d313a" parent="aspace_a085a8a86c952608944aee9537d295a5" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a0095a364243bccc8e247a1d8a0af243"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains local 1199 pension fund financial report, local 1199 pension fund meeting minutes, and local 1199 pension fund pension plan study.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_096db47397967cfa3d8aacad7d629949" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Pension Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b69e5221c7f48da5139f8e64562c0a9" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_0311818ca4d98624958de08a3e516a37" parent="aspace_8b69e5221c7f48da5139f8e64562c0a9" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d778fe127402551a91a1fc83a475f0ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memo regarding local 1199 pension fund trustees, secretary-treasurer's annual report, trustees of local 1199 pension fund investment account, local 1199 pension fund financial report, local 1199 pension fund meeting minutes, State of New York Insurance Department report on examination of local 1199 Pension Fund, local 1199 pension fund annual report, and local 1199 pension fund statement of financial condition.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d884dea8978756af2760c191ba53e633" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Pension Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1975" type="inclusive">1965-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b3b90e552f524752627c72b31b79a41" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_06dec957dcc10de116299af4752ea0e6" parent="aspace_7b3b90e552f524752627c72b31b79a41" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c66224463debe64cd69cd8b226057f87"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains local 1199 pension fund outline of principal provisions, local 1199 pension fund meeting minutes, trustees of local 1199 pension fund investment account, local 1199 pension fund financial report, local 1199 pension plan brochure, secretary-treasurer's annual report, a letter and financial records from accountants, and local 1199 pension fund statement of financial condition.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_576c04aa3307a7dace9cc80c7ded91dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Pension Fund</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1966" type="inclusive">1951-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_2666aa6cb29951089b60e154f1b5d70f" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_66551dcce3d24954773777f329250654" parent="aspace_2666aa6cb29951089b60e154f1b5d70f" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9bd64b007abcd877f9ee0d2626482e27"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains local 1199 pension plan brochure, report on pension activity, trustees of local 1199 pension fund investment accounts, local 1199 pension fund trustees meeting agenda, secretary-treasurer's annual reports, local 1199 pension fund meeting minutes, local 1199 pension fund statement of financial condition, and article about the pension that was in the 1199 News. Also contains correspondence regarding pension fund trustees meeting and the appointment of new trustees.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_44b5b2852ddf2b7e2d6856eaf2b096c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Staff</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_250dad8283c5542ebd56e672ac60c53f" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_6731460eec7473a264797203c4bbc592" parent="aspace_250dad8283c5542ebd56e672ac60c53f" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8418423a59e2149e4b7e25f176a0c5b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a resignation memo, an employee grievance case, and guild division staff assignments.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ea4ece2dc8e98dc97b1a481dca5115b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Training Programs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4b49e90255e7ce9796167d5890ef5bf" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_307ebf50dac9bdcd86436e0c90813cc5" parent="aspace_a4b49e90255e7ce9796167d5890ef5bf" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_298f689771dd2aa9fa46d86153a47fd6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains local 1199 tentative proposal for training, local 1199 training possibilities, correspondence regarding Health Service Mobility Study, existing training, the future training program, correspondence regarding hiring a training person, training program proposal, and a copy of GHI health issues newsletter.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ff0853c720a9c561a8525f9c126ded43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Endorsements</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4f423ac4acc783a4638622d087565ab" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_327a4b7f13087469dce55ef1a83fc0e0" parent="aspace_e4f423ac4acc783a4638622d087565ab" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c7fb60fc3ce174d399b672387629ccc8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with several government officials in regards to local 1199 endorsing their political campaigns. Also contains a list of political endorsements, a statement by local 1199 on Richard L. Ottinger, a press release about local 1199 backing a political candidate, and a telegram from a candidate thanking local 1199.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_57731ec2e78e236641d5444c21bf45e9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Endorsements</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_c31afabe109dc2ac6f381fcc1f3aee12" label="unspecified" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_5c982c17b4f92045770b22e9f03aa23e" parent="aspace_c31afabe109dc2ac6f381fcc1f3aee12" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_223c9b3a9a02b11dc8a6e0f7e87c650a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with several government officials in regards to local 1199 endorsing their political campaigns. Also contains a memorandum, telegram, statement, press release, and correspondence regarding local 1199's support of presidential candidate George McGovern.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_95d0ea12337fb0586930ee10776b8101" level="file"><did><unittitle>Executive Board</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1972" type="inclusive">1969-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_d38c49b3af8089cbff468581fb6f65ff" label="unspecified" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_279af4c166614b877166df04e697ca04" parent="aspace_d38c49b3af8089cbff468581fb6f65ff" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_844dcfd848fb836e42092b39e36aed77"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains income and expenses report, executive council annual report, list of national union staff, list of executive board members, letters of invitation for the executive board meeting, memo to all board members, and a list of employees earning more that $10,000 a year.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_aee1e64ecda2db573d47286ab1958900" level="file"><did><unittitle>Executive Council-Appeals, Requests, Hearings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_de3a69f68ff36b5aa71a2591e0a613f1" label="unspecified" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_84755513de12675bb064be39b2eb3679" parent="aspace_de3a69f68ff36b5aa71a2591e0a613f1" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5907076307d58ca2e86338e1529b75fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a revision of dues schedule, request to have a day off on black solidarity day, petition to have a case put on the Delegate Assembly agenda, secret ballot for changes in dues, and a letter of invitation to the executive council for the retired members annual banquet.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9737a7386225386ffbc56a3245dcf105" level="file"><did><unittitle>Executive Council-Appeals, Requests, Hearings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1973" type="inclusive">1971-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_78a5cf22ebc9742a294d927dd40df9ab" label="unspecified" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_15087f312e4efbb0ac295c427986912c" parent="aspace_78a5cf22ebc9742a294d927dd40df9ab" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72163e323fecb07f3f12ae58e11416dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains letter and correspondence with various political, religious, civil rights, health and other groups including other unions, regarding event invitations and donation requests. Contains form letters and contribution receipts. Contains petitions from local 1199 members to executive council regarding pay board decision.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ab993e710cf6bcc18d7d8f966ffb3ba8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Executive Council-Appeals, Requests, Hearings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1969" type="inclusive">1966-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_df390426126851dce0aa5d17676ef1b2" label="unspecified" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_204e258168c3c0f645cb4932982ac0ac" parent="aspace_df390426126851dce0aa5d17676ef1b2" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_423d4d6ae04d5bfeb1842301a7029812"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a memorandum to area directors regarding executive council decision, a complaint filed from a union member, petitions from local 1199 members to have certain issues put on the Delegate Assembly agenda, a petition to amend the local 1199 constitution, a petition to change the payroll system, and a petition from retirees asking for increases in their pensions.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_5fbe1dda213f56b351db0e075822e3d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>French Polyclinic Health Center</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_e40225cb3ebb21d8bb55865e4a8b4fe4" label="unspecified" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_885f79c183224fe31674ab889bb199fa" parent="aspace_e40225cb3ebb21d8bb55865e4a8b4fe4" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8cfa5156efd872dc098f7b1e27e1ad0a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains form letters, pamphlets, telegrams, and correspondence with local 144 and the French Polyclinic hospital regarding the merger of the two hospitals and which union will get jurisdiction over all the union employees. Also contains a copy of the local 144 hospital pension plan, and a sheet with the number of union employees at the French and Polyclinic hospitals.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_94a8b5a6c0ae7ebea2e9a529eb8e1d9a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gouverneur Health Service Program Dispute</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_82ab1baf0dc9e76f932f46b86ab796d4" label="unspecified" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_4970353fa91aeaa9671407f9c2f24ba2" parent="aspace_82ab1baf0dc9e76f932f46b86ab796d4" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_245d6d28c8a36c7ed3395c39badfec70"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a statement issued by local 1199 with respect to Gouverneur Health Services Program, contains a petition from Gouverneur Health Services Program employees, contains statement from the fired union members, and contains correspondence with lawyers regarding why local 1199 will not support the Gouverneur workers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_244a4d4973357f1fbd21ce3887ed528e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Guest Appearance on "Direct Line"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a6746591ef67e1f5e1949c2c3047ac1" label="unspecified" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_602110dd1ff4339177dd7d3749115263" parent="aspace_1a6746591ef67e1f5e1949c2c3047ac1" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d45fe3526ffc0283578818a12e3239ae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a transcript of what was said when Leon Davis was on the talk show "Direct Line".</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ac629121b899fad5ef6a6096f0c481da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health and Hospital Corporation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1971" type="inclusive">1967-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_3615dec91f21ae935f7b0ff9defc6bf5" label="unspecified" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_99fde9a4b4bdf897d21417bceb6a31a2" parent="aspace_3615dec91f21ae935f7b0ff9defc6bf5" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b7fcf4aa027d20359694baf172189600"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandum and correspondence with New York City Health and Hospital Corporation regarding affiliation contracts for hospital workers. Also contains newspaper articles and brochures discussing the conflict between 1199 and the NYC Health and Hospital Corporation, a supplemental agreement, affiliation memorandums, and proposed amendments to the local 1199 constitution.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9b602acdcc1ae113ecf4ad3d8a13c60d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health and Hospital Corporation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_175d3d1c6c0057c13289db346b8e3ba6" label="unspecified" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_220377966cfdf579d5837c06001b32ca" parent="aspace_175d3d1c6c0057c13289db346b8e3ba6" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49bb3ee7953c254fad68f5dd8c7ff0c4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with New York City Health and Hospital Corporation regarding affiliation contracts for hospital workers. Contains telegrams about 1199 strike rumors, arbitration case, rollback of affiliation non-professional employees, a memorandum of understanding between the department of hospitals and the district council, a transcript from a talk show featuring the Health and Hospital Corporation, and press releases.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9783f34aac9bec5e2f849c2d0a65f055" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health-Medical Care</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd650e7f9af3658f936376ab8b05ff50" label="unspecified" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_076ce6035200352088cca4f1e2f54621" parent="aspace_cd650e7f9af3658f936376ab8b05ff50" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_16a1ed66f44a1d390b9e503f05bf668e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a statement of Jesse Olsen-Vice-President local 1199, new job description, notice of public hearing on health manpower, transcript of Davis' testimony, journal article, correspondence with state senate, statement by Davis, and a schedule of hospital inclusive plan rates.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_fcc9484740bd23a48a15e30786f27c19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health-Medical Care</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca0afaed87f7bd934964d65ef3e58274" label="unspecified" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_c478657c779d7d6603795c8ed043fd34" parent="aspace_ca0afaed87f7bd934964d65ef3e58274" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1db6199f196cd1fd7128a4733378b6bf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains letters requesting Davis to testify at state senate Executive Session and a notice of Executive Session.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d35f954ee78bc0b19afc4da91dc36c64" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospital League-Local 1199 Training and Upgrading Fund</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f351d7020f5bb5d71037ef2c6404234" label="unspecified" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_fc2284043c9fd2e19e441ace3d349739" parent="aspace_0f351d7020f5bb5d71037ef2c6404234" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d024bb93a4bb9c7d1f3348f1adf3a737"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with students, hospitals, accountants, professors, the Training and Upgrading Fund, and government officials regarding a training conference to be put on by the Fund. Also contains financial statements, resumes, memorandums, agenda, list of applicants and meeting minutes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_4597f3ecfdcb01c702cc92f7814d1e68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospital League-Local 1199 Training and Upgrading Fund</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_b001cce3cd642de565ada885055f6f65" label="unspecified" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_2f13b1b77503c981411d3d1001516f6d" parent="aspace_b001cce3cd642de565ada885055f6f65" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5bc1b1d294c85fd93e1a1bd586630a36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with colleges, hospitals, the Department of Labor, and the Training and Upgrading Fund, regarding a training conference to be put on by the Fund. Also contains meeting minutes, agendas, a list of applicants, agreements, contracts, applicant information, and newspaper clippings.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_34ec87c53cc0cb3dc2019c6a5c0a647b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospital League-Local 1199 Training and Upgrading Fund</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0f1e690575038e651c90f441e7870c7" label="unspecified" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_44af3e4b32d4e1cf057cad3fec372d97" parent="aspace_e0f1e690575038e651c90f441e7870c7" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5f062f2363f4d5dcfae90d01d19044f3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the Training and Upgrading Fund. Also contains financial statements, meeting minutes, and annual reports.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f01e5da863e08942d6d58a702cb6a5ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospital Model Contract</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_f580b19c2b95090f3ae7de327d297dfa" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_fad48a994db89d1e964420d95f9ee370" parent="aspace_f580b19c2b95090f3ae7de327d297dfa" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_29fd32758f5c3e34eea1df917f5d5e9b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers regarding revisions to the model contract. Also contains index to contracts and articles of agreement.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3de09b1d88256252b89581233626d25e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospital Negotiations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_19e1438fd0bd4084faef7b83a0aead79" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_a162ec0de69e1863b90d73733236addc" parent="aspace_19e1438fd0bd4084faef7b83a0aead79" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_76a63d6dbc6fa2e3e0f7f10584b90788"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the State Mediations Board, the 1199 Delegate Assembly, the League of Voluntary Hospitals, and 1199 members regarding negotiation of the collective bargaining agreement. Also contains collective bargaining stipulations, committee on negotiations meeting minutes, contract demands on behalf of hospitals, 1199 contract ratifications, a confidential bulletin, flyers, telegrams, a notice of entry, a memorandum, a summary of gains in the new contract, a transcript of the public hearings, contract changes proposed by 1199 membership, a proposal, a statement by Davis, contract expirations, and a strike plan.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9411b831785a869c95573cd5f3cc4fe4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospital Negotiations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_343f61d0f50c83343ba842676de18b10" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_a5feced6c4071f3beffdb28accd14009" parent="aspace_343f61d0f50c83343ba842676de18b10" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_24c0f0db92799d17e416c75b4a7942e0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with congressmen, lawyers, the Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, and Mayor Lindsay, 1199 members, the League of Voluntary Hospitals, and 1199 members regarding the collective bargaining agreement. Also contains notice of hearing from the Department of Labor, a transcript of an arbitration, a summary of gains from the new contract, the Department of Labor recommendations, a memorandum, and index of benefits, an invitation, a poem, a telegram, list of lunch reimbursements, a statement by Davis, a letter to the New York Times, a press release, and a proposal for contract renewal.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c416274ee221d08dca987109ba7cc7c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1970" type="inclusive">1964-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_adb5c898764b1df089d6a73366320553" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_4f62b7b7f48a80432a3dea233aec368d" parent="aspace_adb5c898764b1df089d6a73366320553" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25044ddc2884e3be95da9e59d0e0eaad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a letter from lawyers including arbitration proceedings. Contains correspondence with universities, and lawyers. Also contains an arbitration decision, telegrams, an order to show cause, the Hospital Executives Club membership roster, and a paper written by Theodore Kheel.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_4321138ab23278e3da951c50c6f8bdd3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d3f1ce90412575ab76932a87a9d7750" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_5904f7f3de95e4bd59a95f0ae7d6f8fa" parent="aspace_1d3f1ce90412575ab76932a87a9d7750" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_87dc5d51a8aaf2fee31eeb56854fd93d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers, the city of New York, universities, and hospitals regarding contracts, work stoppages, and union member issues. Also contains court proceedings and decisions, and union flyers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_51b975f87eec90b9d7ae9c6b2a7b85bb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d254efed8096c65c0a16fca7c6e9b2e" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_379815fee029207683684714d7ee0d77" parent="aspace_6d254efed8096c65c0a16fca7c6e9b2e" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_541618376acfb1300d4bc632be66691b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with 1199 members, hospitals, the IRS, and the AFL-CIO regarding labor contracts, strikes, and union representatives. Also contains telegrams, a supplemental clause to an agreement, and news clipping.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a761530d88bf3720a4fe883a30bca92b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1969" type="inclusive">1967-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_23af06f79319e1f2c9d85582a007b18f" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_6fe4454d179b66e0d8b2dd6ded39db76" parent="aspace_23af06f79319e1f2c9d85582a007b18f" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b80e8e6d1b531f7d00af5ad727f5a9f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with New York Medical College regarding financial problems. Also contains correspondence with universities, hospitals and lawyers regarding terms of the labor contract. Contains a list of hospital rates, a publication called The Effect of Unions on Hospital Management, and a magazine article.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_461917ad52fb890219edbc0ab22af5a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Housing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_02db865138cf8702545a7a1ee826da01" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_cc001ee8c98449fd16f880ef1f31dae6" parent="aspace_02db865138cf8702545a7a1ee826da01" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96513d77180d8ef543b941ec95d3acc2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with government officials, non-profit housing groups regarding fair housing initiatives. Also contains news clippings on local housing issues.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_225f1c13facf14a98eb8b9a7d899c285" level="file"><did><unittitle>Housing--Union Sponsorship</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e39e9c2a2c0d0e28fdbb630c4ed12ff" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_f8aec26f4a7c19012dc79a8b4882faf3" parent="aspace_1e39e9c2a2c0d0e28fdbb630c4ed12ff" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9938d1ca6972dae3daf120d9f5ea0c1b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with government officials, the Housing and Development Administration, lawyers, architects, and contractors regarding the East River Urban Renewal Project sponsored by 1199. Also contains memorandums, telegrams, meeting minutes and a list of applicants to help sponsor the project.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_12450dd7e516e97bcf1e7740dab064a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jewish Currents Dinner</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ea2a85e24ad6bb2cefcc8f03d1d4b8c" label="unspecified" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_7939e67d48f103d2128aa7aad3183fb4" parent="aspace_6ea2a85e24ad6bb2cefcc8f03d1d4b8c" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe5b326c7dd36bf6def8f60160ec4e43"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the Jewish Currents publication regarding a dinner where Davis is scheduled to speak. Also contains Davis' introduction and his speech at the event plus an article written about the event in a Jewish newspaper.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e02c61e11940ba387587e04898c352b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1961" type="inclusive">1959-1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_388e8331e4c6296b4a94b27b2c889be9" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_77317ea3cce172c6a8f27294c327c9fd" parent="aspace_388e8331e4c6296b4a94b27b2c889be9" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21740c19f1a82fc2accf4c6710eabc01"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains the following publications by the Department of Labor: State Labor Relations Acts and the Second Annual Report of the Advisory Council on the Labor and Management Improper Practices Act. Also contains a pamphlet called Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959, a pamphlet called Understanding the 1959 Labor Law, and a pamphlet called Labor Organization Information Reporting. Contains a memorandum from General Counsel and a statement by the National Lawyers Guild about the Act. Contains newspaper articles, telegrams, and correspondence with other labor organizations regarding the new Act.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_683c5410fb36ca286c8224b231b7104b" level="file"><did><unittitle>League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f38c473bdee703d1f62b32145c6f883" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_20024d6d70282cede111d75fd9af514c" parent="aspace_4f38c473bdee703d1f62b32145c6f883" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d812be80ab50525bf67ec6f3f9d4e043"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a copy of the collective bargaining agreement with the League, correspondence with lawyers and the League, and a list of members of the League.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a65870e19d4114b335e038c758e98575" level="file"><did><unittitle>League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_07120cbb768831978765c7715c0a7e2a" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_07e0a2d320fc7f914b24d0b839449372" parent="aspace_07120cbb768831978765c7715c0a7e2a" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e7bf9cff7dd2319b8d05e5d17d6117c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a copy of the collective bargaining agreement between the League of Voluntary Hospitals and Local 1199. Contains correspondence with the League of Voluntary Hospitals regarding terms of the collective bargaining agreement. Also contains letters from hospitals who have recently joined the League. Contains report from the Impasse Panel.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2cb29a9807cbaea09354a846d0467d42" level="file"><did><unittitle>League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_eca75b97dec6531d4df2ae1d5c3b71f4" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_0b446a1d859512fc4a04ac675ec575f2" parent="aspace_eca75b97dec6531d4df2ae1d5c3b71f4" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f0207a91cccb4b9062318d0537f451ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a copy of the collective bargaining agreement between the League of Voluntary Hospitals and Local 1199. Contains correspondence with the League of Voluntary Hospitals regarding terms of the collective bargaining agreement.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_654c2b88c9df3854d14088fbdbedd9ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.--Union Arbitration.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_e753666117565dd71e7708b59441a777" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_b729afe9b946ce26fb0bb9be832a8997" parent="aspace_e753666117565dd71e7708b59441a777" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1feadf560e2e79e4d65bdbed9cb863e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the League, lawyers, the State Board of Mediation, and the mayor's office regarding arbitration cases. Also contains a settlement agreement, a list of exclusions by agreement, a copy of the Local 1199 benefit plan, financial reports, and arbitration briefs.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e89646b115f245f5709cdc521616a2db" level="file"><did><unittitle>League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.--Union Committees.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_b7bbd2be33ae533b21bcfe69239559c5" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_b40e16fba12b0c215eabf826cceb3e55" parent="aspace_b7bbd2be33ae533b21bcfe69239559c5" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1df7e2c5cc061f49d01fbab13436fcbf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the League regarding the formation of the following for committees: Training and Upgrading, Job Study-Inequity, Hiring Hall-Recruitment, and Pension. Contains a list of who is in each committee.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b2c044b2e23ca10224f85407553fa7c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.--Training and Upgrading Committee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_7512e69e656a197439a4f1aba4bb308c" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_0f0ee33ce8ef83463921bf3dc05f8b22" parent="aspace_7512e69e656a197439a4f1aba4bb308c" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a776ba6a59ddc3472b72998903d9e72f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the League, the training committee, and various government and non-profit organizations regarding the formation of an Advisory Committee for the training committee. Also contains resumes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c1653e44ba8ec8d2c05ad72caed6c0e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes of N.Y.--Training and Upgrading Committee.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0a72c2a0b1a6ea97cc21dc92312b47b" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_d11577f04faea04e472d49e9eaa1d101" parent="aspace_f0a72c2a0b1a6ea97cc21dc92312b47b" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ffadf044fcd056b357b9291a0fdc487"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the training committee, universities, and hospitals regarding recruitment, new programs, and meetings. Also contains telegrams, a memorandum, a list of institutions participating in the program, meeting minutes, a report on the training program and an agreement and declaration of trust.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_4cfe60ecd1bbf79f0af9919dcba23cf1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal Opinions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_2edf9787c840855e918c459848ad6b4f" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_f72f307f38d978d05b07721c97b8f95e" parent="aspace_2edf9787c840855e918c459848ad6b4f" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_22a1ef255e6057be169e7e2b5095ae1c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the training committee, universities, and hospitals regarding recruitment, new programs, and meetings. Also contains telegrams, a memorandum, a list of institutions participating in the program, meeting minutes, a report on the training program and an agreement and declaration of trust.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_473052b2427e756ef7206e545c29d528" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legislation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6630fb5e6dec77861374926af4a5d6f" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_46d42d7b6bd333c244061c260f9888e7" parent="aspace_d6630fb5e6dec77861374926af4a5d6f" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4700fe1e25ec5562f2480516cdab58e0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers, and government organizations and officials regarding certain legislation such as the Health Security Act. Also contains a copy of a bill (National Public Employee Relations Act), the Health Security Act and a memorandum.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_9faeb824ce2587b8af40b6de767304e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legislation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe48ef1178c7a7beacbc9eb776d6426d" label="unspecified" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_8da93e2490d46a29169b7f4077687b29" parent="aspace_fe48ef1178c7a7beacbc9eb776d6426d" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6de5b41f7c2c1ae2722eb52b8a53bffc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers, and government organizations and officials regarding certain legislation such as anti-busing bills. Also contains a proposal for amending labor laws in regards to nursing homes, and a memorandum.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f9d789370a506ddeb0994febbd380ff3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 B- Charleston</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_36f9529e045faabab8aea72d04cc217d" label="unspecified" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_ffc0c433113fefc4305994b3f6a7277a" parent="aspace_36f9529e045faabab8aea72d04cc217d" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_212a3a1f70e3a5d5942e38a5212988f8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis and organizers of 1199 B in Charleston, SC regarding problems in Charleston and the establishment of the chapter. Also contains 1199 B financial statements and list of things to be done in Charleston.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_6ddba9490a27e3d599e91d738dd02c95" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 C- Philadelphia</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_8901bf9a65c09916c69dcfebd2b70287" label="unspecified" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_c10ce0ebb639ee650258435b362cc6a4" parent="aspace_8901bf9a65c09916c69dcfebd2b70287" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4fc6b35e7e4c7bbcf0a553eb83d2c7ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis, lawyers, and organizers of 1199 C in Philadelphia, PA regarding union members, collective bargaining agreements, traffic violations, financial matters, and affiliation with RWDSU. Also contains copy of 1199ers United.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f05fe9c2501368d01d526b588f4143c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 C- Philadelphia</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7a5a5d92ab33675753d7bc6818874ba" label="unspecified" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_648a5feda6db186c8ea1bc7cdc3152e6" parent="aspace_f7a5a5d92ab33675753d7bc6818874ba" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d1791e68d6f17fa6d636438041957a2f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains death certificate and funeral bill for Norman Rayford, a union organizer for 1199 C who was shot by a security guard during an 1199 C rally. Also contains a card from Rayford's wife. Contains correspondence between Davis and 1199 C regarding stolen goods, 1199 C expenses and renovation.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d1e765df2aa2c583c60b59a1b1ad4b95" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Credit Union</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_62b7d03964e95eda792ab56c2a32e2b5" label="unspecified" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_55c71ee9c4c84a245152043e05169fc5" parent="aspace_62b7d03964e95eda792ab56c2a32e2b5" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a7a90971696ce758131cd81d6424c1c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers, the League of Voluntary Hospitals, and 1199 members regarding the establishment of a credit union to deduct union dues automatically from members' paychecks. Also contains a deduction check off list, 1199 credit union financial reports, and an oath taken by committee members of the credit union.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e2fcb264ef7434864fcfe4cf805e1f7d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 E-Baltimore</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4921a9ea0322549e92596d267b98bc2" label="unspecified" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_6d4d80fafbda7474618d6bcfa7385691" parent="aspace_d4921a9ea0322549e92596d267b98bc2" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_939c08502ba21719b869bcc74f79ddda"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers, 1199 E, and accountants regarding financial situation, collective bargaining agreements, and the national union. Also contains financial statements, the 1199 E newsletter, and internal disputes plan, and meeting minutes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f2736218aea91dd4e7ba6137b7a869ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 E-Baltimore</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd62100ff1b74e02bf10c5f40d4bf9b3" label="unspecified" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_0eae18d17ecf986ab437e260a756397b" parent="aspace_cd62100ff1b74e02bf10c5f40d4bf9b3" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e59f67fa789802ca06d6c91e85071757"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with 1199 E, Davis and lawyers regarding financial matters, strikes, union issues, and by-laws. Also contains 1199 E administrative rules, financial reports, a proposal, a petition, meeting minutes, election results, and proposed 1199 E by-laws.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_506a569f852207f66b043f513e38a37b" level="file"><did><unittitle>1199 Financial Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1968" type="inclusive">1965-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c093616ee13f3ad71b41facb86f58ae" label="unspecified" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_a009c1479e4f56efd3f32b81f167d5cd" parent="aspace_9c093616ee13f3ad71b41facb86f58ae" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_18fadb8dba92274ca400019aaf6cbcea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains 1199 reports, 1199 statements of financial condition, and 1199 financial reports. Also contains correspondence with accountants.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ac81679e6ccd0c02e6deef4ff9a2c567" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Financial Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_13f2cb1d0e3bea3aceb7518c039f4189" label="unspecified" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_31f80621d883fdd4b3438782c8733b7d" parent="aspace_13f2cb1d0e3bea3aceb7518c039f4189" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_598f12a4b955926199625ecf74df9605"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a financial report and national union budget.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_abc460dd51cee05e8123c04a4338f75b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Housing Project</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_338e28e7a3a81a9f55d9cf81de08d2db" label="unspecified" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_8784cbbdef9e58de734a8c4387e65c6c" parent="aspace_338e28e7a3a81a9f55d9cf81de08d2db" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c4c89b012381740d367f505b1118d149"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a petition sent to mayor Lindsay regarding the renewal of an area in NYC. Contains memorandum from lawyer regarding 1199 housing- community facilities. Contains correspondence with government officials, the Housing and Development Administration, lawyers, architects, and developers regarding various housing projects including the East River Urban Renewal Project, sponsored by 1199. Also contains news clipping.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_dbae8d409917341e4d42d358aeb0fd56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Housing Program</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4b9cf4286ab16833a6af055d0412a47" label="unspecified" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_89d2b3a2c74e692841c5a88bf0a380fc" parent="aspace_e4b9cf4286ab16833a6af055d0412a47" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_12a0ff00e83f9ed490812d2545db23c9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with government officials, the Housing and Development Administration, lawyers, architects, and developers regarding the East River Urban Renewal Project. Also contains meeting minutes, the Calendar of the Board of Estimate of The City of New York, and an agreement.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7679bc1b2ba915392c08e52d8ef41512" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Housing Program</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_95cce981872883de9baa42da30daad51" label="unspecified" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_599edf54adb61ec9c0982cd703ce7805" parent="aspace_95cce981872883de9baa42da30daad51" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a78dadff35b0a8b52aa200fb7be955c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with government officials, the Housing and Development Administration, lawyers, architects, and developers regarding 1199 housing corporation and the East River Urban Renewal Project. Also contains an information bulletin on the 1199 housing corporation, and a memorandum on the East River Urban Renewal Project.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_86adf005124184990e2642d7aac6ca21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Massachusetts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_875c25cab06dbd1951ba8feb12e1bf5d" label="unspecified" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_4dba91a190b1327819444380734ef775" parent="aspace_875c25cab06dbd1951ba8feb12e1bf5d" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7517f268e182ce674cac24a8816fdf1c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with union regarding the national union and contains financial statement.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a3106d856e502ac5c4a47349bedc2a9d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 P-Pittsburgh</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_044a3236506e85c0340bfbf8ca3e0aba" label="unspecified" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_9b899bcbc8f722f0dddcf11a34e96761" parent="aspace_044a3236506e85c0340bfbf8ca3e0aba" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_76467bde1068d8b2c3da94f2bcc55025"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis, lawyers, and organizers of 1199 C in Philadelphia, PA regarding union members, collective bargaining agreements, and an arbitration case with the University of Pittsburgh. Contains copy of the arbitration and the attorney's ruling.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_fe9dbb86115ef27af09c37ea74937ea2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Staff</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1969" type="inclusive">1966-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_06dc134995f5d9abcef8df0afb3a8664" label="unspecified" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_e05f084c29466291942dc50e232c8c85" parent="aspace_06dc134995f5d9abcef8df0afb3a8664" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3ecb0cae71d3daee1b450a8deac8d5d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains letters from staff members to Davis submitting their resignation or discussing personal issues.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_10e42d40c7dad1bbf1a7561b367e179f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Staff</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6c75269659b0986e63418acc9a2107f" label="unspecified" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_359ec6e324c9536f19752a91ebca2fe0" parent="aspace_f6c75269659b0986e63418acc9a2107f" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b1b969f7d1c29f7fd3a9dc000e3ac12d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, petitions and memorandums between union members and Davis regarding the layoff of a staff member and various other personal and work related issues. Also contains a list of staff members.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_85de1ef3af86e7b0db23f2e684a875eb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 1199 Union Headquarters</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c6f0658cb8a721ebb9e82690331eee7" label="unspecified" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_f43244a945c48dfaef37da3e2b1e4301" parent="aspace_4c6f0658cb8a721ebb9e82690331eee7" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5aeb37e2ddfe4f773088a1e4dd08155b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with architects, insurance company, and artist regarding building the new 1199 headquarters. Also contains drawings, invoices, and brochures.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_99d183fbd2326cdb1fe6aba6e7d5f0f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorandums</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_56ac954e5fd1aa640af97c246daa2c11" label="unspecified" type="box">20</container><container id="aspace_173dc0e10fff56f389145d35c553a2ae" parent="aspace_56ac954e5fd1aa640af97c246daa2c11" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_feac065e224ff32d6616a66570cdb724"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums regarding meetings, trainings, arbitrations, picket lines, food, furniture, collective bargaining agreements, employee issues, wages, contracts, rallies, bills, and more. Also contains letter from lawyers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ee1a2b0f7d0657643354667d0b46b28d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorandums</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b96d39cc9954c2677a9041ba2d04ea1" label="unspecified" type="box">20</container><container id="aspace_9664cd84519ea889caff0786bd2df3c1" parent="aspace_3b96d39cc9954c2677a9041ba2d04ea1" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aa27f82ad250f3059e3d4346c6241ec2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums regarding staff expenses, parties, complaints, financial reports, elections, wages, meetings, rallies and boycotts, furniture, reimbursements, training, arbitration, invitations, complaints, and more.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f9b10ca73525ee7bee03fc7f8e40e7a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minimum Wage</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_b882bfcc68e0dfae9914f162a2794e2e" label="unspecified" type="box">20</container><container id="aspace_eb723aa3090a3baca78b89672c793481" parent="aspace_b882bfcc68e0dfae9914f162a2794e2e" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70aec7c696b75940280854ca5f265af6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with government officials and unions, memorandums and telegrams regarding increasing the minimum wage. Also contains correspondence with lawyers and a brief of a court case involving 1199 as interveners between the City of New York and Prudential Laundry Corporation.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a860f2f618ab2876e13a4ca05d0ae59d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Montefiore Hospital</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b245ed132b0d6835bc92c3f6d492d2a" label="unspecified" type="box">20</container><container id="aspace_a41ce22f8c4d8befa2e3096b94d3c2fc" parent="aspace_0b245ed132b0d6835bc92c3f6d492d2a" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eb37cd83a8988a878940ebb4c19b6ffb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains Montefiore Hospital and Medical Center Third Annual Report.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_76ec36dc75bc31e7df24b5f7853bb84a" level="file"><did><unittitle>NLRB-Compliance Taft Hartley</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1958" type="inclusive">1953-1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0c013d39203ba36463bb66cdb6a91e9" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_cebcf357d17873bea43c239a403cfe74" parent="aspace_f0c013d39203ba36463bb66cdb6a91e9" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5774b53c22bf28b250e4b35e37328b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains letters from 1199 lawyers notifying them that they need to fill out forms to remain in compliance with the Taft Hartley laws.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_0840c644ed5393b951ed456dca469ec8" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Union Conference</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_110a6647487915ff469514607b4576fb" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_c6e8be1010c3f5934206428100c73f2c" parent="aspace_110a6647487915ff469514607b4576fb" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b7e15b360d59d7ff7c49b80455684b3a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, invitations, brochures, and financial statements regarding the National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees Conference in December of 1971.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e1b5b852d73d173c94ee8260a010a85e" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Union -Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_d504f4b5553a2b5ca9f4c696e1c0ebf2" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_2fd30cfbe2452272c0cec32755846990" parent="aspace_d504f4b5553a2b5ca9f4c696e1c0ebf2" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_365cf266454ed8702297cbc1d356bd02"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with AFL-CIO unions regarding loans, and correspondence with 1199 members who reached out to Davis for help. Also contains 1199 operating budget for 1970, the envelope stock for all of the 1199 branches across the country, and a request to Davis to be an Impartial Umpire in a labor dispute.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_370d4af23f74fd81486be33246ab0cbe" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Union Founding Conference</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef6451740e3344b529be4f6db9fe8538" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_3a36c7a38912e3305f9f0e4884b03d7c" parent="aspace_ef6451740e3344b529be4f6db9fe8538" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_36b617ecdae278bde782898f19cbff26"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers and government officials regarding the establishment of a National Hospital and Nursing Home Employees division of 1199. Also contains income and expense report for the national organizing committee and for 1199 B, conference invitations, a conference agenda, list of conference attendants, confirmation from the conference hotel and catering service, a state of the union report, and a newspaper clipping.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f346ce04be20405c5c75b62abeaf65a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Union Membership Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bf26ad3a060125d198ea81ac278a820" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_325034a3fff8a7d17e9e8e0ebcf02c87" parent="aspace_2bf26ad3a060125d198ea81ac278a820" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04fb2f705f7bc94a15264533f5d54a67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a memorandum regarding the National Union Membership Report for November 1970. National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees Membership Report for November 1970, October 1970, May 1970, June 1970, July 1970, August 1970, and September 1970.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_693c1fb524ab11d58f0a43ae9e8bc8a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Union Memorandums</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_a24d8f1540107c78c710853b47cd37a9" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_a787d8e63d41fd34981961667abc4d42" parent="aspace_a24d8f1540107c78c710853b47cd37a9" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_19735862d186d86076c1a166008b8e59"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums to 1199 members about union policies, financial reports, legal issues, conferences, phone bills or about reports that need to be made.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_8211ff4fa2e35d9c6d80357470d32431" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Union Memorandums</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8251502910d15336f72c97e9933013c" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_ab5c4e67fd3192df8f1afc1ae1c96186" parent="aspace_c8251502910d15336f72c97e9933013c" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_43030078cb81e25a87dc1622e1e54736"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums regarding union policies, and new technology. Also contains summary of National Union Strike and Defense Fund.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f11e9375604417a37c6d8e34ab7fe688" level="file"><did><unittitle>Negotiation Committee Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_f670b383e476bf5d682cbfe470b454e1" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_06195eefffaf6567cce4a84387fb1818" parent="aspace_f670b383e476bf5d682cbfe470b454e1" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c9a643337d26c02b8b0746375d50eec0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains negotiation committee meeting minutes and proposals for the 1972 contract.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b7d90c0a53eeecc4258db290f7d00454" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Jersey AFL-CIO</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_845b676c9756cc25623d6eaf9093aa41" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_4bf61994bfb8f75e547910d0416653e9" parent="aspace_845b676c9756cc25623d6eaf9093aa41" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_26cf111b4a3bbe154b160fd35a030052"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains invitation to New Jersey AFL-CIO conference, a copy of the 1968 legislative program sponsored by the New Jersey State AFL-CIO, correspondence with the New Jersey AFL-CIO regarding advice on resolutions, strike funds, and union events. Also contains New Jersey AFL-CIO election information, and the constitution of the New Jersey State AFL-CIO.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_8bda65937f297a858126609e04c0e4dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>N.Y.C Central Labor Council</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_6312af289b32da704c73c9aed57e7ce6" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_d0e0cba22282992fb71396cba8bbeab1" parent="aspace_6312af289b32da704c73c9aed57e7ce6" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f1cc1f6eb5de8be3e4245acd33a86d35"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the NYC Central Labor Council regarding strikes, civil rights laws, organizing taxi cab drivers, meetings, and elections. Also contains a telegram and a receipt.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_6a2f4c07b329add024c926a5ffda531b" level="file"><did><unittitle>N.Y.C Central Labor Council</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_817a0a7feb3d41118d7b6c944264e114" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_c45da96851baa118224bace391d7dbd6" parent="aspace_817a0a7feb3d41118d7b6c944264e114" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_18b1d519ab83d40597e5467f525a09d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the NYC Central Labor Council regarding meetings, conferences, dinners, mass demonstrations, payroll taxes, strikes and wage freezes. Also contains a telegram, a memorandum about the Governor's Program Bill, and a list of NYC Central Labor Council officers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_aeb3ee3bc779c237a487639c5a216479" level="file"><did><unittitle>N.Y.C Central Labor Council</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_560bf5a30dbd8c6a98ba71690657a4d3" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_4897085f335029f5dd149abdb51669fc" parent="aspace_560bf5a30dbd8c6a98ba71690657a4d3" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cb7e156a180ed9042c407c242735facb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the NYC Central Labor Council regarding strikes, advertisements, and parties/events.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_87afd5523f147e186378a351f52d5b47" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYC School Strike</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1969" type="inclusive">1967-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f6822c88b84bb9177587a5a100b28ee" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_b7c9f4fde5f94d0162003c469414b421" parent="aspace_4f6822c88b84bb9177587a5a100b28ee" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6fd33f882b64498f718df3175f0c8c28"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains telegrams, correspondence, statements, pamphlets, and summaries regarding a teachers union strike in NYC during salary negotiations. Also contains correspondence with southern groups regarding voting rights of African Americans in Mississippi.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_087bcdf6a76fe6ff2e4621841313b216" level="file"><did><unittitle>NY Urban Coalition</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_9567ea751b92bba0352be95d6a70de52" label="unspecified" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_7a5db181b5227594fb692ed7a70b75b3" parent="aspace_9567ea751b92bba0352be95d6a70de52" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a85d3983280de83e90d0fa0612780880"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with the New York Urban Coalition regarding Yeshiva Teachers Strike, meetings, scholarship programs, unemployment, luncheons, government campaigns, housing projects, the Adult Career Ladder Program, and Davis' reelection on to the board of directors. Also contains meeting minutes from NY Urban Coalition board of directors meeting, and a policy statement regarding low-wage workers in New York City.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_12ce0d46fd9a6c639cc9f73992b6aeda" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personnel Applications</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_e907a7b4ebff414ce96c97068dac0b46" label="unspecified" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_a3c8d035a11b2b8947bbbbe2e3a52fc7" parent="aspace_e907a7b4ebff414ce96c97068dac0b46" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77e1d0fcf58f7cf144a3de71340cc3bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis and job applicants for various 1199 positions including office manager. Also contains resumes, and job advertisements for the New York Times.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_632353236f17c00b0f2abe549f5aee42" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personnel Applications</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1965" type="inclusive">1964-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_905d7ac4a73d0c29bef914ad9778210d" label="unspecified" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_c3d64704744b2c32701068eb3014fb9c" parent="aspace_905d7ac4a73d0c29bef914ad9778210d" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b98839707560397e9aeb4d52edc0b145"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with people seeking employment at 1199, in particular students who seek summer employment. Also contains resumes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c6e7fc845027d00e04a05af0f21cd227" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personnel Requests</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b2dab3dad9149c36583dd397725a385" label="unspecified" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_a53f4684c6a30634027e6c404df0b081" parent="aspace_0b2dab3dad9149c36583dd397725a385" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b27dcb680d0d94c712eb62848dc11e5b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with people seeking employment at 1199. Also contains resumes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e029dcf37de1845e6a6be22fa3d5f632" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political Action</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_0823fdfcdf5b0b2993ef67c9ca2a35ac" label="unspecified" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_23bf813f6bc0da0eec3562a964e17e8e" parent="aspace_0823fdfcdf5b0b2993ef67c9ca2a35ac" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e3aed690e615b55e8c175f5583802082"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, statements, and memorandums regarding various political situations including elections, court cases, laws, etc.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_6426d9c291c0c4965967df6061b25ed1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political Action</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_d686c35b99c66180db55a1927bedfad1" label="unspecified" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_9f374b9807b50d29c72556c49fba1b53" parent="aspace_d686c35b99c66180db55a1927bedfad1" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_986ef6c074782d75c8dca34579918dd1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains telegrams and correspondence with civil rights groups regarding race relations, and housing in New York City. Also contains correspondence regarding court cases.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2f090b6d1031106ebaf02b28346a7bc7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Public Housing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_4078499d407fba0ae012534c6abe1963" label="unspecified" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_9d4b8b24fe8126eab1775d19feff19d8" parent="aspace_4078499d407fba0ae012534c6abe1963" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9e0a5236add0d0147d5ad538418bc400"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains housing project proposal, various brochures and reports about housing construction plans. Also contains correspondence about housing project plans, and list of people involved in the project.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_13e22fb6d2c75c761583de1b710f7cab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports-Membership [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee0d1fb3ef151bf99a7028bc4a38e585" label="unspecified" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_0b3b800b98ca122dc2484a39a094056d" parent="aspace_ee0d1fb3ef151bf99a7028bc4a38e585" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0d7a4ce95f31cfc36be878b5edcc7c94"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains detailed 1199 membership reports for each month in 1968.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_183d93c82485a77f4c308c95a24daae0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports-Membership [folder 2 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_509e6f61e154850ff30e507a1b00b9f2" label="unspecified" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_baa65d9fb3177e54cff162f3fd317762" parent="aspace_509e6f61e154850ff30e507a1b00b9f2" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee557530a2647f7f31342040bf3637d0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains detailed 1199 membership reports for each month in 1968.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f158204ec1fd5653b0ab87c9403b694c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports-Membership [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_36033af3eef688bb63542bac619df934" label="unspecified" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_3f3f784d665565a4e069bc34959b066f" parent="aspace_36033af3eef688bb63542bac619df934" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a6511603a860897b327333e5c4c137ec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains detailed 1199 membership reports for most months in 1969.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_287cfcb08c8747fa2d58778506b99fc0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports-Membership [folder 2 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_4b81031bf9d277a50d0d4703d5ab56a1" label="unspecified" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_0b535df30fe30132415f6ef77f80186d" parent="aspace_4b81031bf9d277a50d0d4703d5ab56a1" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d91d6a0b2ae34c4aedbf7a9f87452593"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains detailed 1199 membership reports for most months in 1969.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_252e695a644f84372a75077abd5782a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_da2d2571fc0054c1e11e7972cb39fc83" label="unspecified" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_e4756822f7d0cdd979d45fca947f9791" parent="aspace_da2d2571fc0054c1e11e7972cb39fc83" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be90bb94b1786811e39543b86d8b4ac5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains various 1199 reports from 1970 including a yearly report of membership meeting attendance, grievance reports, annual reports, and membership reports. Also contains handwritten notes, financial statements and a memorandum.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_432930ace24c645257244245fd3f655a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce151d6da0982f7ebaf27719a2833759" label="unspecified" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_f5ab434e3af5626e7902701250a760f2" parent="aspace_ce151d6da0982f7ebaf27719a2833759" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3d3d96034cf1f19ace0f92ce824e881f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains memorandums and correspondence regarding the compilation of the annual report. Also contains a list of monthly reports, financial reports, and handwritten notes.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d2e1a432b605f7fa7a932e17320e95cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Monthly Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_52b735fe75734f0228c48cf15e80b4fc" label="unspecified" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_aefa260749e5a1476d4b7d5616843f5b" parent="aspace_52b735fe75734f0228c48cf15e80b4fc" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_09f070c498f920ca2526a504f7c95639"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains monthly membership reports, and hospital division activities reports.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a52507057ce5a9f1cc1062eca267da98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Monthly Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_85d1d1220be8cba0a1dc398b84f99290" label="unspecified" type="box">24</container><container id="aspace_fffe8be2ddc1b131bf4e97fcb61c079f" parent="aspace_85d1d1220be8cba0a1dc398b84f99290" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a9a7b8b5d9b22097ca5d0bcb07c4aecf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains monthly hospital division activities reports and contract information reports from January to June.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_5ca8dedbe79b302e48783a7c8cd65a9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Monthly Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_df5d4aff2fc0593d6bc1061bb4a47886" label="unspecified" type="box">24</container><container id="aspace_05b81d72edaaf1b3c0a6ef9bb963158f" parent="aspace_df5d4aff2fc0593d6bc1061bb4a47886" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b5ce4987a07ab6b9eb746759c37297d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains monthly hospital division activities reports and contract information reports from June to December.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_89ec9ffe25bfa7cbe0f4cb5a1bb3d4d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Finance Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_cfcd4dd39d30d1558847a96cf56cfdb0" label="unspecified" type="box">24</container><container id="aspace_ee0656ffe43daab37d3c21576d680b46" parent="aspace_cfcd4dd39d30d1558847a96cf56cfdb0" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_499dce3466d2e9a26308547073718fec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains 1199 statistical reports for each month in 1972.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_140a62ee1d8002db1c44b1c3d0b6663f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Annual Report</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_58668eded134928c917b2a9a2210b6b4" label="unspecified" type="box">24</container><container id="aspace_29f06855d103dce85837890cd7d774c7" parent="aspace_58668eded134928c917b2a9a2210b6b4" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7cc6bc2d2bab0f90f35bee3ab3acba21"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains the annual report, the strike and defense fund financial report, a report to the delegates assembly, and various handwritten notes and financial statements and statistics.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d58b0b1250cf78e91a6c1257865c8aae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Monthly Reports [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca87ff7f5921175d2d98bf101413f527" label="unspecified" type="box">25</container><container id="aspace_75ef8859271868dfd688f05d256dcae2" parent="aspace_ca87ff7f5921175d2d98bf101413f527" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23439377f6858270584373f8a983fe08"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains 1199 Division Activities Reports for January through June 1972.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_46e480e6496d67d9b1ac69c5c910a6d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Monthly Reports [folder 2 of 2]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_b232d5d278d04899e2b40b955d2f4b90" label="unspecified" type="box">25</container><container id="aspace_b5479ba24e3721da09ccdc67b7e2bcd2" parent="aspace_b232d5d278d04899e2b40b955d2f4b90" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_231d2fedc48a3dfc98e36b9ff0f7daec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains 1199 Division Activities Reports for July through December 1972.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_aa59d665a854c35f647b311f940c637d" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_f30a130aa842a30e2735da908202297c" label="unspecified" type="box">25</container><container id="aspace_81783954d655432cea9068456e2b830c" parent="aspace_f30a130aa842a30e2735da908202297c" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_692022b795b6aa9bbf34d781f5f6cb75"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis and the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) regarding pension plans.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_675a740649aa53e4d722c53048ee7297" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f0f81ce6f435401e3e7e30a130cbe92" label="unspecified" type="box">25</container><container id="aspace_e4ef87674275eae71fbcf705acd3d4eb" parent="aspace_4f0f81ce6f435401e3e7e30a130cbe92" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_923607b1fcb5817fe99c953644e9ece4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis and the RWDSU regarding meetings, strikes, current events, and conventions. Also contains telegrams, handwritten notes, invitations and invoices.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_0d679f36a34dac9d5c5bbb7c32eb678e" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_117bf86a97c5ed50c66adcd3584d7cf8" label="unspecified" type="box">25</container><container id="aspace_f843f8cd833f4e49b37e86a5b211084f" parent="aspace_117bf86a97c5ed50c66adcd3584d7cf8" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_243f8a4342105e78c9bc071013f8d152"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with RWDSU regarding union policies, laws, meetings, and the charges against executive board member David Livingston.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_c651c8664278572ad26bce679a7aae4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_26aba8a073846f490fa1046e4a505366" label="unspecified" type="box">25</container><container id="aspace_0138a9b0a2e163247a32ebdee616ee23" parent="aspace_26aba8a073846f490fa1046e4a505366" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cacebeeb03b563b1d9046db822ace848"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with RWDSU regarding Livingston charges, 1199 membership, meetings, the AFL-CIO, current events, and pension plans. Also contains a meeting agenda, a proposal, resolutions, an agreement, a statement of assets and liabilities, and telegrams.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_85e94d0162aa6b95b6adf42b0d77f51f" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_d84049ee5d3c78694a2be42b0b06d8b2" label="unspecified" type="box">25</container><container id="aspace_834611bdbd8fa52fbe2a8627fdab3671" parent="aspace_d84049ee5d3c78694a2be42b0b06d8b2" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b561bfb528e87698781de1b7d465bcd6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with RWSDU regarding meetings, and pension issues. Also contains national union membership reports for July through September.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_46ecfa1de1a343a0fa2ec2498fd0d081" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Convention Proceedings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1960" type="inclusive">1956-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef270d4690e4f628745dc4bb97ded236" label="unspecified" type="box">26</container><container id="aspace_f53cb8b84a46b2d891cbace9c68c0d7e" parent="aspace_ef270d4690e4f628745dc4bb97ded236" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_394122b293137da92b87a3cd7145fc1e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with RWDSU regarding meetings and current issues. Also contains RWDSU meeting minutes, resolutions, president's reports, financial reports, and financial statements.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ee282b48feca8fb8a7da269f306ec98b" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Convention Proceedings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1967" type="inclusive">1960-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c2614034fca0e7aca4669550f709b66" label="unspecified" type="box">26</container><container id="aspace_6856a2565aaf213c79fd9bf7a8ea894b" parent="aspace_3c2614034fca0e7aca4669550f709b66" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fffc2bf9328c4edb683ae3ea36e5b65d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with RWDSU regarding meetings and current issues. Also contains RWDSU meeting minutes, resolutions, president's reports, financial reports, and financial statements.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_042e2eefbbade2626eccce458c466b6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Pension Plans</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1969" type="inclusive">1965-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_e87ce30d2f3fe97b01fbb8c45f8da8d3" label="unspecified" type="box">26</container><container id="aspace_5a35cc272b484ec8dc96d1d07b115ad4" parent="aspace_e87ce30d2f3fe97b01fbb8c45f8da8d3" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5084426aee9515016aad9ff637aa8ac8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains RWDSU pension plan summary, highlights of the pension plan, statement of assets and liabilities, budget estimates, eligible retirees, proposed amendments to the plan, and staff retirement plan booklet.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_21c307c4daf4bf421ad02f2ea0ebc758" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1969" type="inclusive">1950-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_9182871df9658824300b63e43bfa6a0b" label="unspecified" type="box">26</container><container id="aspace_ed330a0c3e76b699ca449a6df62eaa25" parent="aspace_9182871df9658824300b63e43bfa6a0b" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_33b61f1689e8cf2267fd586a053c962f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains RWDSU meeting minutes from 1967 through 1969. Also contains Proceedings of the Distributive Workers Union Founding Convention from 1950.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_2dd64e4167a74a6a0ee0f7265b6c5dfe" level="file"><did><unittitle>RWDSU Convention Proceedings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_bbff7e9bdea4002331f3545b61491ece" label="unspecified" type="box">26</container><container id="aspace_111ef1a8427d7a017b6bb634d6703cfc" parent="aspace_bbff7e9bdea4002331f3545b61491ece" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7834fe499af480436a6883cc4895c427"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains copy of an 1199 News article on the RWDSU. Also contains resolutions, and correspondence and brochures regarding RWDSU Convention.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e9b68f539e67fc65e0e01d99371b6abb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Review of Union Activities</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec35b7d1dc2ea4773d333b51fbad731f" label="unspecified" type="box">26</container><container id="aspace_1083fec3518d00c1f2f677df102a75be" parent="aspace_ec35b7d1dc2ea4773d333b51fbad731f" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c1c7c504c976ac742b81411563508821"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains reviews of 1199 union meetings, each 1199 division, and the 1199 benefit plan.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_aaf206a86dbd9786d95deb1cc8c14400" level="file"><did><unittitle>Roosevelt Hospital</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_0605f96decf39caf3e00504b86cda066" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_35d9c691ea9d4fe7694f5c21df8d9983" parent="aspace_0605f96decf39caf3e00504b86cda066" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8fc33c84eab9a63450a93b41eba42e81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between lawyers, 1199, and Roosevelt Hospital regarding the collective bargaining agreement and an arbitration case between 1199 and Roosevelt Hospital. Also contains court proceedings of the arbitration case and the decision of the mediators.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_aa58cf78a4416f7d4b7b3bc4b2e062b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Roosevelt Hospital</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c1980111141e44dd3dd4ea64ca5e01a" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_fbf36c1528e31c632ded89a187ce226e" parent="aspace_9c1980111141e44dd3dd4ea64ca5e01a" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5daa069553866c9fe894a4d9982f8cb3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis and the hospital regarding an arbitration case. Also contains NLRB decision on the arbitration case.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_b3e928d97dce75be0bfc8523a25193ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rules and Regulations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1969" type="inclusive">1959-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_f60db0d72416e43a8b30c85174cadee4" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_d9731282eaf263579f5ef1ad76f5bd43" parent="aspace_f60db0d72416e43a8b30c85174cadee4" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e75f51859220b44d22747c62ab47d42d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains staff wage and employment policy, memorandum of agreement between 1199 and office employees union regarding benefits plan, clarification of rules and regulations, salary schedules and actual agreement between 1199 and the office employees union.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_416b6d399ab3b143f9eb9b0d4d7c2214" level="file"><did><unittitle>Russian Visit</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1967">1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee1baa883eefc8d07e32ff904db843f3" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_ed207f3ee21138189a795300942fd956" parent="aspace_ee1baa883eefc8d07e32ff904db843f3" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0190ed20175a0bb1f685ae3b3f881eb9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, written notes, an agenda, and receipts regarding Davis' trip to the Soviet Union. Also contains an envelope with pictures from his trip.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_91904ea56da2697fdc5f4b9ad9acc5c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Salute to Israel</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1960" type="inclusive">1957-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f97805ebf81c17687b6efaaf779afb5" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_323f6f2d633bc08e2c343a8cc6b3abeb" parent="aspace_6f97805ebf81c17687b6efaaf779afb5" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_48f4199802a5a2849cf0a8500028213b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, invitations, and flyers regarding the Salute to Israel hosted by 1199.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_d60e21ed289ced835fe637ec5b8659b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Salute to Israel</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1966" type="inclusive">1960-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_509688002a852a856249fec88d2a4aa4" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_48a04b15394594674e460483aadea5d9" parent="aspace_509688002a852a856249fec88d2a4aa4" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3d3a659435de52aa48b1ad3f52d4300e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence, invitations, and flyers regarding the Salute to Israel hosted by 1199.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_709e89b84525ddbddd5eb5579eeff538" level="file"><did><unittitle>School Decentralization</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_b0474cbb66642b22095e272aaed88f55" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_3d45a33f0d1e45b1d2bdad9bb1404c72" parent="aspace_b0474cbb66642b22095e272aaed88f55" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ce554587e9146b0e8f71040024688f28"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a plan for development of New York City school districts, a statement from a school board, and revisions to the decentralization plan.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_3b9fa387bdca174dae6e0b11d5bd326a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Senate Subcommittee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_3fe210cb1fb18adee41b8a993987e293" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_ff0417de57b50fa9915563467e0fd32c" parent="aspace_3fe210cb1fb18adee41b8a993987e293" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_525989a8ce7528afb7d20bd935508d83"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a court summons for 1199 to appear before the Senate.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_bde7ec2125674e0210780f4792559853" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sipser, Weinstock, Weinmann, and Eisner</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_f180e211630dc2d9536ef5cf4da6c7b5" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_fbab2e2d228c57581825f83f49236905" parent="aspace_f180e211630dc2d9536ef5cf4da6c7b5" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d9bf450340b64f49e5630473379c797"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers regarding legal fees and expenses and arbitration cases.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f769a13bd04518ecbff4389da69582db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Special Union Meetings</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1969" type="inclusive">1967-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_57189f852e41c387c62099aafb17f8fa" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_e254fb482ae27568092bd45be942d558" parent="aspace_57189f852e41c387c62099aafb17f8fa" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aefd701e83cacc5fb43abf0f3dcb185e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains form letters inviting 1199 members to various special 1199 delegate meetings.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_06ae672ac321c2d84f6af61e231b35a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Staff Development Program</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_bd9c85d1439a12eb88b3709bbd40accc" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_6f4b2ecbd39c8181c1f2ab1e894b460f" parent="aspace_bd9c85d1439a12eb88b3709bbd40accc" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f32fcb05e312da357e6212d896186283"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis and the Cornell University ILR school regarding a delegate training program for 1199 delegates.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ec051e97e301d79da46d52195d432905" level="file"><did><unittitle>Staff Development Program</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6208295d4e596f7c5d901b06c0a372c" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_5bb6b5a58e7f9b9dda7f4100a4803a01" parent="aspace_a6208295d4e596f7c5d901b06c0a372c" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b2236f5a7a1f1e7e5198a0b0e9c9848"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence between Davis and the Cornell University ILR school regarding a delegate training program for 1199 delegates, and regarding Cornell students visiting 1199 and talking with organizers.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ca3a108221475d1b41bcd96b39718e8b" level="file"><did><unittitle>State Department of Health</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_257ed3c5ae9e0ebf2a5f289a81bd5565" label="unspecified" type="box">27</container><container id="aspace_b6ee76329a8814da5939123e56a7b6b9" parent="aspace_257ed3c5ae9e0ebf2a5f289a81bd5565" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee8bdbcdc890980135f00452eecb0363"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with lawyers and the State Department of Health regarding the financial reports of hospitals.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_7064f01ec6739e6057fb1186d6128739" level="file"><did><unittitle>Taft Hartley Act</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_46c233e263f84648b95b6e52efb2d610" label="unspecified" type="box">28</container><container id="aspace_538878bc5850170ac7803d97ec135d15" parent="aspace_46c233e263f84648b95b6e52efb2d610" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c8a85cc1b8c29c4ae0f30117a68d3c0c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a complete analysis of the new Taft Hartley Act as well as a booklet of questions about the act, political cartoons about the act, and a summary of the act.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_92d5c89b0ddf2066cca9cb41d0f50ebe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trade Union Division of SANE</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1967">1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_f77cf5fbd7b78d4e7d94ad0ff8a23555" label="unspecified" type="box">28</container><container id="aspace_8abebd0389a19d4cc513af0f064a081f" parent="aspace_f77cf5fbd7b78d4e7d94ad0ff8a23555" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b683a355a415a3707699498f3a883b6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a ledger of cash receipts, cash disbursements, and the general ledger of the Trade Union Division of SANE.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_1c1af5b96add655723d287a90127d5b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trip to the Soviet Union</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d52a2fd818238b4994b1776d5cb9c0f" label="unspecified" type="box">28</container><container id="aspace_3c4e2cc8afb6b5f9781cd20bba7e75cf" parent="aspace_3d52a2fd818238b4994b1776d5cb9c0f" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf982497643cdae3da5f90c69b28906f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with various government, hospital and union official in the Soviet Union discussing Davis' upcoming trip. Also contains an agenda, receipts, pictures, and travel arrangements for his trip to the Soviet Union.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_e347a708a717af4d53a41c2706c813fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Union Hospital Management Conferences</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1967">1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_f62e11c188cb03ae8883d576c700ef7b" label="unspecified" type="box">28</container><container id="aspace_08be168512e46d287284a7754a3f2f98" parent="aspace_f62e11c188cb03ae8883d576c700ef7b" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc71ee6cf95ddce45dacf9c4f173bc6a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains correspondence with hospitals regarding a conference for hospitals and 1199 to get together and discuss issues. Also contains list of people who attended the conference.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a2586234f2280cdb23834e32dc3570d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wage and Price Freeze</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a0489dcb42788fe6d8f6343b60f768f" label="unspecified" type="box">28</container><container id="aspace_e29b0845b7ccef302936bbb164a92425" parent="aspace_0a0489dcb42788fe6d8f6343b60f768f" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_55034b858891d0f14f907c8da39ad6a6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains documents summarizing president Nixon's 90 day wage and price freeze. Also contains correspondence with government officials and the AFL-CIO regarding the wage freeze.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f6c0dae195fff92ca98e27e1f23572f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef4a508ede02389996d474b24529838a" label="unspecified" type="box">28</container><container id="aspace_c09336efc47a66c3a1a54806c0c89925" parent="aspace_ef4a508ede02389996d474b24529838a" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2902a4abdd3960d55c3f8ab5085a747f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a copy of the Industrial Union Department of the AFL-CIO's IUD Digest that contains an article written by Davis. Also contains an 1199 organizing flyer.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
