<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL05976mf</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm <num>5976 mf</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>August 05, 2015</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall Tower Road</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 607-255-3183</addressline><addressline>kheelref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-10-10 00:21:45 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50049424" role="creator" source="lcnaf">Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>5976 mf</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.33 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1940/1977" type="inclusive">1940-1977</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_1b63a88f1f38071ff2f7902ee84bcc84" label="Quantity:">30 microfilm reels</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_3a1cc4cba6822af4ca192829d1fe5fbe" label="Forms of Material:">Records.</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_55fc16cd488bbf7639176dceb8931782">This is Series A, Part 1 of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters records.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f7bcb7ad3456241a6f2e33275b31084b">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">5743747</unitid>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f3de482d6efb94a2810f46aa52056fb5">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters (BSCP) was, in 1925, the first labor organization led by blacks to receive a charter in the American Federation of Labor (AFL). It merged in 1978 with the Brotherhood of Railway and Airline Clerks (BRAC), now known as the Transportation Communications International Union.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f45a184a1dfc82ccaf9542bbddb6783b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e79faac2217deedfe649df0ca37438d6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_13ca9312e78a6e4ed6328c5d03249d2f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm #5976 mf. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <odd id="aspace_2ce4c5299adb38df7af7e400566b9a39">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheelref@cornell.edu">kheelref@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel">https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>Kheel Staff, March 12, 2013</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Randall Miles, August 05, 2015</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_ed0bb7df94b9c48adc6b6e860a68e8d8">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related Collections:  5462 mf: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters, Chicago Division, Selected Papers on Microfilm  6110 mf: Records of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters, Series A, Parts 1-3 on Microfilm</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Porters -- Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Employment -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
    <corpname rules="local" source="local">Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters. Lady Auxiliary</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">5743747</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_cd1ff6a1052d4e01fecbf0503d13f94b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1925-1927</unittitle><container id="aspace_860986cb49e53245deb6916ab2c144e9" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_214774906f402bc9151ba4f201079c7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. 1925. 132 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1925/1925">1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_a3eba6e1b345fc43607eb0f5722e8d7c" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_59d5d9f6c12ae12c9154fc2f31104661"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pullman Company operations and activities; tipping of porters; Pullman stock purchase plan for employees; C and W Railway schedule of wages and rules of compensation of conductors and trainmen; applications and dues; correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_603c9257a213bfc7b87a024bbcfcb77a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0133. January-April 1926. 142 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926/1926">1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_69c7beaf59cec1dc2d1557cbb86d2beb" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3662fa077183395a07e3aad6b8099b4d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Assigned working numbers for porters; financial statements; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; effort to eradicate Communist influence in trade unions; voting plan in Omaha District; applications and dues; embezzlement scandal; revision of schedule of rules and rates of pay for Canadian railroads.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c29dd7910d2d7e2121bf2ed723ffe08c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0275. May-July 1926. 106 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926/1926">1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_c4b9e6723121a07e22cbc4957a52d16d" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1c078949b22849a1c3ea387768e26f8d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Organization meetings; financial statements; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organization activities; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; dispensation for new members; dues collection; Watson-Parker Bill; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People endorsement of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_23d3ee0f00e0b57f81e8651c1e55ff60" level="file"><did><unittitle>0381. August 1926. 122 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926/1926">1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_25d82012f3fe75a7b8353a43dfbec045" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_722bab54e184ab1334fd3a26afa3cbc3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Pullman employee representation plan; organization meetings; Randolph wins libel suit against the Whip; porter grievances; financial statements; dues collection; Randolph's meeting with Clarence Darrow; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters legal expenses to Chandler Owen; questionnaires; organization meetings; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary membership drive; request for conference with Pullman; applications; attack on the Pullman Porters Benevolent Association; propaganda circulars; confiscation of employee property by Pullman; negotiations with Pullman; appointment of a National Advisory Committee of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2d51e7f21eb4a33e191e658471adff86" level="file"><did><unittitle>0503. September-October 1926. 155 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926/1926">1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_e795e05d3d773adbe22a2c3ee735bdab" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dcfceb5635beb8d2b4a5b025d99dd261"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Applications; Pullman employee representation plan; dues collection; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; questionnaires; organization meetings; porter grievances; request for conference with Pullman; suggestions on wage scale and working conditions; financial statements; reduction in membership; request for conference with Pullman; Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen's assistance to the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before National Mediation Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1532b6d5a60dabfffe91480f792c649e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0658. November-December 1926. 166 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926/1926">1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e2eb0e1b3860569463504aea4e35dd6" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca4f0e0acee266a8d80540400c9c5d49"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pullman intimidation of porters in employee representation plan elections; Chicago Enquirer's support for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; questionnaires; porter grievances; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; demands relating to wages, rules, and working conditions; financial statements; propaganda; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters hearing before the National Mediation Board; organization meetings; Pullman Porters Benevolent Association convention; applications; standing of the Pullman Porters Benevolent Association under the Railway Labor Act; financial statements; dues collection; expenses.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3f88974acb0d34868a51fc01bc6ebe14" level="file"><did><unittitle>0824. January 1927. 78 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_98f9dced1e8bc9826b035511e992a07b" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f9eba4d7e3bad7c50311498f37c6c68a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters opposition to communism; special assessment; Pullman reprisals against employees; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; organization meetings; financial statements; National Mediation Board proceedings in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_67e8aeaaf1e276ed4154264f3e8f10e0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0902. February 1927. 83 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_594f1aa230d114e965372e92076c9cdf" label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1ee5c84c2796f4d4ed01b1f799fbab64"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Propaganda; special assessment; dues collection; financial statements; changes in Pullman employee representation plan; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; membership statistics; organization meetings; National Mediation Board proceedings in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; tipping issue; National Mediation Board union representation election for Pullman porters.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_fe0bef95a3703189e3806b60665dece1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1927</unittitle><container id="aspace_6c2165b7c3f0d7bf65f3d1fa3db85c10" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><c02 id="aspace_0c18aed61f182156ad697fc5f2a3cfc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. March-April 1927. 116 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7fbf9372af67058eb2b6a186ccda3fc" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_48bdc4d88a4d5e63386791291aeb5f36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; porter grievances; questionnaires; Pullman employee representation plan; special assessment; financial statements; dues collection; propaganda; National Mediation Board proceedings in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; political situation in Chicago; reports on poor working conditions; New York Citizens Committee of One Hundred; funds advanced to discharged members; Randolph's speech to the National Urban League Conference; resignation of Ella Jones; president of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; activities of Pullman Company spies; support of Negro ministers for the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; aims of the Trade Union Committee for Organizing Negro Workers.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fa79793d33350f9350ef5f375ea8009c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0117. May 1927. 58 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_da04f3f12fdc7fd47e1583abf4021455" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_09b2d185eb0b578ab00a9d63c27b6040"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Dues collection; National Mediation Board proceedings in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Wage Board proceedings; financial statements; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; Pullman employee representation plan; special assessment.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1b8817ab84f183d53a7af1a5f2414c16" level="file"><did><unittitle>0175. June 1927. 77 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_aaa0d31ada246da240f4a39e28a9234a" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_01e7d01356259133a6b89c68063ba893"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Dues collection; special assessment; financial statements; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; wages and working conditions of Negro porters; National Mediation Board proceedings in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; endorsement of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters by the Switchmen's Union of North America; list of new members.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0a70ad61d1e970c7e3db08457c765d2f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0252. July 1927. 56 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea9d06ddb503750d8b01787a687eba34" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_18c8d4fb6f3111143ba2a189026377f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Dues collection; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; alleged National Mediation Board denial of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters request for wage increase; special assessment; National Mediation Board proceedings in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; Pullman propaganda; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; financial statements.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1765ecef50f266e48390bc0e475d2e0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0308. August 1927. 67 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_86a7699b3578395675b8c7d14293c130" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_092622e8bc88812bd347b10bc76feb57"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Applications; financial statements; special assessment; dues collection; list of telegrams sent by A. Philip Randolph; National Mediation Board proceedings in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; wages and working conditions of Pullman porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2a21c3d57c96509eee4b31d2194d4fd1" level="file"><did><unittitle>0375. September 1927. 85 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3483fb43e8a7d64bf73fbc2792d624f" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8197fd57b3838a0511c457c2b55e22e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pay rates for Pullman porters, attendants, and maids; applications; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; dues collection; special assessment; itinerary of tour by A. Philip Randolph and A.L. Totten; financial statements; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters files petition with Interstate Commerce Commission regarding Pullman case; wages and working conditions of Pullman Porters; Pullman propaganda; elections under Pullman employees representation plan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_43b5781a8778bb394550d1b15f3dba92" level="file"><did><unittitle>0460. October 1927. 77 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_a64d27a8ca8a0fb3c7deae3375de7ae7" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cbda68806022990d8d1244dcd51aa90d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Dues collection; special assessment; fund-raising activities; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; hearing of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case by Interstate Commerce Commission; financial statements; election under the Pullman employees representation plan; special assessments; list of members in the Chicago District; mass meeting; Pullman Company intimidation and propaganda.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_02d0eb974b98bee913b5cf83976a7619" level="file"><did><unittitle>0537. November 1927. 95 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc2f35120301cef0d298ef4fb3eef92c" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_418233119c881a73f888c4ac72efebb5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Applications; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before the Interstate Commerce Commission; mass meeting; financial statements; special assessments; dues collection; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Pullman Company intimidation; Pullman wage conference; organization meetings; Pullman Porters Benevolent Association convention</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8a73af588c203b7e75fbc1a96140a3f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>0632. December 1927. 81 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa36f6bb5d3460f17fb98e8fb2a6f379" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_263441457d62ef746948b0cbf925e3af"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Hearing of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before the Interstate Commerce Commission; Negro Labor Conference; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; financial statements; special assessments; dues collection; Pullman wage conference; Pullman employees representation plan; support of Chicago Defender for the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; plan to charge fee or duplicate dues and membership cards; Pullman Company intimidation.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0bd97cdcf4e9a0dc1523d77bb485be54" level="file"><did><unittitle>0713. 1927. 84 pages.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d9ed2691872e846bdf9e61ccca0b950" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dcc28b28e5d5ae29fa3f238094830fd5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Mediation of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Pullman Dispute; instructions to Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers on handling strike situation; duties of Pullman porters; program of action for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; Pullman employees representation plan; schedule of rules and pay rates for the Canadian National Railways; newspaper comments on Pullman porters wage and tip case; membership lists; porter grievances; organization meetings.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_11b21c6ecb36df306c5de5337d01ce13" level="file"><did><unittitle>0797. Membership Lists, 1927. 181 pages.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_7abdba7926430b904dcc16d5c4c3572e" label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_9dc7c8010b8b7bab8cebbe1364bcafdb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1928-1930</unittitle><container id="aspace_f8583aa958876e2f6205ba683a59459b" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><c02 id="aspace_0fc110233bed4df1cc23d65a616d9ffb" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. January-February 1928. 147 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b11638a582da23720f984db3c0fefb8" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2b5394f65cb13d7341c5457c85b7b44"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Negro Labor Conference; financial statements; proceedings in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before the Interstate Commerce Commission; conference of Brotherhood chiefs; Pullman employees stock purchase plan; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Pullman propaganda; dues collection; membership lists.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b7eb9c31ca0cfee37eb9aeae9281c070" level="file"><did><unittitle>0148. March-April 1928. 100 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_c370a1423d139c558216ede5f9f8d133" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2a8d67f2977f20ebc6e935e13f41f402"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; dues collection; conductors' wage increase; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case before the Interstate Commerce Commission; financial statements; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters strike vote; proposed resignation of Randolph to achieve Pullman agreement; mass meeting; propaganda.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1c1a79a1c2688a1081f6742312264522" level="file"><did><unittitle>0248. May-June 1928. 97 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_75b909ca811615cfdf6f498b5e82473a" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2d645f9ce9c3c53cbc250fa393f378e6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters strike vote; correspondence between a. Philip Randolph and Milton Webster; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Policy Committee conference; financial statements; Pullman reprisals against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers; propaganda; Pullman Company intimidation; amendment to the Railway Labor Act.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_241e5840c265b5a6577d02f90bb2121e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0345. July-August 1928. 108 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_45d69f820a55dbd31266c142abc7921d" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d5a9c673b1d83beda6e11e305add89d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Financial statements; new Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters oath; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Policy Committee conference; Pullman Company intimidation; Pullman employees representation plan; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Pullman propaganda; tipping issue; yellow dog contracts; Catholic Industrial Conference; endorsement of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters by the Negro Business League.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9a35bd885fe570f14349f80b10c5c2da" level="file"><did><unittitle>0453. September-December 1928. 142 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1544febae7354a63de36ca5d19d3e98" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_276120b44839541679f5752798aad822"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Catholic Industrial Conference; propaganda; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Pullman porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters insurance plan; porter wages and working conditions; yellow dog contracts; elections under the Pullman employees representation plan; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to secure statements from Herbert Hoover and Alfred E. Smith; Pullman Company intimidation; charges of dishonest practices by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organizers.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_220ae6ebcff8c72c17ce9d51fdedf13c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0595. 1929. 154 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_b83cf191a5eccf00bf2166d06b5ef988" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b114815ba44cd143ca9dd437b83d53dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Articles on the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Negro Labor Conference; relations between the Pullman Company and its porters; porters wages and working conditions; attack on A.L. Totten; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership in the American Federation of Labor; mass meeting; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters first annual convention.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aa62c4f4b4e029a9df0d335039583c64" level="file"><did><unittitle>0749. January-October 1930. 109 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1930">1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_8ab39295d0a56d34811e074d61ffc87b" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4d1f5c83f7074a24419a737f9e203e00"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Dues assessments; financial statements; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters affiliation with the American Federation of Labor; United States Supreme Court outlaws company unions; Pullman employees representation plan; American Federation of Labor notes for speakers; injunction against Pullman Company; Pullman Company intimidation.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e3eaaf59f6e8a044527b313303a9d596" level="file"><did><unittitle>0858. November-December 1930. 69 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1930">1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_20c31fa0cbcebcaef7d0cd7ca894a69a" label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6001de0298bcfbedf465af12cf5da3ac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Financial statements; injunction against Pullman Company; election under the Pullman employees representation plan; Pullman propaganda; alleged diversion of funds by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials; Negro Labor Conference; Illinois Labor Laws; American Federation of Labor notes for speakers.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_4d6382f05a53543c96ac691235d0bbf5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1931-1936</unittitle><container id="aspace_f1728ee0445bfa9cae1d001e0895806c" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><c02 id="aspace_6ef5d18abc26c5f06eb7ab861d5ce2d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. January-April 1931. 101 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_d444d7f7489b987bec5da2222f8e5842" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35c1b79b69a019df5248bb5abdc29e48"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Randolph's open letter to the Pullman Company; Negro Labor Conference; limitations on federal courts injunction power in labor disputes; American Federation of Labor notes for speakers; Pullman employees representation plan; Pullman Company spies; reinstatement of members; Reduction in forces and wages by Pullman; Illinois legislative program for labor; Kansas City mass meeting; Milton Webster's visit to West Coast.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ca869ff5198f3cc86ae97f2db5bd0627" level="file"><did><unittitle>0102. May-June 1931. 56 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_ba775877685a9e89fdf60ba919a54987" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fbe47205f08f6d564b20abb65c122c2b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Milton Webster's visit to Minneapolis, St. Paul, and Kansas City; Illinois legislative program for labor; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters recognized by Milwaukee Railroad Company; dues collection; economic plight of Negroes; Ohio passes bill outlawing yellow dog contracts; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to get injunction against Pullman under the Railway Labor Act.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_68a62316fc70653d9e786634e976ae28" level="file"><did><unittitle>0158. July-December 1931. 158 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd9fa0d96dff4e5d5fa8f1a15f20b246" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e71728b16ee65ed8e987aca5c08c6627"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Ohio outlaws yellow dog contract; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters injunction against Pullman Company union; porter grievances; Milton Webster's visits to Kansas City and the West Coast; Pullman Company spies; porters demand for eight-hour workday; porter injury claims; articles by A. Philip Randolph; duties of porters; exploitation of Pullman porters; dues collection; election under Pullman employees representation plan; working conditions; The Crisis; tipping issue; American Federation of Labor notes for speakers; index of press reports and economic supplements of the International Federation of Trade Unions.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_80a9bf6b9ad787b8858ad014ed8a8f22" level="file"><did><unittitle>0316. January-May 1932. 129 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1932/1932">1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_24549142312ee1d8dafa9fb65fc67592" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04e0bd2e6d71cb8a7b1db088f3234741"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Membership list; dues collection; limitations on federal courts injunction power in labor disputes; reduction of hours; wage decrease for Pullman porters; address by Randolph on the Negro worker in the depression; unemployment relief plan; bill for five-day workweek; tipping issue; Illinois state charter for Negro Employees Improvement Association; seniority rights; memorandum of agreement between the Southern Pacific and the Dining Car Cooks and Waiters Union; minutes of the Advisory Council on Race Relations of the Council of Christian Associations; allegations that Randolph was a Communist leader; Tom Mooney case in California.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5f705f8fc18f44c63929311daecd49c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>0445. June-December 1932. 117 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1932/1932">1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_328bcea39483f35e206069a413f2c1f9" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ac726255ae4578ecdff895871647075"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters injunction case against Pullman; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and Fiorello LaGuardia; porter wage reductions; fund-raising activities; basic work month; Randolph's address on the Negro in the trade union movement; proposed establishment of a Labor Institute at the University of Illinois; Workers Education Bureau; dues collection; Pullman Company intimidation and propaganda.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9c54aa6b094c9b8fa7de4b9d4299dfc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>0562. January 1933-January 1935. 170 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1933/1935" type="inclusive">1933-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c831d86a234bfaa7cc3e7739e0c7dac" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_caa90c2cb3453d2c9b3b0ef63ad0b9d4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Unemployment relief; A. Philip Randolph's address to the American Federation of Labor convention; membership list; dues collection; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters injunction case against Pullman; fund-raising activities; Fiorello LaGuardia's address to the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters eighth anniversary celebration; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters educational activities; list of organizations affiliated with the American Federation of Labor; conference dealing with Negro workers in relation to National Recovery Administration code.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f41df7a2c3fd392f430e432a33950ee8" level="file"><did><unittitle>0732. February-December 1935. 161 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_8610ada7c3d71deba8b33987c9e1030c" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0dc1a4a6e7516bb8bf29447fd06198a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Schedule of regulations for the Pennsylvania Railroad; discontinuance of retirements under Pullman pension plan; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organization campaign; Pullman union representation elections; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters application for American Federation of Labor international charter; dues collection; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters contribution to social progress; National Mediation Board certification of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters as official representative of Pullman porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dfca0123833e6b2793a5d5b409808333" level="file"><did><unittitle>0893. 1936. 48 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_ced80b47a74f4dd852eb748b94fe2720" label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6036c97011310898697cd7f04429113f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Dues collection; business meetings of Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; brief for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters election ballot.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_65694a51c20adbb2a83bf9fa8278d32a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1937-1940</unittitle><container id="aspace_60c1a620970862e29287f7ab81fea2e3" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><c02 id="aspace_ea1908dfae2580dafdd3d1fb44852586" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. January-December 1937. 125 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef88fec9d269832189538b085e2e3172" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_753d45671a9f969315d51e6c949207ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Dues collection; railroad retirement legislation; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Wagner Labor Relations Act; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Midwest and Detroit Regional Zone Conference; instructions for determining work hours and wage rates of porters; major features of new Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman agreement.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ee8d6de3cf25ec8a6b9b053034187be3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0126. 1937. 115 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f3cf3dc4ef3e426917b9ea11e7edfa5" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e751f51363df94b76841410e9649718a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters strike ballot; lists of delinquent members; porters' service guidebook; program for re-employment, rehabilitation, and government ownership of the railways; dues collection.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fa7a91d619a4e9c44ea63b05f7143493" level="file"><did><unittitle>0241. January-September 23, 1938. 126 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_075312d28b4b3573e8e85a141990c3cc" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5c9fca016302146fb0ce1c5dad546d5a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agreement between the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company and the Dining Car Employees' Union; seniority lists; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; in charge service; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters elections; instructions for organization committees; major features of new Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman agreement; American Federation of Labor unemployment report; constitution and general rules.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_174f55e091f2940b5c22a03e6db840ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>0367. September 24-December 31, 1938. 156 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8db8b693117690a9f0978518f0d66dc" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eb24c5863d8bed45ba8fedf7e9bf31c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Report on Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters fifth national convention activities; program of the National Inter-racial Conference of Churchmen; porter pay rates and working conditions; delinquent members; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_524f967ef02e0d7ba16cc3d91f2955b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>0523. 1939. 164 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_76f2cbbee049b83e451743a68ebef704" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f3dd7e28edd861d0ac0e3950c18aee2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Time slips; delinquent members; dues collection; union representation election for porters of the Chicago and Northwestern Railway Company; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Young Women's Christian Association Workers' Scholarship; National Conference of Negro Railroad Workers; agreement governing pay rates and working conditions between the Railway Train Porters, Local Number 20672, American Federation of Labor and the Illinois Central Yazoo and Mississippi Valley and Gulf and Ship Island Railroad Companies; seniority assignments; rules and pay rates for the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad Company; proposed government ownership of railroads; organized labor's stake in World War II; porter rest periods; health hazards; porter grievances; report of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters New York Division Fact Finding Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_90ee304c7b3fcf9068f0ec0d4d9e454e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0687. January-April 1940. 121 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb1f49cbf6284e7ebcc8cdd5827a2bc1" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_99cd46a1371354d04c7b1b1ae1538e90"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Instructions for porters on the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company; list of non-Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members in the Pittsburgh Division; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Ohio State Conference on Employment Problems of the Negro; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters labor conference in Jacksonville Division; minutes of the Keep America Out of War Congress; New York State Conference on Social Legislation; Pullman disciplinary hearing; dues collection; relief assignments.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a08408997af1a73c248583dd9240e49e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0808. May-September 1940. 105 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_965f888eec33b63fbdffe3cc0c4ed251" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3c1fdb05fba1a25c76a9a53c93943087"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Articles by A. Philip Randolph; dispute between the Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks and the Railway Express Agency, Incorporated; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; benefits under the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act; North Western Porters Industrial Organization; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention in New York City; status of the Pullman Porters and Maids Protective Association; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution and general rules.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_80abc356a41a0449833f49859249a049" level="file"><did><unittitle>0913. September 21-December 1940. 133 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_e19f6c795bab84b07733bdfa75eeea07" label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63aaa3bd827fc87f9393cd402c89b194"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Revision of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman contract; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; stake in World War II of organized labor and Negroes; increased benefits for unemployed railroad workers; illegal crediting of rest periods; brutality toward porter; National Railroad Adjustment Board decision on Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman dispute; Pullman porters convention; relief assignments; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman negotiations; pay rates for porters on the Southern Pacific; resolutions offered by the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; labor planks of the Republican and Democratic party platforms; efforts by organized labor to defeat the Patman Bill.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_0a731d998b10691c610c44b680396885" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1941-1943</unittitle><container id="aspace_8144565e9b226a60be9f6dc373ceb52c" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><c02 id="aspace_1a2c4bb42632b21f7edabc0d70ae1388" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. January-March 1941. 82 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_433c9252d3773833c5ce888295669d13" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ba57e83eaf9bd667c4739d41613fde5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: instances of discrimination against Negroes; Illinois State Commission on the Condition of the Urban Colored Population; porters' working conditions and hours; agreement between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Chicago and Northwestern Railway Company; dues collection; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; seniority rosters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary organizations; contract with the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad; Illinois unemployment compensation law; agreement between the Southeastern Carriers Conference Committee and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; overtime.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_43d6ccad0c5ca3965448ed878b607f9d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0083. April-July 1941. 95 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2182da9548c61b189508a6306eff796" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_42498b7ef2d529e2914ce7eac941de67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Overtime; National Action Conference for Civil Rights; dues collection; list of porters on the New York Central Railroad System; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; porter grievances; reports on porter operations; patterns of National Defense Mediation Board settlements.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_77c8652b766735c0982785f6263edd41" level="file"><did><unittitle>0178. August-December 1941. 107 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_97ded206dec46decd2658702b1221aef" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a52f1f3920ffdc174fdb49d87a1aaf60"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Reorganization of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; porter grievances; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Illinois Central contract; salaries and expenses; memorandum of agreement between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Alton Railroad Company; Illinois civil rights legislation; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters division heads.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ec6a33caff6be89192e8b5b3f241154c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0285. January-April 1942. 85 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_db1957e43cd518d6e597a946319f1117" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_09f6f91a19e15a62dea205a0f8f1e857"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company safety news; salaries and expenses; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Negro locomotive firemen; porter work schedule for the Alton Railroad Company; deadhead service.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_052518dd6b5b505f2380cef17195134f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0370. May-June 1942. 106 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_9fcfc8970ec402c53d2a6b9b3673bdf1" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_03fbb0630c1fae467a43467fa5186f1e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Salaries and expenses; delinquent members; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; March on Washington movement; plans for a Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters youth program; porter work schedule for the Alton Railroad Company; porter grievances.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6c83f38b51031cfe658a0e211750b5ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>0476. August-December 1942. 150 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_6bc475c614928bbf68a8d4edba388b25" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_50d4edc4619612a663f5f6c685b95df5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Victory Jubilee; memorandum of agreement between the Alton Railroad Company and the Dining Car Employees Union; Union for Democratic Action program; salaries and expenses; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention in Saint Louis; efforts to organize Negro locomotive firemen in the South; Midwest Workers Education Conference; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; National War Labor Board procedures for controlling the adjustment of wages of railroad workers; discriminatory employment practices in the railroad industry; recommendations for changes in the social Security Act; proposed national system of unemployment compensation.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bde927a67e38e856473cfe92ea66cc0a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0626. January-August 1943. 148 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_411bd7ac5a40a1c9b36cd3edd27be011" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_daec58471bacb5058f5bc778e267bba4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: International race problems; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; Labor League for Human Rights; race riots in the United States; business meetings of the Chicago division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_364f502cba7b45aedce3c31a77c1e703" level="file"><did><unittitle>0774. September-December 1943. 92 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_deb20ed5e4599c0ca5aac008595c530f" label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_57026825d5b48136a036b1dc0ebf366e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Efforts to abolish poll tax; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; group insurance benefits for Pullman employees; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters scholarship fund; Fair Employment Practices Commission directives ordering abolition of racial discrimination on southern railroads; membership lists.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_9b44d2310c9784473944a1f5aeb6187f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1944-1945</unittitle><container id="aspace_e57ad9f3f7404d9b9964aa6f2fdfb18c" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><c02 id="aspace_d6ed147032277b6118ca237f4174765f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. 1944. 152 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_b0412511bbd45bfbb1783589809f5f20" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2117f592946866d0bd19bf9a408c05c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: War Labor Board directives; Office of Price Administration food ceiling price list; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; increase in salaries for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; race discrimination; voter registration; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters resolutions; complaints against porters; President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice; porter grievances; Wallace Corporation versus National Labor Relations Board; Steele versus Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company et al; molestation case; Franklin Roosevelt's declaration on racial discrimination; employee withholding exemption certificates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d7cfb98101780b8e9ff2fca439b8c256" level="file"><did><unittitle>0153. January-June 1945. 75 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc3b2bc9fb90ca5d0bdeb3e9f8b3c8f1" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f9a303e36838eea1aea04ea5538fa90"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: National Conference of Pullman Car Cleaners and Yard Forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; transfer of dues for Illinois Central porters; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; railroad annuity pension tax; demerit system of discipline on the Chicago and Northwestern Railroad.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c713f42a9ee800052d7d93f4113d35d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>0228. July-December 1945. 86 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_a298315c03cc5f06e628c20aefea7d45" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_293ec0337b0b87f538dea93dbf94d7dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Support for United Negro College Fund; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; list of officers of the local divisions of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters twentieth anniversary retrospective; Department of Labor information bulletin; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters representation for Pullman yard and shop employees; anti-labor bills in the United States House of Representatives; wage demands of Illinois Central employees; instructions for members of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organization committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aaaa3676dbb4dee70c8d5939abf5a66b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0314. Mimeograph copies - 1, 1945. 87 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_17089e9090b5d304e4f7b15d83bd3ca6" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6d5f4c2c163f7a8b24722c4bc4e235cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: National Railroad Adjustment Board racial discrimination case involving train porters; porter grievances; Pullman disciplinary actions against porters; negotiations for paid vacations; Santa Fe Railroad porters and attendants join Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; operation of extra porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters claims on behalf of porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a918900f0dfc79bea760c29ec4fee6b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>0401. Mimeograph Copies - 2, 1945. 114 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_514bcfd850a77c16a56db2d2e0ce580e" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_24baece885d84f7a52fa37904fd8f628"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances; wages and working conditions of Union Pacific chair car men.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c554be4e58ca4ae5352c3bbadb1c72bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>0515. Mimeograph Copies - 3, 1945. 91 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a371103349feec616aeee362309b532" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c44ed241d13bea7baec27a146f2a515e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Memorandum of agreement between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Minneapolis, Saint Paul, and Sault Saint Marie Railroad Company regarding vacation allowances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul and Pacific Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; vacation pay for Aton Railroad; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters named authorized representative of porters of the Chicago and Eastern Illinois Railroad Company; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0384563f3a5791e328fd84c38fcf6665" level="file"><did><unittitle>0606. Mimeograph Copies - 4, 1945. 114 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f2d9ef91c86819f67c4024a1a2cce3e" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_57149a3f5014bc73af88a0221ce673d4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters named authorized representative of porters of the Chicago and Eastern Illinois Railroad Company; Car Cleaners and Yard Forces Conference; revision of Pullman working conditions agreement; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Pullman car cleaners and yard forces; porter grievances; porter wage agreement; report of proceedings of the National Conference of the Representatives of Santa Fe Train Porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5bafc9ceb3dc2a5d7f49fbda4c67dd09" level="file"><did><unittitle>0720. Mimeograph Copies - 5, 1945. 113 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_f84796e74b575e4ae8a5f747d7040bd6" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee7d7d96cf9b5152957c0e0323245990"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3249ff3a43e4cba70dc439e35ddcf17e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0833. Mimeograph Copies - 6, 1945. 152 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_665c2dffd9af84bf3b465616cc5a4d13" label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2fb604358463f86ec8f073ce584a9389"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_073f03efb64176e154785dd4381a3e22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1945</unittitle><container id="aspace_d06090570d826d1e147537f56feb5484" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><c02 id="aspace_ce9a0517c4fd8bc471e61beab25f0fee" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Mimeograph Copies - 7, 1945. 120 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_229e8c4e86c49f186a5a4989da31ccff" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2be9b2ce4d1e77d377cffc61b25fb16c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Porter grievances; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_35d49d89acbff77eb1f022e7c5daf0ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>0121. Mimeograph Copies - 8, 1945. 147 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d7d4595b7ab8b02d4a40a3a3e7e374f" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_174775ef53d51a5474642ee1c7e06a3b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters recognized as representative for porters on the Santa Fe Railroad; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago and North Western Railway Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_324aafed27bca662520a399b58e7914b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0268. Mimeograph Copies - 9, 1945. 132 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5ed2a07e3ba6b95cf28c8cccf6f68cb" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cfc72d285cde6095b6452d6762d3049a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Vacation agreement with Alton Railroad Company; record of number of conductors, porters, attendants, and bus boys displaced from regular assignments; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Pullman yard forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d864a784e5ff34213a30f36b292cc1b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>0400. Mimeograph Copies - 10, 1945. 135 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee198d2dfb3a57656a8afd6af225a293" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3917cef153429088b8b807922c7ad55b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago and Northwestern Railway Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Alton Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9f6726f1be24c4e166cdb6b86bf9be5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0535. Mimeograph Copies - 11, 1945. 110 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f107c1fbaccce08ff4dc146976cd678" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab64b7d646742ad8d1e6234f6a3edf1c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_efb064b7bce1e49c299c182221a0c288" level="file"><did><unittitle>0645. Mimeograph Copies - 12, 1945. 88 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d81b06f295a1f9ffd2363fcc2413811" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21c4291d693362d9177db35fad53654c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ae7535f49a7978c39a4107ea434d86a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>0733. Mimeograph Copies - 13, 1945. 125 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c9c62fc31b741ca7903a6aa856c9d18" label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_51365e4dd19b041c5ff5514cb663e908"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances; conference of Pullman car cleaners and yard forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Southern Pacific dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Santa Fe train porters and Pullman car cleaners and yard forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping car Porters- Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul and Pacific Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board. Vacation agreement with the Chicago and North Western Railroad Company; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_645328d557f609ca63a92b350a6e0c20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1945-1946</unittitle><container id="aspace_140d851f4595827401eaa1537a429f49" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><c02 id="aspace_cb61f878883cdddb1f844e4d846baf7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Mimeograph Copies - 14, 1945. 122 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_941ec769c61aabf60abd29801f4dee38" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a950eff66675df820538a1f93ad3e1d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman disputes before the National Railroad Adjustment Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9c7fe9b3bb06b2763cb0020eec2b2e5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0123. Mimeograph Copies - 15, 1945. 98 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f7be957e7364d739b6118297156cd14" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f78d7da865c12eb68505fb2e103ee3aa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_87df764890a1a5cc14fdc69dac59a15c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0221. Mimeograph copies - 16, 1945. 110 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd2e8cbd7ed7def8e9adfd7f44f7ea28" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3b6865aa9b6b60d63f9a5c11893fb45"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a034175600a44c842aec7283277afa70" level="file"><did><unittitle>0331. Mimeograph Copies - 17, 1945. 153 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_227323d26433c21f939f2499b9285352" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c8a2d2a8688607994b6a47e80f38365b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pullman disciplinary actions and hearings against porters; porter grievances; racial discrimination against porters by military personnel.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_29c1f0d9d5ac21bd563352fde4eb2c7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0484. January-September 1946. 124 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_06bdd505738647b67067484503828bc8" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f723355d9e71684b3b5fec100d61371"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago and Eastern Illinois Railroad Company agreement on pay rates and working conditions and vacation agreement; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; work hours for Pullman storeroom nonclerical employees; travel expenses; American Federation of Labor convention; amendment of Railroad Retirement Act.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_498a307790cdd589c2e366c1430f00f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>0608. October 1946. 187 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_e66e37bedbd96e8cfc8b385741d24cf2" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9c4bf7654ea16f64d0266b6c92e93c97"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor convention program; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; proceedings of the Firemen's Conference of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters in Birmingham, Alabama; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; work hours of Pullman storeroom nonclerical employees.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bff0731df9ff199a6ead02632150d3bf" level="file"><did><unittitle>0795. November-December 1946. 172 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_0901b5b065a0bdff6b53347724b03d4f" label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bef3366e9b8b07531478f8b720baf5eb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; Pullman Porters Benefit Association of America convention; furlough and recall of Pullman car service employees; list of dining car employees employed by the Chicago and North Western Railroad; National Mediation Board election for union representation of Pullman shop and yard employees; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; lists of Pullman shop and yard employees; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize Pullman car cleaners; national policy against discrimination in industry; problems of Negro veterans.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_59f2412e7531cec364d1dd2a85f7cea4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1947-1957</unittitle><container id="aspace_3f59188345b424a0576ed377812965a9" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><c02 id="aspace_0eb39a12c2e7ce3b6bc1040d87d19034" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. January 1947-June 1948. 206 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1948" type="inclusive">1947-1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4b963c4b55f49c07d486cc2e27c98b8" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7abd1c9fb504346839b8fb99d72b19cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Hardships encountered by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters porters in Saint Louis District; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; National Mediation Board union representation election for dining car employees of the Chicago and North Western Railway Company; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize dining car employees of the Chicago and North Western Railroad; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters regional labor conference in Toronto, Canada; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; Illinois Fair Employment Practices Act; list of paid-up membership in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division; list of furloughed and sick members in the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_543148ae92d92f61e1664c995b8ca613" level="file"><did><unittitle>0207. July 1948-December 1950.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1950" type="inclusive">1948-1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_269738e8c4a8eca8166f1176166d1c61" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6d26734286c9569d420f1105d0f0c6f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters elections; fight against Jim Crow in the armed forces; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters division officers; delinquent members; porter seniority list; monthly review of the Railroad Retirement Board; report of proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Southwestern Zone Conference Board; report of proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Southwestern Zone Conference; congressional hearings regarding the Fair Employment Practice commission; porter sleeping accommodations; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters negotiations with Chicago and North Western Railway company; porters' vacation schedule; vacation agreement with the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a3470a1c501149b5bbb40f1dbae10f54" level="file"><did><unittitle>0405. 1951-1952. 165 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1952" type="inclusive">1951-1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_1412930fae8db1749666816d49455ce3" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63f6003853471fd433213217f8be981f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Porter vacation schedule; dues collection; porter seniority rosters; Joint Council Dining Car Employees-Chicago and North Western Railway company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; employee passes; negotiations with the Chicago and North Western Railroad; porter sleeping accommodations; pay increase for porters on the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad; Department of the Army instructions for operations of the railroad; porter grievances; payroll deduction plan for United States savings bonds; Pullman safety record; Veteran's Readjustment Assistance Act of 1952</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3157917c96a42dc7d9d9de99ef0640a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0570. 1953-1954. 165 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1954" type="inclusive">1953-1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_063be5f2e98da69c8d4cd6778037cf62" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_97e7e3fc8bb6537d10be586d133579a2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Veteran's Readjustment Assistance Act of 1952; porters' seniority rosters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters agreements with the Illinois Central Railroad Company and the Chicago and North Western Railway Company; porter sleeping accommodations; employee passes; election for officers of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division; operations of extra employees; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution and general rules; porter pay rights.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_63301bd91d4f98a9b86340f5d62d035a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0755. January 1955-April 1957. 184 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1957" type="inclusive">1955-1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_370a79524c5e0ed9e841af637b6433df" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_924358bf218b5697f91f32fd344e3fd3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Porter seniority rosters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters regional zone conferences; operation of extra employees; financial standing of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members in Denver, Kansas City, Oklahoma City, Omaha and Saint Paul; porter vacation schedule; A. Philip Randolph elected American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations vice president; eligibility for railroad retirement annuities; porter grievances; Chicago and North Western Railway divisional territories; business meetings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division; Bbrotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution and general rules; employee passes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0f77d302ae0cd35a2179a65687cc5653" level="file"><did><unittitle>0939. May-December 1957. 146 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_ab101e799a27ded1d46e8f0ef95e38b0" label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2236cb4c700c12266a226e43021255d0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Conference; passenger train accommodations; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; status of civil rights legislation; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters educational program; George Meany's address on civil rights in the United States; porter vacation schedule.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a3288f3dfdf4c35dc185bcd745a5e756" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1958-1961</unittitle><container id="aspace_406a5436b708962b2bc433b4a7aac5d6" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><c02 id="aspace_342bcb4d7ea9bc301eab988b2b701c78" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. 1958. 196 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_e728e61cd37ab7ac18212b85d481e8ea" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f7ab37504e9810c4f5438f0a33d65db3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations convention resolution on civil liberties and internal security; porter seniority rosters; Chicago and North Western Railway divisional territories; Pullman terminates group insurance plan; Labor Conference on Civil Rights; race hate propaganda by employers; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Executive Council statements on civil rights, housing, and blood banks; porter grievances; discontinuation of Pullman agencies; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman negotiations; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights program; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People charges of racial discrimination by unions; Fair Employment Practices Commission activities.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_96ffa5c83c47bcb9fe44fd9fb6812cb7" level="file"><did><unittitle>0197. January-June 1959. 170 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_499035dbaf3a072f882c5b4385584ece" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2894a7ae13591afc6b81845d77e7490f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; National Association for the Advancement of Colored Peoples charges of racial discrimination by unions; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Executive Council statements on housing and civil rights; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights program; Labor Conference on Civil Rights; porter grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters elections; business meetings of the Chicago Division of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5e498ce5bfcd9d0213feb138dd239373" level="file"><did><unittitle>0367. July-December 1959. 165 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f84330e070efb1bab88ee96ef2d043b" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a1247d5e733e9374bab702d8fda5e917"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Problems of Negroes in organized labor; American Federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; porter grievances; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations policy resolutions on civil rights and civil liberties; members of the Railway Labor Executives' Association; amendments to Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution; list of New York Central porters; Emil Mazey's address on civil rights; segregation by unions.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4d1e6c519ebaf01452ea13decb953af5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0532. January-May 1960. 67 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5369345c86c2eefd98a7dc8fb7af207" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_99bbc160e5d2db5415043ec17f2c824c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights public relations; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Executive Council statement on civil rights; establishment of a School of International Labor Studies at American University; report on civil rights for Negroes in trade unions; porter grievances.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_574e433a27bb1e6656d748017f67ec31" level="file"><did><unittitle>0599. June-December 1960. 81 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_491cc8d599dcbc3e3f63d3bde192d940" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bdc4f6fc4c779184bc65026eab262ea8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-New York Central union shop agreement; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organization Civil Rights Committee activities; porter seniority lists; segregation by unions; civil rights resolutions adopted by Indiana State American Federation of Labor-congress of Industrial Organizations Convention; Boris Shishkin's statement at the National Conference on Constitutional Rights and American Freedom; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Southern Advisory Committee on Civil Rights.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_699ebcfd2914fbf7ed66bce9bb619a23" level="file"><did><unittitle>0680. Hearings Register, 1955-1960. 56 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1960" type="inclusive">1955-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_252a5221f9f539e9d8e6e54f71f88147" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d693b79d9f958a023f9920ecd09b069e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Information relating to porter complaints and union issues.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_647bc5478fa30771e563f131ccfbd586" level="file"><did><unittitle>0736. January-May 1961. 98 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0e076358f0df75c61eeb7b50ca95d3d" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8271f6654bb0702683d9de3a61ef2923"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Civil Rights Conference in Louisville, Kentucky; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; report on the federal executive and civil rights; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations public service programs; equal employment opportunity in federal government on federal contracts; porter rest periods; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago-Midwest and Saint Louis-Southwest zone conference.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_be14c939f4681f617300ed3af1f6b809" level="file"><did><unittitle>0834. June-December 1961. 95 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_085f4411c880026cc7c77cbc6647ade9" label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2483909fa315f7a8d355b06d822c435"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Walter Reuther's efforts to replace George Meany as American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations president; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations report on civil rights by A. Philip Randolph; Negro apprentices; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organization Civil Rights Committee activities; proposed merger of the Great Northern, Northern Pacific, and Burlington Railroads; George Meany's statement to the Special Subcommittee on Labor of the House Committee on Education and Labor; discrimination on the Canadian National Railway; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights publications; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations leaders rebuke A. Philip Randolph for creating gap between organized labor and the Negro community; President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights resolution.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_71c6cc7c4e355175db1568855ba22cce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence 1962-1969</unittitle><container id="aspace_ea42f64dd6f313f89f23ecec84bf877f" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><c02 id="aspace_493ad8420c9eb4a94d82457f3e48225d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. January-June 1962. 106 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_f50ef7172fe667df514d25a44327564a" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f89921f1e3fe46c4e9ec4b7eedd3afb8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities and minutes of meetings; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People criticism of Kennedy administration's civil rights position; state fair employment practice laws; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Economic and Legislative Conference; discrimination by an International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers union local; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations policy regarding use of segregated facilities; George Meany's testimony regarding the Federal Equal Employment Opportunity Bill; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Staff Conference on Civil Rights; porter grievances.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5a7716a7f3adb489716641276facd514" level="file"><did><unittitle>0107. July-December 1962. 80 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4e99d208d7a8066550e9ac13a936d95" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a262447663f9d83c43500a9414b9f742"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights compliance cases; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; antidiscrimination provisions in major contracts; take-over of operations of Pullman sleeping car service by the Pennsylvania Railroad; report of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board; National Association for the Advancement of Colored Peoples charges of racial discrimination by the International Ladies Garment Workers Union; George Meany's address to the Negro American Labor Council; union programs for fair employment practices; wage scale for porters on the SOO line; American Federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations progress in integration of local unions; legislative obstruction by the rules Committee in the United States House of Representatives.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6e0b12ac295a63ac3b59645c118e64d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>0187. 1963. 120 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0db40111b6a6fa2015f4587917eb28c" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc861bb8c74b37fa32add2d12722ac8d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: National Railroad Adjustment Board decision in favor of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities and minutes of meetings; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations civil rights compliance cases; death of A.L. Totten; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations policy on civil rights; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations progress in integration of local unions; search of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members by Pullman Company special agents; porter grievances; porter sleeping accommodations; operation of extra employees; Pullman disciplinary action and hearing against porter; civil rights developments involving building and construction trade.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_082bcd2089637def2465fdb6247ff62f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0307. January-May 1964. 143 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_e5565b2997aa552f80d322e726cd9fd3" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aa285c870a12e34ebccf25ed8e52a401"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Porter grievances; injury claims by porters; passenger complaints against porters; meeting of American Federation of Labor-congress of Industrial Organizations General Board; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee activities; porter time claims; Advisory Committee on Union Plans for Fair Practices.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c35aadca1a0966054dc83fb485c214c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>0450. June-September 1964. 137 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3ada247a3e15cabf1a79a1d120ca6d6" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4794b3d89ae0e465bc796b2e43294c9e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Porter grievances; passenger complaints against porters; National Mediation Board investigation of representation dispute affecting employees of the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad; Pullman disciplinary action and hearing against porter.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c51473f343443792aafb524e2df8db9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0587. October-December 1964. 89 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_214d60bd185da60287bffd18e7c3ba95" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6496c40646f3908b51d538702dfb8906"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: injury claims; passenger complaints against porters; porter grievances; report on the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations and the Negro; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Conference for Santa Fe and Union Pacific chair car attendants.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_28e69ccd9dbd66c017ff791e0b497c26" level="file"><did><unittitle>0676. 1965-1967. 208 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1967" type="inclusive">1965-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_17756ffd9040bdd408bde91f2f7b5d12" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_43997b7e632b798692e4254d7040bc7e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Mediation agreement between the railroads represented by the National Railway Labor Conference and the Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committees and their employees represented by the Employees' National Conference Committee; employment stabilization agreement; basic month; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman agreement effective January 1, 1953, revised July 1, 1965; porters' vacation agreement; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize dining car employees of the Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad; death of Milton Webster; passenger complaints against porters; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations resolutions on civil rights; Railroad Retirement Board Informational Conferences; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman union deductions agreement; minority housing problems; Illinois Committee for Fair Housing Law; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Union Pacific Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; discontinuation of passenger trains; credit legislation; 1967 civil rights bills.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_af124daab306b5b4cc9c34cb2ad7746c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0884. 1968-1969. 180 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7a6840f84ccb4e98b1ed15dc033f601" label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b18b5c9726173ccd7c66baf4a9650dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Social, racial, and educational problems in Chicago; porter seniority rosters; discontinuation of passenger trains; Illinois fair housing legislation; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations voter registration campaign; testimonial dinner in honor of A. Philip Randolph; claims for porter separation allowances from Pullman; dues collection; Labor Conference on Civil Rights; results of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters elections; passenger complaints against porters; retirement of A. Philip Randolph as Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters president; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company agreement; Jerome Miles versus Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Pullman Company.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_0fb79f896d8adbcbb7732b7b3c3c9f1a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence (Undated) and Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention Materials 1938-1975</unittitle><container id="aspace_a86c61616d3ce5c81c2b9f0d16e17a70" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><c02 id="aspace_410d48f351abacb05c8ba09964b1d522" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Undated Items (1). 99 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><container id="aspace_bfe95aa4af61234bf74bdf921b368506" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f69111c1c04dd91097d36c2d4f42d24"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Pullman porters' grievances; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board; list of Chicago busboys and attendants; union representation for porters on the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul, and Pacific Railroad; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad Company agreement; A. Philip Randolph's speech at the First Baptist Church of Memphis, Tennessee; alleged raid by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters on jurisdiction of Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters divisions; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a074e67f87f47ff7885edf461ba99274" level="file"><did><unittitle>0100. Undated Items (2). 143 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><container id="aspace_b6fe8a654f84fdec4f9a87b885617101" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_620b03263f0c6592c7e86b4a05ed3d25"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; union representation election for porters on the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad; mediation of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman dispute; state public utility laws; creation of Illinois Fair Employment Practices Commission; in charge service; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership lists.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c33d2c3a317db085ac5aa335f67de347" level="file"><did><unittitle>0243. Undated Items (3). 104 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><container id="aspace_a450b89f3e6ffe9c7b8cdaa16434d55c" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd7eeb93add85668ad0b3df8afd89d1a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters volunteer organization committees; lists of men contacted by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters organization committees; delinquent members; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters local division officers.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e3f5e643a4900ef1acfa1bb4fd01017e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0347. Undated Items, 1940-1947. 275 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1947" type="inclusive">1940-1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3538e21ee49c01c05690c82c45b23c3" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5954acd20cd059b3a8a08fe223888be5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; discrimination against Negroes by the railroads; Pullman activities to aid the war effort; union representation election for Pullman yard and shop employees; Pullman Company records donated to Newberry Library in Chicago; American Federation of Labor support for Negro workers; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters propaganda; report on Negro pioneers in the Chicago labor movement; proceedings of the First National Convention of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ca616084bbd4aba24dbba75fe3f356ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>0622. Notebook: 1938 Convention. 140 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_be55713a5be08616e660c40b91dda40d" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8137be573f293a7c38781e0b02874fd8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Fifth National Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on September 19-24, 1938.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_37c595538b85fd92f8d962f77df95d4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0762. Notebook: 1940 Convention. 276 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_402c127c652e866b57eba77cd9d39e85" label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_badbbc1b701a281e0851126d948d5ab6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report on the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in New York City on September 15-20, 1940.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_f08d65232b07a61a57fb155cf8d9f281" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention Materials 1938-1975</unittitle><container id="aspace_3924879dfe282e6240b00bfe3f939841" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><c02 id="aspace_51f8991b75caf6b476bdad1edf19b88d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Notebook: 1942 Convention. 80 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_57eef25723cbe7fd093c5ed5b821c335" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b091c15d188c8547827c8315d671979b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Saint Louis, Missouri, on September 13-18, 1942.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_48cb670b5ea31f64ce487e48d31a0bbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>0081. Notebook: 1944 Convention. 113 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce0201b294c73b94c68ec33c0b0a31c6" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8ecf25cca939a891496591bfec79ea7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Cleveland, Ohio on September 17-22, 1944.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_af0d92e4615768f700353cc2ab2a00dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>0194. Notebook: 1946 Convention. 144 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_15e305a39fe4f9f34b7dc3a059c395b0" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f74ac67182e342fe5832431743c4592b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois, on September 16-20, 1946.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6ef153b2eb6e54b7dc2e7da4bb3d01bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>0338. Notebook: 1948 Convention. 117 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_eba5543e44e7db6631916e683309d78a" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e18b5a5c5ea063d335c7340128548c4c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Detroit, Michigan on September 12-17, 1948</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0752337d00ecd6e74bfdcbce7cc760aa" level="file"><did><unittitle>0455. Notebook: 1950 Convention. 162 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e567ac16f3ae3bd5dc66f6721d4a43c" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9409c4fb3c16c8e941fd4b2ad53a60aa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in New York City on September 10-16, 1950</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3c9e7ae420d0a203669f7ac37893daa0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0617. Notebook: 1953 Convention. 120 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_f65ea34c8bac62599d254030627e2ac1" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ef3bf515d001ed75cbaf5d0d3e06fef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Los Angeles, California on October 4-9, 1953.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8e5173d872a31ab95f9a131aff61316c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0737. Notebook: 1956 Convention. 141 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_f73e2e85af7f75c33f74e634dd67bca1" label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_795fd3dd9ac79b4985ccbf95b9b4f31e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Saint Louis, Missouri, on September 10-14, 1956</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_4ee8d2e73317c71a72ab9574db402b92" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention Materials 1938-1975</unittitle><container id="aspace_d16d78c61eb8875ec6d0a4f8ba016677" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><c02 id="aspace_87abc59fbf07666c1e38e4aef10eae5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Notebook: 1959 Convention. 155 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_6981ab83605ef9d4bac8093ea84f09c5" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e9ed27ba96499281c5d3cea9d76156fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on September 6-11, 1959</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f7608b4839526209377c0948f0b73a66" level="file"><did><unittitle>0156. Notebook: 1962 Convention. 147 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_21d35e9a91312635e380607d6b7e8d21" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d16156a56ce7c896d95dde1d92e87c53"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Montreal, Canada, on September 9-14, 1962</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_15de70f9f37b1168499111b58a80d1a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0303. Notebook: 1965 Convention. 154 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8923d6f07281e5189e42bed67f1bc0d" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bccaf7e2fdd5524b3cf43dbe972988f3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on September 12-17, 1965</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_72dd960a3fed7e84386d41121aa10293" level="file"><did><unittitle>0457. Notebook: 1968 Convention. 63 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b4a894b89f165239acf17e6e2762d3d" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b0c387ac5b631b9114715e174ca43866"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in New Orleans, Louisiana on September 2-4, 1968</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0ee6eeb7b7150eb4e2e1ed66c65229ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>0520. Notebook: 1971 Convention. 103 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_605578c3cbc233ea1e8fb5b153a072a0" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a335b66558b6e01b4307463850a94556"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on September 13-15, 1971</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f746a0040de4660def88b0f66cb81f07" level="file"><did><unittitle>0623. Notebook: 1975 Convention. 82 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_9990f0b2c001c8083f6139716a30cf22" label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8b0ce0bc1bb7231912785fcdbe8cd2e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the proceedings of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Convention held in Chicago, Illinois on August 25-27, 1975.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_4bb35262c3c76e20b602aeda9066e246" level="file"><did><unittitle>International Executive Board 1948-1955</unittitle><container id="aspace_fbc5083d36965b2ed19bddd680ec7fa2" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><c02 id="aspace_3ee54a78f1e2eabf418b7ff3df85e942" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. International Executive Board Minutes (June 3-4, 1948). 23 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_47675c6755472ff34d6a687761249a36" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7b3e17bac37ade408868e860cb4377cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Detroit, Michigan; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters finances; rules on assignment of runs to districts, temporary discontinuance of an assignment, overtime pay rates, and pay when used on layover or relief days; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman vacation agreement.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a338b15687b05fa9232ff8dd84920c50" level="file"><did><unittitle>0024. International Executive Board Minutes (September 19, 1948, Post-Convention). 51 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9683b74d93cbef36df3706f9ed8d068" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eede431045c1fa70a48b6e0cee4df329"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; resolution to provide protection for international officers after retirement; procedures for press releases; railroad passes for porters, preparatory time; porter sleeping accommodations; report on storeroom nonclerical employees.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e48227e37be53d1664ad9b42f9d11c7d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0075. International Executive Board. 1948 [Correspondence]. 50 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_b0c3c1183cf52caedd4e782beb109af7" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b41dc4df9872f668b10252b1f3631977"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters finances; arrangements for International Executive Board meetings.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9d0f4d21639798a50d4029a9bd547cb0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0126. International Executive Board Minutes (April 18-19, 1949). 15 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_50428291a8701224d3368f16ee934b92" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f6d0fe814f3aeed86cf0ef0aeb56da7c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in New Orleans, Louisiana; request for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial support for the Americans for Democratic Action; memorandum of understanding regarding rules on overtime pay rates and pay when used on layover or relief days; report on storeroom nonclerical employees.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_28b3bf7d4079361671d8f231d4862cbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>0140. International Executive Board Minutes (December 5-7, 1949). 41 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ab9076bbc84128d85d8c443d35779fb" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23d79549786e47d280d3a3e29ba78f5a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman vacation agreement; memorandum of understanding regarding rules on overtime pay rates and pay when used on layover or relief days; conference between Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Internal Revenue Service officials regarding income tax charged on tips; special presentation on education for the Negro; request for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial assistance for the National Farm Labor Union.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a76cceff9df80f82a43806e0c9d28584" level="file"><did><unittitle>0181. International Executive Board. 1949 (Presentations/Retirement Plan). 48 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_10e296e7f387ca11fc75f537fc30175d" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70736390caa49ac8921864ca170af0c3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Requests for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial assistance for Bethune-Cookman College and the National Farm Labor Union; special presentation on Negro education; analysis of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters pension retirement plan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dd8c516330c0eeaa8f9436867ddac840" level="file"><did><unittitle>0229. International Executive Board Minutes (September 8-9, 1950, Pre-Convention). 51 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_ffd9364ed5cf5cafd2122899ea691486" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e47f6efa02dccf708299ae26d2f9a840"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Abolition of Pullman porter quarters; sign-out rule; minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in New York City; report of Budget Committee; report of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9877bf476f6986b408f12b66d3a29973" level="file"><did><unittitle>0280. International Executive Board Minutes (September 15, 1950, Post-Convention). 13 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_3521bf5a544ac7dc7a573d95cb31aaa4" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b50a3b0bf80860f7e354f4cb54a9e4c4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in New York City; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial statements.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_41f0a23fc9ba8bcaa741cb281df6f0ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>0293. International Executive Board Minutes (May 14-16, 1951). 26 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_760b5b3cc5ea902ca50a7f1d9759c475" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b72f6998884f3c969aa55dbb6e2201e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Request for increase in salary of officers of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report of Budget Committee; proposed change in rule dealing with hearings for Pullman rules violations; proposed Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters pension plan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8172c07b55ab3cb391e97892a07dfaad" level="file"><did><unittitle>0319. International Executive Board Minutes (December 3-5, 1951). 21 pages.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_7388c6f6d997fd3fd757ba9e91065b33" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_27ef46917c1fe48211cb4fb09edb58e8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; proposed Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters pension plan; report of Budget Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1f72d5dee42b76a9f3d520624f9da49d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0340. International Executive Board Minutes (May 5-7 1952). 65 pages.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e6ba44593577ca2d20283ed79df4793" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04df98a929d98bab25ce8fdd9c19ee51"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board Meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report regarding selection of site for the 1953 convention; report of Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d6d842be4620dc830a492319ea7d04ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>0405. International Executive Board Minutes (December 1-3, 1952). 19 pages.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_80b44e1d4f97f994422c56be309eaecf" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_22ad21ad0a91e1420817dff624cda271"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b21c2dc548c9c496b58df498b6b97e0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0424. International Executive Board Minutes (Correspondence, 1952). 43 pages.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b30a44a1ee722d7875d7cc91bc2cc38" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_effc6c4e9b3ad3595bc40eff95308a1b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Selection of site for the 1953 convention; A. Philip Randolph and Norman Thomas's plans to visit to Japan; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meetings; reorganization of the Negro Labor Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_eb53cd47802d3e8e842b7eca99ee8af5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0467. International Executive Board Minutes (Financial Reports), 1948-1952. 77 pages.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1952" type="inclusive">1948-1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_4127bbce24888bdecc8333ce353b3999" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7d08845732dba6d43d9a492fed1280b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Financial reports on the status of dues-paying members in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters divisions; annual tax payments received at International office; breakdown of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters expenses; statements of receipts and disbursements.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e959a0e1c6b5405fce8f3465b9aa40d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0586. Meeting of the International Executive Board (September 1953). 14 pages.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_70da29854a2042c19fc4d9034f1bc06a" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_01f7bce383a4d5627b22d999b24bc7c7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d9f3a3b163a33b811524eba45c8c0a6c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0600. International Executive Board Minutes (October 2 and 10, 1953). 7 pages.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_bbe30e9d4e34c651e2e4795f808520e4" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5aac2abe8ded5cd68bc050a2dbaaf4ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Los Angeles, California.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f10a9e0a4434786b8c154a9921948f0e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0607. Report of the International Executive Board to International Convention (October 1953). 122 pages.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_016eaafcde02b5950871d252c38a015a" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c36f925e1301447f042e655304c10213"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Report of the International Executive Board to the Los Angeles convention; membership status of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters divisions; resolutions adopted at the Los Angeles convention; pensions for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters leaders.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dd0eaf44e612a90078074a1b0da59de9" level="file"><did><unittitle>0729. International Executive Board Meeting (May 3-6, 1954). 39 pages.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2c430944fa7d103875f32fd07171c38" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9e431104fdb0fc5732b9e9b2591bdc31"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda and minutes of International Executive Board meeting; report of Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_db8eec48601675b63a4917070f4f426a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0768. Supplementary Board Minutes (Meeting of May 3-6, 1954). 74 pages.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_7364b7aa7821771030f1bd44f75a816b" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4350abdd00561a93ee931e8dd859ef08"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; hearing on petition for reinstatement of Claude E. Grooms as Second Vice President, Chicago Division.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cabdc29c03bd599ff67039e4cc40b163" level="file"><did><unittitle>0842. International Executive Board Minutes (December 6-8, 1954). 13 pages.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_3df520f2fcf78c343f738d54a190b9d0" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4f37be0b34f4a77deaed3244fe990c8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4bf76f9fb8fa8a0e45f25e12664e5aa5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0855. International Executive Board Meeting (December 6-9, 1954). 47 pages.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb80b3b45b03ae2d88c145c4734e9587" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04c424592da2698e8c99f234e0d8d481"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Changes in Pullman Company practice of classifying and handling parked railroad cars as station duty; operation of extra employees; request for increase in pensions for retired porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary activities; agenda and minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; porter sleeping accommodations.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_122c98446a6407ba7b5fe572b10ad189" level="file"><did><unittitle>0902. International Executive Board Minutes (May 16-18, 1955). 12 pages.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_6215b530171d1186991a03138e6f6994" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf803bb2c4b8c9876957309c3150f24e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c7c2ffed259ae0b0e1f98d630bc2dc4a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0914. International Executive Board Meeting (May 16-18, 1955). 49 pages.</unittitle><unitid>23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_152a7d91f474827e921551c6d168d97a" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_016d442f0adef6de12b3b29cf0ba5fea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Death of Jack Mills; minutes and agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d06f31ec26c54d51af48840b0439dc82" level="file"><did><unittitle>0963. International Executive Board Minutes (November 27-28, 1955). 12 pages.</unittitle><unitid>24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_1988ff7651d997199b7a5b8684114393" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_289aa1a670c1da7decd9518bd3d1f689"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e341b0d45780b8043da07a2d896b1f6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0975. International Executive Board Meeting (November 27-28, 1955). 30 pages.</unittitle><unitid>25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_8077a99c91ffd0c68d2c003280cc2d25" label="unspecified" type="reel">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a74e2a86663d9743395726372d875ecb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report on reallocation of runs.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_0fd4a214bb049e6dc95e4ac423928a1c" level="file"><did><unittitle>International Executive Board 1956-1964</unittitle><container id="aspace_6ef5928f7d191b8fb3e59da3923170dd" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><c02 id="aspace_cefedb6a8d6f3593be969aea76dc4ddc" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. International Executive Board Minutes (May 7-9, 1956). 43 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_58828e07ba2c8d048a84ec24e88922b9" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca22e750631921aff841f76ea97e5c5f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_59bdbc8ce6f38d2feefbfbbf38323f24" level="file"><did><unittitle>0044. International Executive Board Minutes (Pre-Convention Meeting, Post-Convention Meeting, Special Meeting - September 6-14, 1956). 44 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_f710cc0211224b9c393aaf7dfaec71ff" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8dc94392b7381664e268ab91e025f8e8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meetings held in Saint Louis, Missouri.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2cf284c49e39bd639cea7dde9b17e44" level="file"><did><unittitle>0088. Meeting of International Executive Board (September 1956). 32 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_67954bcd671dbbb8c5d13d2c23f170db" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25471ad41d5081be17be6cd1a3286d51"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda and minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of Finance Committee; reorganization of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; International Executive Board report for 1953-1956.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fe0454ae446008d43468921373702468" level="file"><did><unittitle>0120. 1956 Convention Expenses - 2nd Triennial (1956). 7 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf5e3559383bc17481fb2b1d3dddcd65" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5bccee8bb855057fe2bb0b2fd465e81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Receipts and expenditures of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters 1956 convention.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f1650e07b21fe8598145889e71f70e83" level="file"><did><unittitle>0127. International Executive Board Minutes (May 6-8, 1957). 18 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac9585a9a9ab9ff2e044d90bf94c174b" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_27341b9c910c1235fdd57a38bc38fa60"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aa87101335f49e7c8e7bbb5ddd457963" level="file"><did><unittitle>0145. International Executive Board Meeting (May 1957). 43 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_4dd58608e0a52937ab92c702369c5059" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c9385f36f2dddd3358713b043e892980"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of the Finance Committee; vacation pay; Milton Webster's objections to election of A.R. Blanchette of Canada to International Executive Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0a7153e1e0f7d252ad40cdaea099ce26" level="file"><did><unittitle>0188. International Executive Board Minutes (December 16-18, 1957). 33 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_876c0bb7544d4733ccb1509a188cbf36" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_13b4129f9cd71841653bd14c4feb1f29"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d923f597a61417d08b4a85d20ca5b57e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0221. Meeting of International Executive Board (December 16-18, 1957). 40 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_33ab2641cc66a236834f989f2cfbf111" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_84f1da7bce9c95b9ea73771fcbe3ab3c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Vacation pay for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters office employees; report of the Finance Committee; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; request for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters financial assistance for the United Negro College Fund; agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c03fb71b327117e94ab840d34a01bce5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0261. International Executive Board Minutes (June 2-4, 1958). 33 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_088d754a441441ec46c3281b82ba8219" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca4d0e052e64243bf34d0e7ffccd5041"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f7b886ed0d774d59c81133b86f5247b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>0294. Meeting of the International Executive Board (June 2-4, 1958). 28 pages.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_39923eb904d4f015e01c94ac68307846" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8695a9dd491ed08ab5111bc05094c12b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8a4f5720763924aafda446661554a183" level="file"><did><unittitle>0322. International Executive Board Minutes (December 10-11, 1958). 17 pages.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e9a641b3597fe39fe77754038ea4e6a" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60361a68970fde2eb1db15baf50460f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9615985350a2b5dc5673079640f03948" level="file"><did><unittitle>0339. International Executive Board Minutes (December 8-11, 1958). 86 pages.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_42da15dc2615ebc50d5a9dd7f950f824" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8a513cfb6db41f1d85de49b9454a0c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; recommendations by international officers of measures to bring down Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters operating expenses; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters finances</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_054281091c0a9aa2de3f49b905d55744" level="file"><did><unittitle>0425. Executive Board Correspondence (1958). 76 pages.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_7562e25c3283fcd49c7ce4a744b61d60" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3d53a8bcb0a91cd05a6fbf342703e6b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meetings; plans for investment of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters funds; plans for changing methods of handling Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters auditing; voter registration drive; opposition to "right to work" law movement.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7258b670de2ff9074a80a78e83080555" level="file"><did><unittitle>0501.Addresses [of] International Executive Board Members (1958). 6 pages.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_db0b8147284e449dfe3199b6a36f7b5a" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6638c7191ec6f455878a9b0fe62e8aaa" level="file"><did><unittitle>0507. International Executive Board Minutes (May 4-6, 1959). 19 pages.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef9230f7276174fc32bb3025d4563b92" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af25fbf9171c3bc6b6225409e385c3ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b034f4fa6a2a27aec31c4839a0af055f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0526. International Executive Board Meeting (May 4-6, 1959). 26 pages.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_e7757d6afa998ac7f4a54f8d4ac632d0" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b277d04aaacd3e3fe9a028121b8e6a12"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a9e8378f3684b7f1b30c2e7873630de3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0552. International Executive Board Minutes (Pre- and Post-Convention, September 1959). 15 pages.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_61964eb6ef42098c77dffef329fcd23a" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a251f9c69ff8013fd3304165a4b2936d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b8468fb53d43ede96f6b4b88524c2f0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0567. International Executive Board Meeting (Pre-Convention, September 11-13, 1959). 74 pages.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_79b60afe8b34a3fd0b8a3ffb6c60af66" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dcc04e81e4b7cc915be792b7cc6fcb2d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters statement of receipts and expenditures; agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; revision of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution; report on Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board; recommendation to raise dues.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1bd44885304a4f524fcb20d95e7a1580" level="file"><did><unittitle>0641. International Executive Board Correspondence (1959). 56 pages.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad98cbfdaacfd63f76b06a55e14be3f1" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9fbb22c210d17b9cd91fd10b4e990676"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters contribution for Committee on Political Education; report on interest rates on government bonds; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; dues collection; revision of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution; financial problems of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Los Angeles Division.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_00f90f65357759273dda3fda27345374" level="file"><did><unittitle>0697. International Executive Board Minutes (May 31-June 2, 1960). 14 pages.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_25b2fb20b8097360a10d8d9d05fcf965" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b1f5053131e070c11ddf1b54554b423"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b0d18e5fcb96fed16696e343e11dce9e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0711. International Executive Board Meeting (May 31-June 2, 1960). 62 pages.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_498fe4c70ef7799062c1d00eb148ac37" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_137aaee917f4d4f2a91b5c71bd3c9475"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters finances; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; salaries of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters employees; agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; reduction of per capita tax and assessment to the American Federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations; assets and liabilities of the International Association of Railway Employees; report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cfeeb74ccb043d992aa41bf7728d82d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0773. International Executive Board Minutes (March 27-29, 1961). 54 pages.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_b48c4d78fc7a54e16f9f31ffa666201c" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_438f8d6ee338b51ebbec0709de2b4db0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cad562f402c012032dce082ca093ac8b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0790. International Executive Board Meeting (March 27, 1961). 54 pages.</unittitle><unitid>23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_52a5997be0fe608f4e03c4545431cd9b" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f8c364877a48b3f069a77ae94dd7d5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaint by dining car union regarding Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters raids on their employees; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of the Finance Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9271e2b5df5dffdc816f83b00b458929" level="file"><did><unittitle>0844. International Executive Board Minutes (December 1-2, 1961). 12 pages.</unittitle><unitid>24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ff238d05a72fbd7bfeadce22ac67067" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c71ef954b6af97bfd51905a923036418"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_12b8f49394d4260da346e0d7a584497f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0856. International Executive Board Meeting (December 4, 1961). 34 pages.</unittitle><unitid>25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5f5cd0be194daffb28c7177b995d816" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fa70a8f9df8a01bf0395e5387cf57910"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting and convention; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations group accident and disablement insurance plan; agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters statement of receipts and disbursements.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ddf862ff7978a28ebfd4cc92c437e0f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0890. International Executive Board (Reduction of Hours-February 16, 1962). 11 pages.</unittitle><unitid>26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_86e34e02bddceddb0dea64e12b212bb5" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96b132d1176f0647e84250fb85887665"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda and minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters plans for reduction of basic monthly hours.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_20dab2207cfecb28b33840f3d80beb31" level="file"><did><unittitle>0901. Meeting of International Officers (Reduction of Hours - May 10, 1962). 2 pages.</unittitle><unitid>27</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_96c41edbbab1a9e46521a7148a87572e" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66cd99bb5aa0ad7d22638ee7bcd4b57d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5c2d019b3503bb1a33cf4212be544d3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0903. International Executive Board Minutes (September 7, 1962). 13 pages.</unittitle><unitid>28</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4799af00eab9eba8201dfb0d92227b4" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_428d925c8833c8994f65e2cf36af43a1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Montreal, Canada.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f920e1f2899b196715d89333861acb85" level="file"><did><unittitle>0916. International Executive Board minutes (June 3-4, 1963). 13 pages.</unittitle><unitid>29</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_65e9cc5856fde8a1bc0cd0b1195c9dd2" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_debac2e9bfb0a3dac8119f8823d98868"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_414ff54a081f4bcc6e0f8a57998aa40f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0929. International Executive Board Meeting (May 31-June 4, 1963). 10 pages.</unittitle><unitid>30</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_f03cd56bd5de7481d54cb1c75910dc42" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd3b5b4e62ea62dd64e6537b5f2d897f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; proposal for revision of proration procedure.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f7f4a579a59e5714bf9c785392ecffad" level="file"><did><unittitle>0939. International Executive Board - General Correspondence (1963). 24 pages.</unittitle><unitid>31</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_0babcc28dc433037bd64e3e25b36f372" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96bc7a1da4cd819bfb6bd4afe221f98e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Death of Ashley L. Totten; appointment of William H. Bowe as Acting International Secretary-Treasurer; readjustment of salaries for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials; arrangements and agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters proposals for shorter work month, pay increase, and job stabilization program.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f3b7ea3b8146c7c86559ea04cba35782" level="file"><did><unittitle>0963. International Executive Board Minutes (January 7-9, 1964). 13 pages.</unittitle><unitid>32</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f8f5743fc077d5824ddc84199dbb088" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25c76349959e86363a5904ace37298d9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Special assessment for building Brotherhood Fund; minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_86714c35db0e18c4823cc60c41595010" level="file"><did><unittitle>0976. International Executive Board (1964). 25 pages.</unittitle><unitid>33</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0e2deec092ffd69b688fda4e706098a" label="unspecified" type="reel">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ecf4e2953e1d5a448ca01e3b44f872f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Proposed Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters sponsorship of a middle-class housing development; agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_d6898f7b8d459e91f81ac1fdd5189585" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1941-1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_eb2bca938944966eaa114201e74c418f" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><c02 id="aspace_4c9b158af33778a37388d686ce81a880" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (June-September, 1941). 285 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_574c7f2ff88599c54287cc72c2a6ed47" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_823c207eb8b3e404c07983618529ffb2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Executive order reaffirming the policy of full participation in the defense program by all persons, regardless of race, creed, color, or national origin; Milton Webster's appointment as member of the Fair Employment Practices Commission; plans for integration of Negroes into national defense jobs; creation of the Labor Supply Branch of the Office of Production Management's Labor Division; complaints regarding discrimination in national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; government procurement policy; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; antidiscrimination clause in defense contracts.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b0a779fdebef45976f6942edd56470fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>0286. Fair Employment Practices Commission (October-December 1941). 168 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce32ff0fa56b20d73e9571b846a8db70" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d8905e0889d33ae1bb7681ac283a80f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; antidiscrimination clause in defense contracts; Twin Cities Conference on the Training and Employment of Negroes for National Defense Industries; problems of Negro veterans; National Defense Mediation Board activities; labor disputes affecting war production; exclusion of Negroes from service in the United States Navy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4997f334875435e53915d33f26ca4e14" level="file"><did><unittitle>0454. Fair Employment Practices Commission (1941). 77 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd0d5c7205417bc2646b663a9f7ff9a8" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_02ebfb283b9d89f3f0123e9637f56179"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Efforts of Negro women to obtain jobs in industry; notes of defense work available for Negroes; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program; antidiscrimination clause in defense contracts; business training for defense; Fair Employment Practices Commission pamphlet on minorities in defense industries; schedule of bids received from the army and navy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3663b0abe8b971b0d5df02f47f66830f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0531. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-February 15, 1942). 129 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_616f35c28cdc9139c804aa57ccab4bad" label="unspecified" type="reel">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8eb8d0cb95f947c4ffed2947bb85ba54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; labor's assistance of national war effort; efforts to increase number of defense workers; war labor disputes; establishment of the War Production Board and the National War Labor Board; resignation of Mark Ethridge as Fair Employment Practices Commission chairman; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meeting.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a8608c03365417b92e92e20e2f0f2fad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_fb43b7cf953a07abc47ee1871d8a5279" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><c02 id="aspace_08a1bfb8a93ce4e458e17543f4702764" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (February 16-17, 1942). 614 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_6fe67776ef9cc62a2ddee91ba515768e" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db177845c574be3d7e105a828a343bfc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Negro employment and training; March on Washington Committee; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings in the New York metropolitan area.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e90c90c5a8a542838ecb42a0d763471d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0615. Fair Employment Practices Commission (February 18-March 1942). 109 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d4b56dd6107fdbeacbe7db2bcd45b51" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_52ae8e88381db57c90522a74bd0508d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Summary of compliance with Fair Employment Practices Commission findings by firms in the Chicago area; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; proposed elimination of questions relating to race on government employment applications; appointment and tenure of Fair Employment Practices Commission members; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; preliminary report on defense training.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c228d3ff9c36cfc4293273465b9e68a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>0724. Fair Employment Practices Commission (April 1942). 262 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7bfd15a279361579c4f9884a88288ee" label="unspecified" type="reel">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db5e7fa365e28168af79c9c65d1d3a3b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; report on the Negroes in the defense industries; labor market problems; Negro employment and training; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings; United States government policy and instructions to ensure full utilization of labor supply.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_d1ac69dc6450762a8c6aeed94406b491" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_254bbeb579728416c731bfeb4fbfdd95" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><c02 id="aspace_410604c647f82fd4a23dca3b1db3e9af" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (May-June 15, 1942). 168 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd638322f4a9606b40fd070ad1f8aa93" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00bec2894e5e56f57fb611659c9b22cd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; elimination of practice of introducing discriminatory specifications into employer orders; United states government policy and instructions to ensure full utilization of labor supply; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings on Negro discrimination in the South; memorandum to Fair Employment Practices Commission submitted by representatives of the Southern Negro Youth Congress; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3459197afe139e021b3fb664088a6189" level="file"><did><unittitle>0169. Fair Employment Practices Commission (June 16-30, 1942). 149 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_d7affab9b27e6b74f27f00c398d62f64" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_500d4cbbc3ca63334659791211301446"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Summary and findings of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings on Negro discrimination cases in the South; minutes and report of the Negro National Defense Committee; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; United States Employment Service discontinuance of separate employment offices for whites and Negroes; Titeflex Metal Hose Company case; defense training courses for Negroes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_48d1b4c84802939635aedd3ea43f6a10" level="file"><did><unittitle>0318. Fair Employment Practices Commission (July 1942). 237 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_501591642ed8a082ae47f867676479fa" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cbdc480984e85eef5aa7ab34d3b2d418"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; United States Employment Service discrimination policy; occupational deferment under the Selective Service System; list of government-owned, privately operated ordnance plants; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; list of Fair Employment Practices Commission members; summary of compliance with Fair Employment Practices Commission findings by firms in the Chicago area; summary and findings of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings on Negro discrimination cases in the South, Fair Employment Practices Commission clipping digest; proposed congressional act to prohibit employment discrimination; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; employment of Negroes by the United States Civil Service Commission.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_382d6c87aa32087ddb3bf0e34b51f787" level="file"><did><unittitle>0555. Fair Employment Practices Commission (August 1942). 199 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a299be68f70018ad397680b3e99f4bc" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ca3901879c75bb941de08c3b7748be1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Emancipation Day celebrations in Canada; Fair Employment Practices Commission relationship with War Manpower Commission; Fair Employment Practices Commission findings in the Titeflex Metal Hose Company case; Fair Employment Practices Commission functions and jurisdictions; report on Hispanics in the war effort; racial discriminations in the South; United States Employment Service discrimination policy; discriminatory practices of railroad companies against Negro labor; report on national defense migration; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; progress report of the Bay Area Council Against Discrimination.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0f8b124d76789a9e5de8e6cad2877e9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0754. Fair Employment Practices Commission (September 1942). 143 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_df253a5dda9a9bae9874b5f77ddbc01d" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ff6549543d15c64240baa462137a55e9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Discrimination against Negroes by railroad companies and unions; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; materials in the National Archives relating to labor and labor problems; seniority of white and colored trainmen; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meeting.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5fb14369e0fa169f211a2d93c88e4c37" level="file"><did><unittitle>0897. Fair Employment Practices Commission (October 1942). 183 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_07c0f48783f18af5f129b4e2dbc79aba" label="unspecified" type="reel">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7c84c7c8e2a12be4804f243a08e80700"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Relationship between the Fair Employment Practices Commission and the War Manpower Commission; discrimination against Negroes in the railroad industry; list of labor organizations having constitutional provisions disqualifying Negroes from membership; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meeting; summary and findings in Fair Employment Practices Commission cases.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_82ce7cff65076ee47aa5ff2323c2276f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1942-1943</unittitle><container id="aspace_4ea349a67edc9ac24758ab33fe207f98" label="unspecified" type="reel">21</container></did><c02 id="aspace_85bca944657a4b15e41182b35277dce3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (November 1942). 225 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_1618b4103f6208f1d41a3f48126f4c3e" label="unspecified" type="reel">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_daaf00d408ade201514311a7721d2be8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; discrimination against Negroes in the railroad industry; antidiscrimination clauses in defense contracts; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Capital Transit Company case; Kilgore report; Fair Employment Practices Commission operations bulletin; decisions and proceedings of the National War Labor Board and the National Labor Relations Board; summary and findings in the Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; United States Employment Service operating policy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d70289e9cf5de5d0182bb7b83cbc1a7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0226. Fair Employment Practices Commission (December 1942). 201 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea8bc6b832ba6fb98b399fab6ad49c55" label="unspecified" type="reel">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5e94a49239364462d8cc455a858f7795"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Fair Employment Practices Commission progress report; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget; report of the chairman of the War Manpower Commission; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry and unions; upgrading and hiring of Negroes as Pullman conductors; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearing in the Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company case; samples of firms with fair employment policies.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2e7b97a50ad490848d0bf18299c80ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>0427. (1942). 70 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_4838130c3a11b4594512e601257151d7" label="unspecified" type="reel">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d3b7e78a2376eca46cfe54d07ac45157"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Proposed elimination of discriminatory practices by the Civil Service; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; samples of firms with fair employment policies; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; transfer of Fair Employment Practices Commission to the War Manpower Commission.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_93698a6080b37d3f6c60e546eece5cc9" level="file"><did><unittitle>0497. Fair Employment Practices Commission (1942). 251 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_08229194a53c3c6b648525ca13892a24" label="unspecified" type="reel">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_150a505b5c6bc8fe77935b6ea5785e5d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; summary of Fair Employment Practice Commission hearing on discrimination in defense training; report on how management can integrate Negroes in war industries in New York state; special research report on the Negro worker; recommendations to Fair Employment Practices Commission for approval of staff appointments, promotions, and placement; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7dd1a962a0aa010eb57f13f382b59137" level="file"><did><unittitle>0748. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-February 10, 1943).</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_79239729dde3e9d1023a42c686f1e50c" label="unspecified" type="reel">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cb2bb6a763243d4ab860e65af729bc42"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; adjustment of complaint against the War Shipping Administration; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; development of nutrition program for federal workers; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; defense training for Negroes.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a992238cec134cd97dec366dfcfdce17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1943</unittitle><container id="aspace_6ee3ea55d685f2befa1b047b245e4f6e" label="unspecified" type="reel">22</container></did><c02 id="aspace_4847640900c60bed735921ff019b7f30" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (February 11-28, 1943). 284 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_c695046d15e5626847118f71ada836e3" label="unspecified" type="reel">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_145e8ebc6f8e4ee63a18e4856e0de66e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission operations bulletin; United States military compliance with antidiscrimination executive order; employment and assignment of Negroes in the federal civil service; summary of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings in the Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company case; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates; proceedings of the Conference on Scope and Powers of Fair Employment Practices Commission; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; Columbia Steel Company case.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_eddc9d051af27fd18f7fd5d134bfd347" level="file"><did><unittitle>0285. Fair Employment Practices Commission (March-April 15, 1943).</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_394835005e5ffb84272ed8ff547974a2" label="unspecified" type="reel">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c02104bed846c4778a70f5818bb4bec3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government department and agencies; work stoppages due to discrimination against Negroes; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; list of War Manpower Commission personnel; report on action on United States Service 510 reports; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; Fair Employment Practices Commission personnel; participation of Negroes in the National Youth Administration war program; requests for occupational deferments; Fair Employment Practices Commission report on employment discrimination.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0698067998ab9969c3e6c22ca4ade6c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>0515. Fair Employment Practices Commission (April 16-July 1943).</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2f10960c4e3338f3e7ec53bd0fd59f1" label="unspecified" type="reel">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b0de90ab89f5c6e6e4c974805724e550"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Capital Transit Company case; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; report on the segregation of war workers; Fair Employment Practices Commission personnel recommendations; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; report on utilization of nonwhite workers in war production in the Detroit area; report on equal employment opportunity for Negroes in local transportation systems; Fair Employment Practices Commission May 1943 annual report; creation of American Labor Conference on International Affairs; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates; report on racial discrimination in Pacific Coast shipbuilding industry; report on racial discrimination in the mining and oil industries of the Southwest; Milton Webster reappointed to membership in the Fair Employment Practices Commission ; American Federation of Labor Committee on Post War Planning and Minority Group Problems; report on racial discrimination in the United States military.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb00894ed96aa3aa502b3802a12fa072" level="file"><did><unittitle>0848. Fair Employment Practices Commission (August-September 10, 1943). 201 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_1160d450eb4cafebb6b4cd868353e738" label="unspecified" type="reel">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63fa429d713dae83d6e5baed9996c99a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Operating agreement between Fair Employment Practices Commission and the War Manpower Commission on nondiscrimination program; proposed establishment of a Fair Employment Practices Commission sub-regional office in Detroit; Fair Employment Practices Commission personnel; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; War Manpower Commission field instructions; cooperative agreement between Fair Employment Practices Commission and the War Labor Board; responsibility of the War Manpower Commission in the utilization of minority groups; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_3f2729652af2e0d70f6651507040de9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1943</unittitle><container id="aspace_39b34f0e2719f3118fc58e7978c50b01" label="unspecified" type="reel">23</container></did><c02 id="aspace_3f510cd1deb57981ece7d1746d35e187" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (September 11-30, 1943). 336 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca66dde5a049963b32eb53c0f90167dd" label="unspecified" type="reel">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a0d0dbed32fac9951d996046d722ec9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry and unions; seniority lists for dining car employees; Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings, findings, and directives on discrimination complaints against the Pennsylvania Railroad Company, the Southern Railway Company, the Louisville and Nashville Railroad, the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, New York Central Railroad, the Norfolk Southern Railway Company, Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company, the Jacksonville Terminal Company, the Georgia Railroad, the Gulf, Mobile, and Ohio Railroad, the Norfolk and Western Railway Company, the Central of Georgia Railway Company, the Southeastern Carriers' Conference, the Illinois Central Railroad System, the Union Pacific Railroad, the Chicago and North Western Railway Company, the Atlantic Coast Line Company, the Seaboard Airline Railway Company, the Saint Louis-San Francisco Railway Company, and the Southern Railway Company; National Mediation Board agreement between the Southern Carriers' Conference Committee and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Engineers; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; description of functions of Fair Employment Practices Commission personnel; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings in Dow Chemical Company case.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_508636eff51fa156981f19ffa02c051c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0337. Fair Employment Practices Commission (October-December 1943). 292 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfd844f5f7258421f6df3e38b47aa386" label="unspecified" type="reel">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2aca79e67a4be3f0eb463fcd935f92fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings and findings in the Northwest Mining and Exchange Company case and the Philadelphia Transportation Company case; Malcolm Ross appointed Fair Employment Practices Commission Chairman; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; report on the employment of aliens in war industries; sample of cases handled successfully by the Fair Employment Practices Commission; employment relationship to the Committee for Congested Production Areas; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; report on developments in the employment of Negroes in war industries; agreement between the National War Labor Board and Fair Employment Practices Commission; list of officers of the local divisions of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget; discrimination in federal housing for war workers; Capital Transit Company case; Oregon Shipbuilding Corporation case.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a8ef805e95fc1a9fb9a9adb7e007a06e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0629. Fair Employment Practices Commission (1943). 303 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_92bef634a1e599637de12254d7e7cd0d" label="unspecified" type="reel">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_07956e3de66bd87bbb12d6ae09db2faf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Notes relating to Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; National Mediation Board agreement between the Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committee and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; mediation agreements between the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen and the Illinois Central Railroad Company and the Gulf, Mobile, and Northern Railroad Company; summaries of discrimination complaints against railroad companies; executive order relating to discrimination by companies or agencies engaged in the fulfillment of war production contracts; Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company case; appointment of Monsignor Francis J. Haas as Fair Employment Practices Commission chairman; Milton Webster's address at the American Federation of Labor Post War Forum; operating relationship between the War Manpower Commission and Fair Employment Practices Commission; digest of Fair Employment Practices Commission railroad hearings; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_131da46e559349693a1a91a8a9ec0197" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1944</unittitle><container id="aspace_088a7241e3bab65990891c8a063fcb36" label="unspecified" type="reel">24</container></did><c02 id="aspace_9252f4f80f65e9d8a2eeae67ef9c8e0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-April 1944). 266 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c1d537486eb2b43cfa3288a484e0869" label="unspecified" type="reel">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5bbedb7b25612749bbc06983538bffcf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Congressional bill to prohibit employment discrimination; Carter Carburetor Corporation case; Warner Electric Corporation case; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; report on status of Fair Employment Practices Commission discrimination cases docketed in Region IX; Malcolm Ross's address before the National Freedom Day Celebration; Inter-Race Peace Rally; Dow Chemical Company case; Northwest Mining and Exchange case; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; report on experiences in Negro employment.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_11523a01ec81e2b0ce04b00930cde969" level="file"><did><unittitle>0267. Fair Employment Practices Commission (May-July 1944). 231 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_225e85ebc3f74e163153d9996f95b7c1" label="unspecified" type="reel">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_55a720feec065a2cd59381742870afd5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; summaries of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases in the Saint Louis area; National War Agencies Appropriation Bill; proposed executive order on discrimination against aliens; statements in support of Fair Employment Practices Commission; Malcolm Ross's address to the Baltimore branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored Peoples; congressional bill to prohibit employment discrimination; abolition of segregation in the armed forces.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7dc5558626a230da7667965958f29209" level="file"><did><unittitle>0498. Fair Employment Practices Commission (August-September 1944). 257 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0900375e557206c9946a9f2b7f9fae3" label="unspecified" type="reel">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7b726807fe0d59ae20d3cab25529b9d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; summaries of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases in Saint Louis area; McQuay-Norris Manufacturing Company case; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Saint Louis Shipbuilding and Steel Company case; operational statistics for Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; agreement between Fair Employment Practices Commission and the Maritime Commission; Fair Employment Practices Commission jurisdiction; antidiscrimination clauses in defense contracts; congressional bill to prohibit employment discrimination.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3c7ac788c8d1b78fde9f875b93b5ef5f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0755. Fair Employment Practices Commission (October-December 1944). 215 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_5703a63e6d97cf919f1b96c44de95452" label="unspecified" type="reel">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3f204e396b518feff655944cf29af68b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; discrimination by federal housing agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget; summaries of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; MCQuay-Norris Manufacturing Company case; Capital Transit Company case; Shell Oil Company case.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_976fd2dd8bd2152d3de121979b5e352f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1944-1946</unittitle><container id="aspace_64ba836bdc027567392607e4139af606" label="unspecified" type="reel">25</container></did><c02 id="aspace_17f1da6e1a36570385a00c3e5eb52b3d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (1944). 201 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_15f6dc9e07a35c2117c4cdf3a6d85f50" label="unspecified" type="reel">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6cfc0c5a5164a82c4a9489078632e398"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Report on the Negro in 1944; report on postwar labor stability; Marinship Corporation case; contract between the Los Angeles Railway Corporation and the Amalgamated Association of Street Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America; congressional bill to prohibit employment discrimination; Fair Employment Practices Commission case load activity by month; operational statistics for Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; report on the Fair Employment Practices Commission and the employment of minority workers in transition to the postwar economy; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; Fair Employment Practices Commission operations; report on nondiscrimination in war industries and the federal government.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ac76047401ed9d33172dc5a322eb3585" level="file"><did><unittitle>0202. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-February 1945). 234 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe551669e2de9205be31dd4c15922180" label="unspecified" type="reel">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_47ef44cb43bbda26a04c2cee5745491d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Shell Oil Company case; summaries of reports from Fair Employment Practices Commission regional offices on status of transit cases; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission salaries and expenses; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; McQuay-Norris Manufacturing Company case; Seafarers International Union case; report on major race riots in the United States; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meeting.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6ac70d808e8b36d2946bac32169e7d33" level="file"><did><unittitle>0436. Fair Employment Practices Commission (March-May 1945). 215 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_dad82a14194bf49de1b03b2b5cabb703" label="unspecified" type="reel">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_68d6d7017ad16bf6020737d986e6160a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; summaries of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Capital Transit Company case; proposal for a permanent Fair Employment Practices Commission; Shell Oil Company case; Seafarers International Union case.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e6183dfe24e57889db924936e0e7bc67" level="file"><did><unittitle>0651. Fair Employment Practices Commission (June-December 1945). 251 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_acdbccaac5be505ba6eb84c7dd387911" label="unspecified" type="reel">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_abd28ea772b71297a1a3e747906b85db"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Fair Employment Practices Commission appropriations; status of Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; proposed Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; McDonnell Aircraft Corporation case; Capital Transit Company case; Fair Employment Practices Commission salaries and expenses; Olin Industries, Incorporated case; Texas and New Orleans Railroad Company case; agreement between the United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America, Congress of Industrial Organizations, and the Fair Employment Practices Commission; proposal for a permanent Fair Employment Practices Commission.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fb69130cca84174a8a1331026a85c00a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0902. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-June 1946). 55 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_63dd35439b6d43a4f8191fdfcb91c2ee" label="unspecified" type="reel">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_83b49673b1d02bbc306aec5fc6429494"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Displacement of wartime workers in Washington, District of Columbia; extension of the Fair Employment Practices Commission by Harry Truman; proposal for a permanent Fair Employment Practices Commission; outline for Fair Employment Practices Commission final report.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_72069e63396c90173ea87f2a4c96dd8b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hearings 1948-1976</unittitle><container id="aspace_4d16c76cd98cee025ffc085616e9ed28" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><c02 id="aspace_d4a8a546329c5966a0bf483dcf81e362" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for C.W. Allen, 1966. 15 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_b63bef1d520af3f7b0f1cd4ea59303fa" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed88513ccc9836e9ec2ec017aad7119e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Charges filed against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members by the Dining Car Employees Local 351 under their union shop agreement with the Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company; memorandum of agreement between the Dining Car Employees' Union, Local 351 and the Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bafaa30da943f2dbd3f6bba6c2af38d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0016. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for S.P. Blake, 1966. 6 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a8d792a203ddfea55569de0587a7617" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a874db2d5906a34c9675d6d9c8a62230"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Charges filed against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members by the Dining Car Employees Local 351 under their union shop agreement with the Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_58b3261c94f491a32c5eac7c126d588a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0022. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for A.R. Blanchette, 1968. 60 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d978411a390c37312a70e636708b1cf" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_19f46e08021c76a1776fef348fce5152"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Memorandum of agreement between the Canadian Railways and the associated railway unions representing their non-operating employees regarding job security; memorandum of agreement between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Canadian Pacific Railway Company.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cba0a80e8795e117d62d3a53ac80f7eb" level="file"><did><unittitle>0082. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for N. Brawner, 1966. 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d1a9532660c28f24496cbace0fa892e" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe71d0ba24f2c7dc7756b5e8e70f8878"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Charges filed against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members by the Dining Car Employees Local 351 under their union shop agreement with the Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d22175de91196efb8403639aea49a925" level="file"><did><unittitle>0090. [Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing, Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad, April 1963]. 13 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_c79e09eaeaf5338def45b67364653b5f" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ec7c867649889b78116dd07cf5be4331"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad Company dispute before the National Railroad Adjustment Board regarding seniority rights.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_053c3f7bde7604801b2e4c95e195e897" level="file"><did><unittitle>0103. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for the Fort Worth and Denver Railway Company, 1963. 70 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_1bfad889a840ebca44c26d38981e5e98" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b1e675226cd9676678057f7ebd546983"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Dispute between the Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks and the Fort Worth and Denver Railway Company before the National Railroad Adjustment Board regarding termination of dining car service positions.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_480c36454af68f4be2b97e380ce84e34" level="file"><did><unittitle>0173. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearings: Kansas City Southern Railway Case, 1951. 55 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_124e0fea1cca6923fc18572c75438004" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66b5ef192986253c94a6e9cf7ae803b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Dispute between the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen and the Kansas City Southern Railway Company before the National Railroad Adjustment Board regarding use of train porters to perform brakemen's duties.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_62e7a1680fdcf90a65e182c95686bbcb" level="file"><did><unittitle>0228. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Locomotive Firemen's Case, 1953. 204 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_602114c2617c144d17ddbfcb101e170b" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_768f05cd173fe304a90df8c1873a7578"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Discrimination against colored locomotive firemen; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; colored locomotive firemen's case against the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen before the United States Supreme Court; proposed settlement of colored locomotive firemen's cases.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c36d6c03f54ece47d95d698e37ab2814" level="file"><did><unittitle>0432. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Locomotive Firemen's Case, 1955. 36 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_caf8d36c8ab0f4be09fbfa90899eb338" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3121d7fdf1dab11ef0e870370950f36f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters efforts to organize colored locomotive firemen; colored locomotive firemen's case against the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Ohio.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ec22c6588ee0ee88a2ca71c01a894f29" level="file"><did><unittitle>0468. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Benjamin F. Morris. 1958. 175 pages.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c80e0c75f119f96e04a9250c78e5546" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_87d19fe662d111edacdc00f78afe7b2d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Benjamin F. Morris case against R.M. Willis and the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters in the circuit court of Jackson County, Missouri, and in the Missouri Supreme Court regarding discharge from Pullman Company for nonpayment of union dues.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_de0f6e89f3f253804739b5336981c64f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0643. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Benjamin F. Morris, 1958. 224 pages.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_185a00d095d9fcb49fe417bbd2a3395b" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6bcc4a6dfb8f17eca2ecee5cc023530c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Benjamin F. Morris case against R.M. Willis and the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters in the Missouri Supreme Court regarding discharge from Pullman Company for nonpayment of union dues.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_de0acb9f487ece242e11e3691398a427" level="file"><did><unittitle>0867. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Benjamin F. Morris, 1958. 82 pages.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6a99d47792be9809e10cfc1c6422ef9" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ef155c359a711fc0e1c5d62efaeb5ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Benjamin F. Morris case against R.M. Willis and the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters in the Missouri Supreme Court and in the circuit court of Jackson County, Missouri, regarding discharge from Pullman Company for nonpayment of union dues.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0f63d4fa51fb520f8eadda50723cae0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0949. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for New Haven Case, 1948. 58 pages.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf44222cd490228feecc96efd387a8a6" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5188ab8f3292cc0e50405538e0f4d30c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters request for a National Mediation Board investigation into union representation dispute involving buffet and club car employees of the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Company employees; National Mediation Board proceedings and decision in the matter of the representation of employees of the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a3ddf72010da30a40c270fa83cde4c09" level="file"><did><unittitle>1007. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Eldrige Parker, 1970. 22 pages.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_10c7569cf4ebab4aadc833b719bf61b1" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ac522d2518075d633cc59ac7ee0967a9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Investigation of Eldridge Parker's job security claim against the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b49b8c391d965294045d3c8b09a6ac36" level="file"><did><unittitle>1029. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Milton Philips, 1975. 16 pages.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc81668dd5a75ad8e3385fb0b9824c14" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be31bbf6a45aa4aa054196543fe7b81e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Statement by the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations on seniority and layoffs; principles for seniority modification.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aae2e40246164477dde39b94f6932898" level="file"><did><unittitle>1045. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for G.R. Tillman, 1966. 13 pages.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_412837ea64cfcad35b3bf33d4de6abd4" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c75bde1425dc9c998c4d96815e5b91d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Charges filed against Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters members by the Dining Car Employees Local 351 under their union shop agreement with the Grand Trunk Western Railroad Company.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f202b8edee8e0c75ba03997ab8f7a03e" level="file"><did><unittitle>1058. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for Union Shop Court Case, 1953. 17 pages.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_484f45c1664dc6603d1e64ad52870800" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_41a2f09c9184e3ba31ae181144b42251"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Complaint against the Seaboard Air Line Railroad Company restraining the carrier from enforcing its union shop agreement with the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters case against the Texas and Pacific Railway Company before the National Railroad Adjustment Board regarding abolition of position of train porter and reduction of employees occupying those positions to chair car porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6639880fb06f825dc9d5438e4b8f79c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>1075. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for J.W. Wesson, 1965. 7 pages.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5a410470bf223611538546b091336fc" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_89460dd251db5f6cc4f885bc6160074f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Investigation into alleged nonpayment of union dues by J.W. Wesson.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc9ab7f53b1cb4cad40e20bf54da7ae3" level="file"><did><unittitle>1082. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Hearing for W. Wheeler, 1962. 119 pages.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_7db11c3d4092192e2d295909ff8a74ae" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9bfcde3ea043f4d7964eeecfb32c8dd6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters complaint against the New York City system before the National Railroad Adjustment Board and the National Mediation Board regarding selling of pillows in day coaches by lounge car attendants.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_43be59d8868e21050b78948c776edcaf" level="file"><did><unittitle>1201. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Hearing for J. L. Williams, G. Thomas, and John W. Amos. 1976. 14 pages.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_b76719f8c8df064358cc910054662c17" label="unspecified" type="reel">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0a60c68685751526192132b56b25e992"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Complaint regarding seniority and working status of Amtrak sleeping car service attendants.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_3670c72291db94eb228c0e694f6c2709" level="file"><did><unittitle>Convention Correspondence 1948-1971</unittitle><container id="aspace_7891f237583b4ee78aee408d130d0eac" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><c02 id="aspace_ca5415234bf5d72f0ffbd6b48681fcd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - National Convention, Detroit, 1948 - General Papers. 45 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_e07dba5522bb187ed48ce67acdd670b8" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6642342a619f292d4ada3fb7d1955b1b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Convention publicity and arrangements; convention resolutions; list of convention delegates.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e16d0868c71236337b4c5fb94d6962e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0046. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - 7th Biennial Convention, 1950 - Resolutions. 106 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_4da6ea2274d7cc3730ba45df97afa0d6" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9ddc000e3b0b9856c49ab73f2db188a0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Convention resolutions; report of the Auditing Committee; constitutional amendment.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d8c45283181e1afdc6251a47cec9274c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0152. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - First Triennial Convention, 1953 - Program. 9 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4c3204b8dd7071e190df373d56ff456" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5ae1cc235a2987f9ad54573d2bbf6263" level="file"><did><unittitle>0161. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - First Triennial Convention, 1953 - General Papers. 80 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_074c85b1b62dcada82cbb7071b2ba0e4" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c00bca1082f3ec9bbefcd9e54a17fe51"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Convention arrangements; convention delegates; convention program and publicity; convention receipts and expenses; post-convention meeting of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7c508d7df4f6c08b0643fc04a3bc5b0e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0241. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Second Triennial Convention, 1956 - General Papers. 23 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_251cd7d149fc5fdad81f4f0d1cf44691" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4d5d2d6e1283879e7c8b05d79b1be6ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Convention arrangements; convention program and publicity.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0634973675122ded213aaae6c298691e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0264. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - General Papers. 122 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_7802cd9c2b4b0d27d47caa5dfe71cffa" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b8b5b34db13047c065e5c9d8895d7fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Convention arrangements; guest speakers for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention; convention expenses; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters labor education meeting; convention publicity; report of the Committee on Scientific Service and Safety Efficiency; list of discontinued Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters districts; financial and membership status of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters divisions; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters endorses National Association for the Advancement of Colored People program; railroad social insurance program.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fab6ddd5abb3ff3535106a84f260f261" level="file"><did><unittitle>0386. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - General Papers. 115 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_1fc48386084ed32b72d0a56116c8bbed" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5c2c9718f50ef94d778ae6362f367982"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Report on Grievance and Claims Committee; list of officers of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters local divisions; convention outline; railroad carriers having agreements with the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; convention programs; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters labor education meeting; agreement between Southwest Reporters and the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; convention resolutions; list of convention delegates; G.E. Leighty's address to the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters convention.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_eba3cb679c3a3cfbcb93c1bc9f9726a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>0501. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - Resolutions. 57 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_84bc9840d99bba4c96de9ab85fe8c62f" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_453a61720b1754381fbdb8c5a8b258b0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Report of the Committee on Resolutions and Constitutions; convention resolutions; constitutional revisions.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_da877f88ab9656f745beb5c66c142a49" level="file"><did><unittitle>0558. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - Report of the Executive Committee. 23 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9e20e1e6141831a0e2f806beec310e1" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c93311de07337bf6b5ebe6567c64a45d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0581. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - Amendments to Constitution. 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_039019893c3208a50aa0cc2dc88f0743" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1c8bf8d4fc3b810bd8b77f67fdb18536" level="file"><did><unittitle>0589. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Third Triennial Convention, 1959 - Resolutions. 141 pages.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_b35d561ab10861bdd7df415e8e79edbf" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d9448103b639861a87b191c9531ead52"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Convention resolutions; minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board pre-convention and post-convention meetings; report of the Train Chair Car Porters and Attendants Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c96eac9c02d4a70dfe8dbc072475bfa5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0730. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fourth Triennial Convention, 1962 - General Papers. 95 pages.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_961df18dfc178d49c76137cfa9157697" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8391c1be4b01334eb55f13104ce5f958"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Summary of matters handled by the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters on behalf of members employed by the Canadian Pacific Railroad Company; convention arrangements and publicity; second convention of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Ladies Auxiliary; convention delegates; report of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board to the Fourth Triennial Convention; convention program.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c819e44888c976692047bfe86d958e6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0825. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fourth Triennial Convention, 1962 - General Papers. 144 pages.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_31580183665e04d2437b6d90af6f9bde" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d4b1b631f48a86797eb8132e252c49c6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Report of the Finance Committee; convention agenda; report of the Train, Chair Car Porters and Attendants Committee; convention resolutions; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitutional amendments; A. Philip Randolph's address to the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Fourth Triennial Convention; convention program.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aa5d0abfc6508b27ead8e8b3acfeccc5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0969. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fifth Triennial Convention, 1965 - General Papers. 46 pages.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_66a5502540935bb94a1724eb4d727c06" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_874e5fce4354a9cbb1401427f34f5abc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Convention delegates; convention arrangements and program; memorial service for Milton Webster.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c8a801331597cee3e0f1a3e5e5b3beb5" level="file"><did><unittitle>1015. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fiftieth Anniversary Convention, 1975 - Credentials. 37 pages.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4cd06c2ba71ebdbd13a9161059e04dc" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_977fe2274421cab66aa5a29a06f28c28"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Statements by the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Executive Council on equal opportunity in housing, voter registration by mail, seniority and layoffs, and Title VII and the seniority system; efforts to merge Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters with larger union; need for expanding Equal Employment Opportunity Commission conciliation efforts under Title VII; report on union role in ending job discrimination; report on civil rights; list of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters local division officers.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f1be7d056ae103a7945d185f086fcdac" level="file"><did><unittitle>1052. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters - Fiftieth Anniversary Convention, 1975 - Congratulatory Letters and Telegrams. 115 pages.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_653c005de9bbfe5314f3b860166e9bbf" label="unspecified" type="reel">27</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_9c74339ba5d4e635d2bf3dcd2eb243c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Membership Ledgers; General Files (American Train Dispatchers Association-Extra Porters)</unittitle><container id="aspace_dc6972827447a99fc8d02bfa559ab3e3" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><c02 id="aspace_5ca92672429101c5c2223f0846b6270f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Box 62-1, no date. 51 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><container id="aspace_2c2f8607543262f5d600b00c103265e1" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c423803a26833a005e4de44482e19cf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership list.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6f47ac533e78bfa4ce2fca133ddd7e3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0052. Box 62-2. No date. 13 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><container id="aspace_424a88a067534e3d9174022fd2df4b50" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2773b79963550c7ac06aaa09cb762189"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership list.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f035b20df2f6776cdb99bba4f60bd15d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0065. American Train Dispatchers Association (Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters). 11 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_79580968400e53a2274e35dd2024cba8" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9ff9c45831f38ca6dd258c2b3e74e2c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Cases pending before the Third Division of the National Railroad Adjustment Board</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_df3851e33ecc8f3fadbb30cf9311649c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0076. Annual $10 Tax Notice (To All Officers in Midwest Zone). 18 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b6f82a9df92140f9a05a7c88ea9a10c" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f03fb06f3ac60e883defd5a8f880196f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0094. Application (17 Cooperating Railway Organizations). 6 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e1e47c254758f7681bf4d485a485561" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_54b5a889c04e0fb46a86ecd153995172"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Effort by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters to join the seventeen cooperating railway organizations that initiate wages, working conditions, and other movements in the interest of non-operating employees.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2c1d8747d181f8604887c2a8c5b810c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0100. Army Discharge. 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_6285ca9c521cd21782ceb5fe6cdccc80" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e297422d18377da85202aab03b1a877c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Procedures to be followed for obtaining release or discharge of skilled workers age thirty-eight or over for the purpose of employment in essential industries.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_67efcf3929bcd5afe91e21cde03e7caa" level="file"><did><unittitle>0108. Association of Western Railways. 62 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c82db1f2ac4f857459d893a87f822ef" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c13daa34db0fe15377324a38d6103cba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Colorado gross ton-mile truck tax.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_170f069ede08ff235bf9b8566dd4faca" level="file"><did><unittitle>0170. Association of American Railroads. 2 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b5f8e6aa6ea11337e8d69e943b7494b" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_24f62146d48c2634d7b70d9d3daa7383"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Association of American Railroads position on United States transportation policy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6af5c7c68d8f9624d16e5081e1aef865" level="file"><did><unittitle>0172. Atlantic Coast Line Porters (CIO). 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_f785ffcbf5740e97cfd060ac315bd821" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4dc2c69f4e3c9257673fefef18f29b64"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Union representation dispute regarding employees of the Atlantic Coast Line Railroad.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_efd463ed6dde109362993b25eec49c95" level="file"><did><unittitle>0180. Audit Report (Special Fund-Drexel National Bank). 15 pages.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_457debe9f4bea25990eb2d0c83da45ab" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_50ff1122fbc2fffae0aa833516d634ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Statement of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters monthly receipts and disbursements of the special fund at the Drexel National Bank. August 31, 1959</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_af17ac1c098db35c692af27ce4ab633c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0195. Authorizations for Handling Board Cases. 4 pages.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_2158b72a30b78ac9de454be6efa4fdbd" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2bf4e150e28044938ea5ae80c49bba52"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Authorization for handling of cases before the Fourth Division of the National Railroad Adjustment Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_591c23dac8e51db85b32553d0120ce0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0199. Away From Home Expenses - Chicago District Porters. 12 pages.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><container id="aspace_8165376ca7025faa68857d5425e09797" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4cd1fa179810f10582d9c8426d77a2f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>No date.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_98c49632d3546d8f3a5d032d5fb8562f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0211. Canadian Railway Board of Adjustment. 15 pages.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1921/1921">1921</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3957c67198eacf7e3fb684a9cd1b5ab" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_95e97a59cef8ca717f8b29d9c10825ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Memorandum of agreement between the Canadian railways and members of railway unions; proposed sleeping car conductors bill.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_18d2ab0c11ce7134f5d4630a283cf70b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0226. Civil Rights Committee. 3 pages.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f7a8e0ba66465a696d20ae0022e82ac" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f016bcbf9f1a4fe1dece693d24b54523"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations housing and urban development program; meeting of American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Civil Rights Committee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ce469b7bd51ca82b86d5307ff0b16f3d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0229. Chicago-Midwest, Detroit-Pittsburgh Zone Conference. 203 pages.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_341d6c455671d0950c98003dde065664" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bce23cd084525cdb734163b0fdf269b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Report on the Chicago-Midwest and Detroit-Pittsburgh regional conference held at Chicago, Illinois; conference delegates; conference resolutions; conference arrangements; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters labor education meeting; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters leadership training conference in Montreal, Canada; conference program; speeches at conference by A. Philip Randolph and Horace Harper.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ee4182e4c31d2e4894f162507a6e507f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0432. Conference Proceedings (of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Provisional Committee to Organize Colored) Locomotive Firemen, Jacksonville, Florida. 189 pages.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c0c056253dce9c23ea7f9e9d948e483" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_092578849ced7e7ca386d38ba170db43"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>December 2-3, 1947.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d49be7fd9545ff52c431844dcb9f7590" level="file"><did><unittitle>0621. Colored Locomotive Firemen's Conference, Washington, District of Columbia. 21 pages.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_eefda6544b39f5f9865370a1ed4c03ed" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_54ef020fb6c94266647c0274696d1a16"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report on the Tenth Annual Conference of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Provisional Committee for the Organization of Colored Locomotive Firemen.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b8090e99194545f837677a2e795f9782" level="file"><did><unittitle>0642. Colored Locomotive Firemen's Conference. 10 pages.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5fceda3eedef15f6b363b00d8781ad5" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_24bd0adfc28b9073696b80d6368c61a9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Notice of the Fifteenth Annual Conference of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Provisional Committee for the Organization of Colored Locomotive Firemen. May 25-26, 1956</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d72654622faf2627968c451c548af5e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>0652. Colored Locomotive Firemen's Conference. 4 pages.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_3bb79836ed70af49bbe2c675db547718" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed550c4e8ed8e287bf7f923452345c42"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Notice of 1958 Conference of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Provisional Committee for the Organization of Colored Locomotive Firemen.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_924320d103f52fb622cbd21f7b68182b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0656. Congress of Industrial Organizations - Pullman Porters' Organizing Committee. 3 pages.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ae861c50016e9b154987f9b07855205" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_70302569940bcf727760ebc7a61e9c32" level="file"><did><unittitle>0659. Congress of Industrial Organizations - Libel Suit Against. 24 pages.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e50874ed7d9dcf32fccfdbe562d466b" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d388825b7ffc996a18532dd7abd8cb23"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Proposed settlement in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Congress of Industrial Organizations libel suits.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6431096f4e8c24d23551487874664d0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0683. Constitution - Joint American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations. 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b7e85b7241ba9086976eb3cc69b24cf" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3c0c8d189a65d7d9463cf668dd8d6eb2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Amendments to articles of proposed American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations constitution.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8971602ca9d86ea51b7e364b93fa0dbf" level="file"><did><unittitle>0691. Constitution - Revision of (International). 28 pages.</unittitle><unitid>23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_76620673aed6d73681ec7df5d6209cd6" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_76111543fd34b691820669c7c71808df"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Amendments to Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e8bb5a33284aaa042cdfb6af0db63d53" level="file"><did><unittitle>0719. Constitution - Revision of (Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters). 169 pages.</unittitle><unitid>24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5f480bf6ff8c421a788d3bfefaece7c" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b7833787d22a1832c240aa9453098e86"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Revision of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution and general rules; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters death benefits; rules and regulations governing the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Auditing Department; resolutions at the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters First and Second Triennial Conventions; Canadian Pacific Railroad Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters membership.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6a893b2414f363b8ffe9235a2c90cec9" level="file"><did><unittitle>0888. Delinquent Membership Dues. 27 pages.</unittitle><unitid>25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1970" type="inclusive">1964-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c54b5ba924c008660fdb1e0d88559d9" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ae6315a3f748a0ea9061ccd00c2f158f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters demands for discharge of members for nonpayment of dues; dues collection; amendment of vacation agreement.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6c8c685421fc03c8937d8525091c09ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>0915. Department of State. 78 pages.</unittitle><unitid>26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_472d2d4e869466bd779cd9c54a57598a" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_13fb14ea1c5088fb03e14c64bbee5e2a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Economic survey of life in the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR); Congress of Industrial Organizations call for price ceilings and rent control; United States overseas information and educational exchange programs; report of meeting between the Assistant Secretary of State for Public Affairs and representatives of American trade unions; report on conditions of Hungarian workers; labor unions' position on the Korean War.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b82b6c0d4772b7edc472bf55772fbe51" level="file"><did><unittitle>0993. Earnings of Extra Employees (Chicago Central Division). 18 pages.</unittitle><unitid>27</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_20cc26d3b1a4b0d0e1dc77c553e08050" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_944615d4693bf68b71d026b14cfe56ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>1011. Earnings of Extra Employees (Chicago Commissary District). 19 pages.</unittitle><unitid>28</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_a3f023bd3410df2efcc8a458d054c1fc" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_60db36dde9357677dd5ee7727d85cced" level="file"><did><unittitle>1030. Earnings of Extra Employees (Chicago Northern District). 50 pages.</unittitle><unitid>29</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a4f59a9ee6707c1434ab184ad2275c8" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c3e3eebf546e61ccd3ee7ecae14cf622" level="file"><did><unittitle>1080. Earnings of Extra Employees (Omaha). 5 pages.</unittitle><unitid>30</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_e39080b6723c3017a2c5e00b3aaf2af8" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5f6a348187963293482288c466557104"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>March 1954.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_99f0f6a69aea4f3404b8ed86dcd0481d" level="file"><did><unittitle>1085. Eastern Zone Regional Conference. 6 pages.</unittitle><unitid>31</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_8db65d5f78597f11dfb4a1dc9fe50e0b" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a683f1d6838d0e9616adb955bafa8630"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Eastern Regional Zone Conference.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_df563cfbea6077721a383e86935d72c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>1091. Extra Porter Salaries. 16 pages.</unittitle><unitid>32</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad345b4286aa230a97cb9716609770e1" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2186a36bd90f4ecb8b48342e4872566b" level="file"><did><unittitle>1107. Extra Porters - Layovers (Unemployment Insurance Act). 94 pages.</unittitle><unitid>33</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_c4929c394dea1aef27867f7a60dd33ad" label="unspecified" type="reel">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a14548985cf29a48b3cfc34be86eed95"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Claims for unemployment insurance benefits by extra porters; eligibility of retired men for unemployment insurance benefits; claims for unemployment benefits for layover days.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_3876a0eeab802fa900c9e840ddd263d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Files (Financial System-Railway Labor Executives Association)</unittitle><container id="aspace_a968a1857555e69608743a4c742fa1fc" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><c02 id="aspace_1a240fae58b7b944bef6d83f81dfb97d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. New Financial System (New York Office). 5 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f98faca331c191f5744691c7dca3239" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_146fd35278c58814559dc7b3953173ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Institution of new bookkeeping system at the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters New York Office. August 1952</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7b8a72ca119721827e58682b5272ab4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>0006. Financing Railroad Equipment - Creation of Governmental Agency (Eastern Railroads). 6 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_383ab943dce77b8120f0991158c66e29" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dca7e5b064c8eed23de91813b0fd9d7a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Proposed creation of governmental agency for financing railroad equipment.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c9374ac276195515a6c9cc71b3229ba9" level="file"><did><unittitle>0012. Financing Railroads by the Government. 10 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_9de8fe3bc712b5009579f12b64f7416a" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_276f2baf1a8dd8221b76ad3319e1fd8c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Mediation agreement between the Eastern and Western Carriers' Conference Committees and their employees represented by the Railroad Yardmasters of America regarding wage increases and cost of living adjustments; proposed creation of governmental agency for financing railroad equipment.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a71751780785859336884743fdd9599b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0022. Financial Report - Chicago Division (United States Department of Labor). 56 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1b8d70e2b050e16fb28dfe32278c634" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a15e1a02ca340548f26e80b24879c32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Financial report for the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division filed under the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters income tax return.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_02ee155fe731b35c843b45173e71cace" level="file"><did><unittitle>0078. Financial Reports - Chicago Zone (United States Labor Department and United States Treasury Department). 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_0dd97d71258f26b9ea058853730b8fe8" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67dee1f70733020722f2b0854ebbcf61"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Financial Reports filed by the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters' Denver, Kansas City, Omaha, and Twin Cities Divisions. July 31, 1963.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_250264c07fd1cda90feb1451e614813a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0086. Financial Report (United States Department of Labor). 14 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_47b2f73cb354331137837f6f74d92faf" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_46756ca32df1702bbba1bc245db41658"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Financial report filed by the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters' Denver, Kansas City, Omaha, and Twin Cities Division. July 31, 1962.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b3470bd0fe5bef9fa8b4bdc0ee086fca" level="file"><did><unittitle>0100. Financial Report - Midwest Zone (United States Department of Labor). 2 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f76df165ce83f24c6e66db12fc6231c" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ffe011147f938ab9936156320f86e548"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Financial report of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters' Twin Cities Division.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6bf001e8b70e8ab555889f53093a7ea1" level="file"><did><unittitle>0102. Griffin-Landrum Bill (Section by Section Analysis). 70 pages.</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_50e597250c588b7930436e61c2740b4f" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66deec091cc3c80daa0351e67f056d54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Analysis of the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (Griffin-Landrum Bill).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9c81002bb6b0e82c3ec9ecdf93b15e92" level="file"><did><unittitle>0172. Griffin-Landrum Bill. 3 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_7cfc39789e41e4b658f430a3388fac15" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b8f85663dc4936a4ebd72efa34655827"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters opposition to the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (Griffin-Landrum Bill).</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1bf46ce0870904752803bd42eed41ec7" level="file"><did><unittitle>0175. Groups, Hospital, and Surgical Insurance (for Retired Non-Operating Railroad Employees and Their Dependents). 10 pages.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><container id="aspace_40b65c5a02a25b9478247806e804170c" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_73982d83dee634667e32332751dc0b70"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Information on group hospital and surgical insurance for retired nonoperating railroad employees and their dependents. No date.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4ed8c8499b1011d3e683c828efbd3cd7" level="file"><did><unittitle>0185. Group Insurance - Organizations. 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e249d2dd39cc19f0d429d65d2850af4" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cc7509a82f4819d82f2342a0457ce813"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Information on Travelers group insurance policy for various labor unions.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2252953cc6c75744ff5011b9722511a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>0193. Group Insurance Contract GA-23000. 10 pages.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae585d78e000aefe69853a0d415fc4ee" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9ccfe5c596d4b0efee125352ca10f8b8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Group insurance contract for employees of the Chicago, Milwaukee, Saint Paul and Pacific Railroad.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_30b49791ef573c740df0a8fc459680d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0203. Health and Welfare (Mr. Leighty's Letter). 7 pages.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_0babd8982e62d0fe30e9e7106a043af8" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2905fa375564e587abf629794c1f1294"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Group insurance benefits for employee's dependents; report on Travelers group insurance policy for various labor unions.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f8e6a2bbe9a256375f67962308f39474" level="file"><did><unittitle>0210. Gratuities and Social Security (Hotel and Restaurant Employees). 4 pages.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_61cd72805cc4b83de014c60e51a906cf" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ab51bd32ad0d14fbcd4d48fbb2f68ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Relation of tips to wages in the computation of pension rights; resolutions of gratuities and Social Security adopted at the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Third Constitutional Convention.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d22e9e6be784df4bdb161b8082255ae0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0214. Income of Locals in Chicago-Midwest Zone. 2 pages.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_3fd88f786612c24c8edbda2eee9eea71" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8796f6ee908697e57b6f0e5e12b681ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Instructions applicable to bonding of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8d53a90dd3fa1262b4375ab4ed375576" level="file"><did><unittitle>0216. Income Tax. 11 pages.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_eeb78bd57e7205ff305f995a18f3da0b" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8fbe6e8a718ec11d266476152269d80"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Income tax return for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_39764c6012740b386cc02bea2459f502" level="file"><did><unittitle>0227. Income Tax Analysis (Regarding Tips for Porters). 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_48a47d418ce210a58f7fbbaf73352af4" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b1233e71f5246816ba7b14d3b9508b6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Information regarding payment of income tax on tips to porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0c1005d42ee395b7779d3d87a7b5b827" level="file"><did><unittitle>0235. Income Tax for Porters. 11 pages.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_c704d09ac2af4642ed34155480c7b10c" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_478d6a1222892a612c03792c1ca1d8c3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Information on income tax owed by porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_592300dca382cb47a7163012915106ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>0246. Income Tax on Porters' Tips. 3 pages.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_834316e344375edb3677a578a98cf391" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_010a7fb2b84f1c35e1444338dfa0f4c7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Information regarding payment of income tax on tips to porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c37e339b3e094e932006d6eb05ab477e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0249. Income Tax of Porters. 4 pages.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c2f65868df0fa52e445e8d931dcad29" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4d8ab5e787d09d9300cb109d5572a061"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Information on income tax owed by porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7fe5bd79cae87fc24548f1d6d4d5a196" level="file"><did><unittitle>0253. Income Tax Report - Chicago Division. 31 pages.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef4939d13dfcd13f3654e90536292392" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_add862fdf73a136a7140ee8a897dc61b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0284. Income Tax Report - Chicago Division. 11 pages.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2017e2aca3213e45c67811bc81a69df" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2749c5d1ceba9ac537a88fac1eeae5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0295. Income Tax Report - Chicago Division. 4 pages.</unittitle><unitid>23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e4e3d384f9d3be99cb76672d86dd507" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5a52ddebcfde887a1ae6fb6067b996ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>0299. Income Tax Report - Chicago Division, January 10July 31, 1961. 5 pages.</unittitle><unitid>24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_6428537f06f29e7d17c7ab02886f4664" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7236b631474a0f215ea45abac3c794cb" level="file"><did><unittitle>0304. Income Tax - traveling Expenses (ruling by Internal Revenue). 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_091c702c700aaa447d7070225882fcb4" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_17faa038da86510fc75768e3a7297d2a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Internal Revenue Service regulations on the reporting and substantiation of travel and other business expenses by Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters employees.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_486c3e699922279224542492a25ea32f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0312. International Association of Railway Employees (Merger). 9 pages.</unittitle><unitid>26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_884ff4a8d8ecf9133178cf78b345d8e1" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a10ee6a9cdf8cc51198668b0f76f694"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report on the merger of the Colored Trainmen of America, the International Association of Railway Employees, and the Association of Railway Trainmen and Locomotive Firemen.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fed49d6daf7771b4098278ecddf7dbce" level="file"><did><unittitle>0321. Joint Council Dining Car Employees Proposals for 25 Cent Per Hour Increase, Time and One Half, Paid Holidays. 21 pages.</unittitle><unitid>27</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_ba57ae43602fa56c8b1dad9791fbe301" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cfb3056970d4b994f62ee372653138fb" level="file"><did><unittitle>0342. Joint Council Controversy. 21 pages.</unittitle><unitid>28</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_2fe2f33af5dc80a0ebd4379bab886b8a" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72c3fab8c57b186ee7ee1f0999cdf7b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Duties performed by waiter-coach attendants on Florida trains; elimination of chair car porters on the Fort Worth and Denver Railway; alleged Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters raids on the jurisdiction of the Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_56d453480947afd9e6e0102abe1558ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>0363. Joint Council Propaganda. 108 pages.</unittitle><unitid>29</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d1c9469266830492ca25cf5b88bc780" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0d730415cf98d4efaf00b8e069f811f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Propaganda issued by the Joint Council Dining Car Employees union.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1f26eb0965782e5bbd40d6cc42624181" level="file"><did><unittitle>0471. Labor Bill (Presented in Senate). 39 pages.</unittitle><unitid>30</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfc7b11a837c8be50b1fbb9d5414ff3a" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2d399a89314e08c8cff1c71e2d290700"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959. April 25, 1959.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e9510cb05654363cae2cdd9f8399f467" level="file"><did><unittitle>0510. Labor Organization. 7 pages.</unittitle><unitid>31</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1964" type="inclusive">1963-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c415808c53935579ed70df89a060692" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_103ee83a681f8769d9508e32c816c62f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Labor organization annual reports on the Denver and Chicago Divisions of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_52c7c137d8d8c4ff170d58b3ac994206" level="file"><did><unittitle>0517. Lathers' Case Decree. 18 pages.</unittitle><unitid>32</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4013a666636be6573a291415ca6e183" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cf5648353f0cf5b8570036eb48a1ecaf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Decision in racial discrimination case against the Wood, Wire, and Metal Lathers International Union in the Chicago area.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6b6aa4c281d12202a554dc0068cae9ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>0535. Lease with Continental Properties, Incorporated (Signed 1952). 44 pages.</unittitle><unitid>33</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c0c24c951442dd4db75e421f96da06f" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_762df8b64f72726c0845b6baa19638f7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Lease for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters office space in Chicago.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_58ec558eb2e746c8a154308ef77758f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0579. National Labor Relations Act - Union Representatives Going in Company Yard. 7 pages.</unittitle><unitid>34</unitid><container id="aspace_393bd6486a23d39d76f1073a08a2ab9e" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b66dea87ea08d60681fcf9098861140d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Terms of the National Labor Relations Act dealing with employee rights and unfair labor practices. Undated.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5810d7ae1a7848fc14aca48718b2bacd" level="file"><did><unittitle>0586. Lie Detector Tests. 10 pages.</unittitle><unitid>35</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_44d012054a1e53aa38251670d81259eb" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fa7f56e2fc255f96b29e5c1536f0b336"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Report on the admissibility of the results of lie detector tests in criminal courts.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_daae8b126723999c57f1e74d2db76948" level="file"><did><unittitle>0596. Newspaper Clippings. 41 pages.</unittitle><unitid>36</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b2387e0825a96185a01d27647bd9fb1" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_10fc17f0935a685c0b572021da2b2c3d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Clippings relating to activities of railroad unions and racial discrimination by unions.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4773b7760ec76974251b38947b7962fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>0637. Newspaper Clippings. 66 pages.</unittitle><unitid>37</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1962" type="inclusive">1950-1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec8e8b3f7b904baa688288bd9649c642" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5aa7555c951d142a01387097d5e75925"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Activities of Railroad unions and racial discrimination by unions. 1950-1951 [1958-1962]</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_78114fded14e2bf51f2da7d2263170d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>0703. Petition (Discharge of Brother Grooms). 160 pages.</unittitle><unitid>38</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c82ed118e7d732c0afeeb4a0a578e83" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23e11902ff99d9b6d2c7159c8b2e2592"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Dispute between Milton Webster and C.E. Grooms; dismissal of C.E. Grooms as second vice president of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Chicago Division; request for hearing by A. Philip Randolph regarding the Grooms case.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5a01c82a339c58b0eb253d03a81b6495" level="file"><did><unittitle>0863. Railroad Adjustment Board. 22 pages.</unittitle><unitid>39</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a4ae879dfb3291f0afd1289801c26b1" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_50bd91c59c63d3e9f4bf6233543525fb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Procedures to be followed in presentation of disputes before Third Division of the National Railroad Adjustment Board; status of dockets before Third Division of the National Railroad Adjustment Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3fcf75a57982d25bd35244aa27c94d9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>0885. Railroad Discharge Forms. 2 pages.</unittitle><unitid>40</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_857e55683a0bc1d7678a251ef42a1f82" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1caa39d7ed3c0aa41b9a1f453a63917c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0887. Railroad Retirement Act - Status of Original Employees Under. 11 pages.</unittitle><unitid>41</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_31d97de0485f8509885b936dbeb76fb5" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2d4f84c06783096c3f51039e73541d9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Unemployment insurance and sick benefits for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters employees in Canada.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2d449e36f764f6bb1f81fa1145e91619" level="file"><did><unittitle>0898. Railway Labor Executive Association (Application for Membership). 7 pages.</unittitle><unitid>42</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1951" type="inclusive">1950-1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_20e0d0f9d2365cf6ec2debe11cddf2b6" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2168594dec4b478494f4be3a475aaab2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters request for membership in the Railway Labor Executives Association.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3676c61b8f95f11b245b4113d0c30cf5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0905. Railway Labor Executives Association. 344 pages.</unittitle><unitid>43</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3d8ef2f6eb94234485ea7ee6572459b" label="unspecified" type="reel">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_728bb516727461ad66401ae546c49a3d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union decision not to participate In the Joint National Railroad Adjustment Board Fund; Railway Labor Executives Association activities; agenda and minutes of Railway Labor Executives Association meetings; liberalization of pass regulations; list of chief executives and members of the Railway Labor Executives Association; amendment of Railroad Retirement Act and Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act; railroad safety.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_961d70c4fb22ccac3230b61b8b921255" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Files (Rate of Pay-Workmen's Compensation Act); Personal Injury Claims; National Association for the Advancement of Colored Peoples; A. Philip Randolph Institute</unittitle><container id="aspace_6d7d395cc9dc185c44c185bf3deb0916" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><c02 id="aspace_92fc9149fa01a946344193810bde16e9" level="file"><did><unittitle>0001. Rat of Pay. 3 pages.</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e33dd7d5bcb9058bec228a7f55eea00" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2f6aef5963c942ad20969b2ac54de0b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Pay rates for Pullman porters.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_436cc692eb998f463af01aa5ddb07862" level="file"><did><unittitle>0004. Resolution 46. 2 pages.</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_55620ab493f787168055866cdd8c4d70" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a08ed3ae343855aab2f8655ccac25cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Proposed increase in Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters dues.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_689b00209ed9204bc6ee84c3731077f0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0006. Rules Governing Monthly Reports of Railroad Accidents (Interstate Commerce Defense). 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>3</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_0483cf0298e929e2c2b4df84ac320a45" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5106fce347ef680a43e6e74bf810de4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>0014. Rump Meetings (Bulletin-APR). 9 pages.</unittitle><unitid>4</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0b861cdd58f7a29201c569c1d5bbf2f" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e1003d2d3185d71c0ce313143cbc014"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major topics: Condemnation of rump meetings of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters international and local officials by A, Philip Randolph; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters bulletin regarding unauthorized circulation of petitions.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8af22e611d2299bd5d91846562244a37" level="file"><did><unittitle>0023. Southwestern Zone Conference (Houston, Texas). 32 pages.</unittitle><unitid>5</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_947cd24daa3d42abd871775ec8a1b06e" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ac0fde88ff8cb03783236bde296a830"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Agenda and program for Southwestern Zone Conference; proper interpretation and application of rules in Pullman Company agreement. April 1949</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc2e657386b486202384e1acc0a8c0b1" level="file"><did><unittitle>0055. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Strike Instructions. 4 pages.</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c032e0fc7e69f4c3a9286c9ebacddd4" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ec0acaaae4785066cbbaaea4827c2110" level="file"><did><unittitle>0059. Train Porters (Organization of). 82 pages.</unittitle><unitid>7</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_2202521d70d166f1e4c35ad138b38b2b" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_32cb7b8a8f93a0bc347aaab168cc383e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Mediation agreement between the Trainmen, Brakemen, and Porters Union, American Federation of Labor, and the Saint Louis and San Francisco Railroad Company; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters granted jurisdiction over train porters by the American Federation of Labor; membership of train porters union; proposals for basic month and wage increase for porters; labor relations law and the Negro worker.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4e085a17be092fb344012e26de149cd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>0141. Travelers Insurance Company. 6 pages,</unittitle><unitid>8</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f30c505c7b97189bf93a5df732c6eba" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd696f3172cba4278bab4c32495daafc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Medical claims filed with the Travelers Insurance Company.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dab3989bfc0b711cd396a737b2feb3a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>0147. Travelers Insurance Plan. 12 pages.</unittitle><unitid>9</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c8a44a527972f39bb614b2df9acfa5f" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ea0b0a56c91c5143291a882622891642"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Travelers Insurance Company group hospital and surgical plan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8c093245afdcf0e8cfff8548b8de343e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0159. Unemployment Insurance Benefits for Retired Men (Bulletin-APR). 4 pages.</unittitle><unitid>10</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_e454c43b958c2ffb481b4d9c6f3ca2b0" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3f9443f71c1b8625773707f602bf1dea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Eligibility of retired men for unemployment insurance benefits.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4b61632dc8033e2bfb1471f69c0bfb41" level="file"><did><unittitle>0163. Union Shop Law. 238 pages.</unittitle><unitid>11</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c280cebddc3478abd6f8eb6be81fdbd" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b6e891661ac1f8d5bb000f0cfafc6cba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Congressional hearings on amendments to the Railway Labor Act; A. Philip Randolph's statement before the House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce on the union shop bill; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman union shop agreements between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Pullman Company, between the New York Central System and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, between the Indiana Harbor Belt Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen of America, between the Monogohela Railway Company and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, and between the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and the Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad Company.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a33fd60d3f58dc907c4d8edf2875d139" level="file"><did><unittitle>0401. Union Shop Proposals (Pullman and All Carriers). 6 pages.</unittitle><unitid>12</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_60b9e5efe77b55e200246c4eda66e4f0" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6bc29d29a6a8892afd83f761ec0bbc6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Union Shop agreement between the Indiana Harbor Belt Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen of America.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4aa7673ae8bc806c4a4d9acbed315026" level="file"><did><unittitle>0407. Vacation and Holiday Movement. 6 pages.</unittitle><unitid>13</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1170fcb37bca74bb2d121fb94e7d487" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_48fae919e3ed2039063cbc05250baebf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters proposals regarding vacations and holidays.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e9c199410b183c817deb73f0326a6721" level="file"><did><unittitle>0413. Wage Stabilization Board. 38 pages.</unittitle><unitid>14</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_af374df77e665fbca3bfaa47e25bc205" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_46b15a6f91a85df823daf159c7462826"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Establishment of Temporary Emergency Railroad Wage Panel; report on wage increases for Pullman nonoperating employees; agreement between the Pullman Company and its clerical, office, station, and storehouse employees represented by the Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters-Pullman agreement regarding pay rates; wage increase agreement between the Pullman Company and its laundry employees represented by the United Transport Services Employees.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_33261f0a9a83c4e4dd6212de94b96c25" level="file"><did><unittitle>0451. Wage Stabilization Board. 25 pages.</unittitle><unitid>15</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_d31a067c33e97264984fcfbb270f199c" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8fe5d1d00cdaa84638fe89a6acb0a97"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Orders and regulations issued by the Wage Stabilization Board and the Salary Stabilization Board.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cc99a858b50203863835bc717a0b0264" level="file"><did><unittitle>0476. Washington Job Protection Agreement (Brotherhood's Affiliation). 11 pages.</unittitle><unitid>16</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_b9d906db3aa5a2689f6293c6c1254ceb" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a746f2e063aaaa860633524dd2bc1f0f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters request for inclusion as party to the Washington Job Protection Agreement.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e8b077eec7b8f1f6dff247522037524e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0487. Welfare Benefits. 10 pages.</unittitle><unitid>17</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b2e514260d1cb684e6a72cc3a5021bf" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_11d8bce7e681f61decbfc0032e309dc1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters application for services of the National Mediation Board on the health and welfare benefits case.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_467fe23a1ad5fcef5c41bdcfa1312ee5" level="file"><did><unittitle>0497. Workmen's Compensation Act. 47 pages.</unittitle><unitid>18</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_e7781f794db8dde8175037786aa85708" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5a2354d7bc2249106cb4c591b81617f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topic: Colorado workmen's compensation act.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b3307a17d07fc776cc1ae36114d29d33" level="file"><did><unittitle>0544. Adams, J.J. - Chicago District, Personal Injury. 3 pages.</unittitle><unitid>19</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_67cdd57be6922d1a60835e5ee4f310d5" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_af8c6394ef97ccf8aca4bc61a4cc1570" level="file"><did><unittitle>0547. Arnold, E. Jr. - Chicago District, Personal Injury. 8 pages.</unittitle><unitid>20</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_743a861e6ff18bf7f8715ca85c2f0717" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2f5a6045ed9dd5e903a0f069d143fa4f" level="file"><did><unittitle>0555. Eufre, P.C. - Chicago Commissary District, Personal Injury. 7 pages.</unittitle><unitid>21</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1ada9ccb0f2800a406250e4c9b5b2a6" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_dfc6c7b265c7cf82fbeae6de82c7697a" level="file"><did><unittitle>0562. Gaines, Houston - Personal Injury. 6 pages.</unittitle><unitid>22</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_8bb4e0d01d1679ea2a4c9843b0036b4d" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_234b275dcf0e6850b4b4ad5599432422" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jackson, O.W. - Personal Injury, 3 pages.</unittitle><unitid>23</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_1cb4821458127e28d50cdfc536d47b4f" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fd31821cc278ba6d0d947aeb6081d3fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Torry, J.P. - Personal Injury. 2 pages.</unittitle><unitid>24</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_ecbca7031546f09b8bec8b5f2b2c85b8" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_745729926d75776328ea3b11899c0be0" level="file"><did><unittitle>0573. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. 75 pages.</unittitle><unitid>25</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_20220df922f2d8b17ef8c3b306f00909" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2227c3da9bba0d30e11cd97ab9039e8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: Report on the history of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; report on election of National Association for the Advancement of Colored People officers; report on National Association for the Advancement of Colored People urban program in Chicago; financial statements for the Southside Chicago Branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; minutes of Illinois State National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Conference.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5c692a53285c2d2f8888e43ba88b3797" level="file"><did><unittitle>0648. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. 101 pages.</unittitle><unitid>26</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0e8982c3359de3571e792e2681ec000" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_089e80bdad3c399ac5440a079561e81b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Political Action Committee report; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People economic, political action, housing, and educational surveys; report on election of National Association for the Advancement of Colored People officers; financial statements for the Southside Chicago Branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; benefits for black veterans; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People positions on the My Lai incident in Vietnam and on employment discrimination; agenda for meeting of the Executive Committee of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Southside Chicago Branch; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People demand for minimum wage legislation in Illinois; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People code of personnel and employment practices.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4f6b1ef6b9ac9d534491a50fbf8e240e" level="file"><did><unittitle>0749. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. 110 pages.</unittitle><unitid>27</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1977" type="inclusive">1972-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_e489afc0720f788ca9a0949eb6a4c012" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4743ac912f1d5f403597dbb6bed66eee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People membership campaign; financial statement for the Southside Chicago Branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; reports of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Legal Office; reports on National Association for the Advancement of Colored People urban program in Chicago; agenda and minutes for National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Executive Committee meetings; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People opposition to moratorium on busing to achieve school integration.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dbe9df6dcca39cd0a28c74aeca9343a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>0859. A. Philip Randolph Institute. 106 pages.</unittitle><unitid>28</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1971" type="inclusive">1967-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4831a45acfd892330cfc782583f6695" label="unspecified" type="reel">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_da84a59e4f2537566ec6079bd6cf7310"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Major Topics: 1970 Senate elections; civil rights movement and the trade unions; report on the failure of black separatism; report on the future of the civil rights movement; recommendations of the National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence; report on black youth; report on feminism; report on the power of the black vote; report on civil rights strategy for the 1970s.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
