<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL05365</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Youngstown Sheet and Tube Co., et al and Charles Sawyer. The Steel Seizure Case Records <num>5365</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>March 11, 2019</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-07-23 00:14:16 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Youngstown Sheet and Tube Co., et al and Charles Sawyer. The Steel Seizure Case Records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname role="creator" source="ingest">Youngstown Sheet and Tube Company</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname role="creator" source="ingest">Sawyer, Charles</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>5365</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_dc175d1c638057e02769615a0edb930d" label="Quantity:">0.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_92c669d84f8cbaf7878ba7a3ac0c4918" label="Forms of Material:">Briefs, transcripts.</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_297f52e6b1156d921638cfb8310b3988">Motions, transcripts of proceedings, judicial opinions and briefs produced for or by the District Courts, Court of Appeals and U.S. Supreme Court in the case of Youngstown Sheet and Tube Co. et al. vs. Charles Sawyer.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b0bea9b5feb23fc2b59e8a087282efd6">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">2295985</unitid>
  </did>
  <odd id="aspace_e897ef876aa78a2bd772e8d840fb01d7">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>Kheel Staff, November 26, 2013</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_7f0042f0f2b65a4093d98da4defd9d39">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>In the latter part of 1951, a dispute arose between the steel companies and their employees over terms and conditions that should be included in new collective bargaining agreements. Long-continued conferences failed to resolve the dispute. On December l8, 1951, the employees' representative United Steelworkers of America, CIO, gave notice of an intention to strike "when the existing bargaining agreements expired on December 31. Thereupon the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service intervened in an effort to get labor and management to agree. This failing, the President on December 22, 1951 referred the dispute to the Federal Wage Stabilization Board to investigate and make recommendations for fair and equitable terms of settlement. This Board's report resulted in no settlement. On April 4, 1952, the union gave notice of a nation-wide strike called to begin at 12:01 a.m. April 9. </p><p> The indispensability of steel as a component of substantially all weapons and other war materials led the President to believe that the proposed work stoppage would immediately jeopardize our national defense and that governmental seizure of the steel mills was necessary in order to assure the continued availability of steel. Reciting these considerations for his action, the President, a few hours before the strike was to begin, issued Executive Order 10340. The order directed the Secretary of Commerce to take possession of and operate most of the steel mills throughout the country. The Secretary immediately issued his own possessory orders, calling upon the presidents of the various seized companies to serve as operating managers for the United States. They were directed to carry on their activities in accordance with regulations and directions of the Secretary. The next morning the President sent a message to Congress reporting his action. Cong. Rec. April 9, 1952 p. 3962. Twelve days later he sent a second message. Cong. Rec, April 21, 1952, p. 4192. Congress has taken no action. </p><p> Obeying the Secretary's orders under protest, the companies brought proceedings against him in the District Court. Their complaints charged that the seizure was not authorized by an act of Congress or by any constitutional provisions. The District Court was asked to declare the orders of the President and the Secretary invalid and to issue preliminary and permanent injunctions restraining their enforcement. Opposing the motion for preliminary injunction, the United States asserted that a strike disrupting steel production for even a brief period would so endanger the well-being and safety of the nation that the President has "inherent power" to do what he had done power "supported by the Constitution, by historical precedent, and by court decisions. </p><p> The Government also contended that in any event no preliminary injunction should be issued because the companies had made no showing that their available legal remedies were inadequate or that their injuries from seizure would be irreparable. Holding against the Government on all points, the District Court on April 30 issued a preliminary injunction restraining the Secretary from "continuing the seizure and possession of the plant... and from acting under the purported authority of Executive Order No.10340." 103 F. Supp. 569. On the same day the Court of Appeals stayed the District Court's injunction. </p><p> Since the issues raised, 1. Should the final determination of the constitutional validity of the President's order be made in a case which had reached only the preliminary injunction stage in the lower courts, and was the secure order within the constitutional power of the president were constitutional questions which it seemed best to decide promptly. The Supreme Court granted certiorari on May 3 and rendered its decision on June 2, 1952. By a 6 to 3 ruling they held that the President has no authority under the Constitution to seize private property of industry by executive order on the grounds that a work stoppage is imminent as a result of a labor dispute and that continued operation of the industry's facilities is necessary because of a national emergency.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0bd962e03fc1ce3e8d0571d2e18b3a78">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Summary: Include motions, transcripts of proceedings, judicial opinions and briefs produced for or by the District Courts, Court of Appeals and U.S. Supreme Court in the case of Youngstown Sheet and Tube Co. et al. vs. Charles Sawyer. </p><p> The collection includes the motion for temporary restraining order filed by Republic Steel Corporation (1952); official transcript in the case of "Youngstown Sheet and Tube Company, et al. vs. Charles Sawyer", District Court for the District of Columbia (1952); transcript of the proceedings before Judge David A. Pine, District Court for the District of Columbia (1952); opinion of Judge Pine on issuance of a preliminary injunction, "Youngstown Sheet and Tube Company, et al. vs. Charles Sawyer" (n.d.); and memorandum filed in United States Court of Appeals by Charles Sawyer motioning for a stay of execution on the preliminary injunction (1952). </p><p> Also included are numerous Writs of Certiorari and briefs of Amici Curiae given before the Supreme Court, including briefs of Amici Curiae submitted by the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, the Order of Railway Conductors of America, the United Steelworkers of America, the Congress of Industrial Organizations, Evert Lyman (attorney, State of California), and American Legion Post No. 88, Norman, Okla. </p><p> Also included is the official "Opinion of the Court," of the United States Supreme Court (1952). Other documents relating to various aspects of the case include an address by Clarence B. Randall (president, Inland Steel); and speeches by Richard M. Nixon and Hubert H. Humphrey, before the U.S. Senate (1952).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3e5f652d05ec03f5815f7ae4bdf4b981">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b67a58a720eaebaa7e4dc32a35de251a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_166bb9e47b9b4dd671f20eebd91c7703">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Youngstown Sheet and Tube Co., et al and Charles Sawyer. The Steel Seizure Case Records #5365. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="ingest">Labor injunctions. Steel industry. United States.</subject>
    <subject source="ingest">Iron and steel workers.</subject>
    <subject source="ingest">Nationalization. Steel industry. United States.</subject>
    <subject source="ingest">Strikes and lockouts. Steel industry. United States.</subject>
    <subject source="ingest">Trade-unions. Iron and steel workers. United States.</subject>
    <persname audience="internal" source="ingest">Lyman, Evert</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="ingest">Randall, Clarence B.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="ingest">Sawyer, Charles, 1887-1979</persname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers (U.S.)</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.)</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Order of Railway Conductors of America</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Republic Steel Corporation</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80049653" source="lcnaf">United Steelworkers of America</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Youngstown Sheet and Tube Company</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">2295985</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_22e6a78934bf70b81d76a48ea147fbc3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proceedings in District Court for the District of Columbia</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_18b24fee2293363139aef867ef8cc6cd" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c79ea2b1fcb5d3eba6a3cce54145c016" parent="aspace_18b24fee2293363139aef867ef8cc6cd" type="folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3ed4fb251af413d7850e68d940fdf0dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. Supreme Court: Briefs as amicus curiae</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_fba2b3d2c9a73a3b5c7cb2437e476a3d" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_0320db646bd0deb61795640bb46bbda1" parent="aspace_fba2b3d2c9a73a3b5c7cb2437e476a3d" type="folder">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2f25f0418b213f8c12cbf5d6269f16f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. Supreme Court: Briefs on writs of certiorari</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_59aa97824f8a0322b8eefc953cdef1ae" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1561c0adcf61b3f1d3f27aad4c2ea6a6" parent="aspace_59aa97824f8a0322b8eefc953cdef1ae" type="folder">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_92d9efbdded90006ff921b39487d3436" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. Supreme Court: Opinion of the court</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_6011f92f88015590af09307d51bb0eed" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4f9c10b0fb254e65d8ed69c2de15629c" parent="aspace_6011f92f88015590af09307d51bb0eed" type="folder">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8f9bcd7552d2b788cb1689974d3406d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous articles</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_57044cc80fe714757f1c5757ff6a7295" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_bac9564773e459fda62a594a1c227805" parent="aspace_57044cc80fe714757f1c5757ff6a7295" type="folder">5</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
