<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL06009m</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Ford Motor Company "Survey of University Industrial Relations Centers" Report <num>6009m</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>October 30, 2015</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-01-08 21:57:04 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ford Motor Company "Survey of University Industrial Relations Centers" Report</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname role="creator" source="ingest">Ford Motor Company Industrial Relations Analysis Department</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>6009m</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_5b6a6d663a834683a08d4053c9940101" label="Quantity:">1 file folder.</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_5330795e8c186a46d4ec7ddf88bfd541" label="Forms of Material:">Records.</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_1e67375b9d76d9b9367d5a1d608241bb">"Survey of University Industrial Relations Centers, Fall 1954," by the Ford Motor Company's Industrial Relations Analysis Department, April 23, 1956.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_1bd404633b27ba6e9d45b463894ea544">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">5758032</unitid>
  </did>
  <odd id="aspace_4fb711a769a6ed7e1782cfe50ab1b152">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>Kheel Staff, October 24, 2013</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Randall Miles, October 30, 2015</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e79cd4c03af659607d6386bfda30457a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of a "Survey of University Industrial Relations Centers, Fall 1954," by the Ford Motor Company's Industrial Relations Analysis Department, April 23, 1956.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c332167f51858b36105bc9b6687afab2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8a1a7f0a806b51a3ea7ed2ccea7ffbe5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_de1e7b098010f8a0ed740869da8fb72e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Ford Motor Company "Survey of University Industrial Relations Centers" Report #6009m. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist audience="internal" id="aspace_d8ebc0551f8ebab67ac4f798d0b6329b">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Ford Motor Company, commonly known as Ford, is an American multinational automaker that has its main headquarters in Dearborn, Michigan, a suburb of Detroit. It was founded by Henry Ford and incorporated on June 16, 1903. The company sells automobiles and commercial vehicles under the Ford brand, and most luxury cars under the Lincoln brand. Ford also owns Brazilian SUV manufacturer Troller, an 8% stake in Aston Martin of the United Kingdom and a 32% stake in Jiangling Motors. It also has joint-ventures in China (Changan Ford), Taiwan (Ford Lio Ho), Thailand (AutoAlliance Thailand), Turkey (Ford Otosan), and Russia (Ford Sollers). The company is listed on the New York Stock Exchange and is controlled by the Ford family; they have minority ownership but the majority of the voting power.
Ford introduced methods for large-scale manufacturing of cars and large-scale management of an industrial workforce using elaborately engineered manufacturing sequences typified by moving assembly lines; by 1914, these methods were known around the world as Fordism. Ford's former UK subsidiaries Jaguar and Land Rover, acquired in 1989 and 2000 respectively, were sold to the Indian automaker Tata Motors in March 2008. Ford owned the Swedish automaker Volvo from 1999 to 2010. In 2011, Ford discontinued the Mercury brand, under which it had marketed entry-level luxury cars in the United States, Canada, Mexico, and the Middle East since 1938.
Ford is the second-largest U.S.-based automaker (behind General Motors) and the fifth-largest in the world (behind Toyota, VW, Hyundai-Kia and General Motors) based on 2015 vehicle production. At the end of 2010, Ford was the fifth largest automaker in Europe. The company went public in 1956 but the Ford family, through special Class B shares, still retain 40 percent voting rights. During the financial crisis at the beginning of the 21st century, it struggled financially, but it has since returned to profitability. Ford was the eleventh-ranked overall American-based company in the 2018 Fortune 500 list, based on global revenues in 2017 of $156.7 billion. In 2008, Ford produced 5.532 million automobiles and employed about 213,000 employees at around 90 plants and facilities worldwide.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85065928" source="lcsh">Industrial relations</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Ford Motor Company</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Ford Motor Company. Industrial Relations Analysis Dept</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">5758032</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_58153d65d273a8b5fe6b74d5ea2172ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Survey of Industrial Relations Centers, Fall 1954</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_93a07e82fcc00ae54f7a507c0d2e95dd" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8bb6d480d1f271e7bbad7b56a305e485"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>April 23, 1956; 85 pages.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
