<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">KCL06036-022</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Mendelsund, Henoch. Interview by E. Finn. <num>6036/022</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</publisher><p><date>January 10, 2013</date></p><address><addressline>227 Ives Hall</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>Labor</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-01-08 21:58:33 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>02/23/2024</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation &amp; Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Mendelsund, Henoch. Interview by E. Finn.</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname role="creator" source="ingest">Mendelsund, Henoch</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname role="creator" source="ingest">Finn, E.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>6036/022</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.56 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1978/1978">1978-1978</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_a164ca8bd8c99c28d02fbd4777081d7c" label="Quantity:">0.333333333333333 linear ft.</physdesc>
    <physdesc id="aspace_c5f2f39ca40aa5d489e44ba1bbf4430d" label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs.</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_48de53a3d31f7f29445a7646100c097b">This collection consists of audio recordings and a transcript of an interview with Henoch Mendelsund shortly after his retirement from the ILGWU.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_051761738de872f797c4dbc25e5fd71e">Collection material in English</langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">5767606</unitid>
  </did>
  <odd id="aspace_b3fa1f7104d288d60e57e44d0274990c">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 <extref xlink:href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref> <extref xlink:href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>Kheel Staff, August 29, 2011</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 10, 2013</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e3184ebca321aca9e94ba4c9cb5a81fb">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).</p>  </bioghist>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2cac53d1b9e9ad435dc9199a71c4f696">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Henoch Mendelsund was born on March 26 (or 23), 1911. Active in the Jewish labor movement in his native Poland, he worked as a mechanic and attended Warsaw University. Mendelsund arrived in the U.S. in 1941 as one of 1,500 labor leaders and intellectuals rescued from the Nazis through the efforts of the ILGWU and other groups under special visas authorized by President Franklin D. Roosevelt. He joined the ILGWU as a machine operator, and while working in the shop during the day, he attended the New School for Social Research at night, earning a master's degree in economics and sociology. </p><p> In addition to his work in cloak shops, during the war, Mendelsund was a member of the National Coat and Suit Recovery Board staff. Mendelsund held many positions during his tenure with the ILGWU. In 1949, he became the secretary of Cloak Finishers' Local 9 and in 1953 became the assistant general manager of the New York Cloak Joint Board under Isadore Nagler. After Nagler's death in September 1959, Mendelsund became general manager, a post he held until 1973. He also served the union as a vice president, and was the director of the International Relations Department from 1968-1980. </p><p> On April 2, 1973 Mendelsund's recommendation to provide initial funding for the establishment of the ILGWU Archives was approved by the New York Cloak Joint Board. Mendelsund assumed directorship of the newly created archives, and served as director until his retirement on March 31, 1986. It was through Mendelsund's untiring efforts that led to the creation of the archives, its professional and prosperous status, and its oral history program. He died on September 22, 1994.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_62f13e5c6f85de34a03a13e8ba58660c">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The International Relations Department of the ILGWU was concerned primarily with outreach to foreign and international labor organizations, working conditions in foreign countries, and international organizing activities. The department worked closely with international relations units of national and international labor confederations, such as the Free Trade Union Committee (FTUC) and the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU). The collection consists of an interview with Henoch Mendelsund by E. Finn on August 30, 1978. Included is the typed transcript of the interview as well as the audio cassette. From his position as director of the International Relations Department, Mendelsund speaks of the union's early and continual interest in international affairs. He states that an actual international department was not formed until 1946 with Jay Lovestone serving as director until his departure to the AFL-CIO. While a department existed intermittently, Mendelsund does not place an emphasis on a formal organizational structure for the department as he feels the union was always involved in international affairs from its early inception, with or without an actual department. Even in the absence of a formal department, he illustrates that the union still had the Committee on International Affairs at the conventions, participating in missions, sending people to other countries, and collecting funds. Mendelsund discusses the lack of attention paid to unions and their involvement with international affairs, labor in respect to the State Department, and the role of labor attachs and representatives. Examined in the interview is the function and responsibility of unions and labor in international relations, as well as international affairs within the AFL-CIO. Mentioned are organizations such as the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) and the Trade Union Committee (TUC). Mendelsund concludes by discussing the place of labor in helping to organize and support trade unions in developing countries as well as the union's projects in Africa, including a trade school, medical equipment, and the generosity of members donating funds for union development.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0ac7e3771592064a3aacb721917ab1e5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4fee0f15ce8ceae89136787e95540be1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e733f0977f3d26b4750173f205dc3702">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Mendelsund, Henoch. Interview by E. Finn. #6036/022. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_907e3b2d906ca51b21f047721deb883a">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related Collections: <extref xlink:href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780: ILGWU records</extref> <extref xlink:href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-062.html"> 5780/062: ILGWU. International Relations Department records</extref> <extref xlink:href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-062pubs.html"> 5780/062 PUBS: ILGWU. International Relations Department publications</extref></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <persname audience="internal" source="ingest">Mendelsund, Henoch.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="ingest">Finn, E.</persname>
    <corpname audience="internal" authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50060238" source="lcnaf">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">5767606</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_9fa6b584a7f860f4ef968d25dc9fc601" level="file"><did><unittitle>Henoch Mendelsund</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9940e506e404995ebf18c91488873ef" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_adba09c04d980b1ef0c3b31fee6c2e74" parent="aspace_c9940e506e404995ebf18c91488873ef" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8fa1489b14c17a9e470630953fa28786"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Interviewed by E. Finn on August 30, 1978. 54 pages.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_5e0b146ae42969409d211db2e9e2dca5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Henoch Mendelsund</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0a4692dfd1b71883446bc23bb38ef30" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_741f02bc67653f4b2bcc7fc557cf34c1" parent="aspace_d0a4692dfd1b71883446bc23bb38ef30" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67ee58cdc62db1d9a5dc9dc0aacd1a38"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Interviewed by E. Finn on August 30, 1978. Audio cassette tape 1 of 2.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_33c90fb90b710a1da847aea780ffee8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Henoch Mendelsund</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_154b5fa2afc1b266b71ecefeb86002b7" label="unspecified" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_619ad4726e7b9bf7f01b79572b0084c1" parent="aspace_154b5fa2afc1b266b71ecefeb86002b7" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a00157ea86469234fc12b2fd00ae4bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Interviewed by E. Finn on August 30, 1978. Audio cassette tape 2 of 2.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
